docno	NN	O	0	ROOT	O
:	:	O	1	punct	O
1111Transition	CD	O	4	compound	O
services	NNS	O	1	dep	O
now	RB	B-DATE	6	advmod	O
mandatory	VBP	O	4	amod	O
for	IN	O	10	case	O
soldiersBy	NN	O	10	compound	O
Jim	NNP	B-PERSON	10	compound	O
Tice	NNP	I-PERSON	6	nmod	O
-	:	O	10	punct	O
Staff	NN	O	13	compound	O
writerPosted	VBN	O	10	dep	O
:	:	O	4	punct	O
Tuesday	NNP	B-DATE	16	compound	O
Apr	NNP	I-DATE	29	nsubj	O
3	CD	I-DATE	16	nummod	O
,	,	I-DATE	16	punct	O
2012	CD	I-DATE	20	compound	O
16:44:56	CD	B-TIME	16	nummod	O
EDTFORT	NNP	O	22	compound	O
KNOX	NNP	O	16	dep	O
,	,	O	22	punct	O
Ky.	NNP	B-STATE_OR_PROVINCE	22	appos	O
-	:	O	16	punct	O
Soldiers	NNS	O	16	dep	O
now	RB	B-DATE	29	advmod	O
must	MD	O	29	aux	O
participate	VB	O	4	dep	O
in	IN	O	32	case	O
transition	NN	O	32	compound	B-PROG
services	NNS	O	29	nmod	I-PROG
before	IN	O	35	mark	O
they	PRP	O	35	nsubj	O
leave	VBP	O	29	advcl	O
active	JJ	O	39	amod	O
duty.An	NN	O	39	amod	O
execution	NN	B-CAUSE_OF_DEATH	39	compound	O
order	NN	O	35	dobj	O
requiring	VBG	O	39	acl	O
them	PRP	O	40	dobj	O
to	TO	O	43	mark	O
make	VB	O	40	xcomp	O
use	NN	O	43	dobj	O
of	IN	O	47	case	O
the	DT	O	47	det	O
services	NNS	O	44	nmod	O
is	VBZ	O	50	cop	O
in	IN	O	50	case	O
force	NN	O	29	advcl	O
throughout	IN	O	54	case	O
the	DT	O	54	det	O
Army.The	NNP	O	54	compound	O
order	NN	O	50	nmod	O
applies	NNS	O	50	acl	O
to	TO	O	58	case	O
all	DT	O	58	det	O
soldiers	NNS	O	55	nmod	O
who	WP	O	61	nsubj	O
are	VBP	O	61	aux	O
leaving	VBG	O	58	acl:relcl	O
active	JJ	O	63	amod	O
duty	NN	O	61	dobj	O
,	,	O	50	punct	O
whether	IN	O	70	mark	O
they	PRP	O	70	nsubj	O
are	VBP	O	70	cop	O
Regular	JJ	B-ORGANIZATION	70	amod	B-P3
Army	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	70	compound	I-P3
members	NNS	O	50	dep	I-P3
who	WP	O	73	nsubj	O
are	VBP	O	73	aux	O
separating	VBG	O	70	acl:relcl	O
or	CC	O	73	cc	O
retiring	VBG	O	73	conj	O
or	CC	O	73	cc	O
reservists	NNS	O	78	nsubj	O
demobilizing	VBG	O	73	conj	O
after	IN	O	81	case	O
six	CD	B-DURATION	81	nummod	O
months	NNS	I-DURATION	78	nmod	O
or	CC	O	83	cc	O
more	JJR	O	81	nummod	O
on	IN	O	87	case	O
active	JJ	O	87	amod	O
duty.The	NN	O	87	compound	O
order	NN	O	78	nmod	O
,	,	O	87	punct	O
which	WDT	O	90	nsubj	O
implements	VBZ	O	87	acl:relcl	O
a	DT	O	92	det	O
directive	JJ	O	90	dobj	O
issued	VBN	O	92	acl	O
last	JJ	B-DATE	95	amod	O
year	NN	I-DATE	93	nmod:tmod	O
by	IN	O	100	case	O
Army	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	100	compound	B-P1
Secretary	NNP	B-TITLE	100	compound	I-P1
John	NNP	B-PERSON	100	compound	I-P1
McHugh	NNP	I-PERSON	93	nmod	I-P1
,	,	O	70	punct	O
further	JJ	O	103	advmod	O
requires	VBZ	O	70	dep	O
that	IN	O	107	mark	O
transition	NN	O	106	compound	O
processing	NN	O	107	nsubj	O
begin	NN	O	103	ccomp	O
at	IN	B-DURATION	109	case	O
least	JJS	I-DURATION	110	nmod:npmod	O
12	CD	I-DURATION	111	nummod	O
months	NNS	I-DURATION	107	nmod:tmod	O
before	IN	O	115	mark	O
a	DT	O	114	det	O
soldier	NN	B-TITLE	115	nsubj	O
leaves	VBZ	O	107	advcl	O
active	JJ	O	117	amod	O
duty	NN	O	115	dobj	O
and	CC	O	107	cc	O
that	IN	O	124	mark	O
the	DT	O	121	det	O
soldier	NN	B-TITLE	123	nmod:poss	O
's	POS	O	121	case	O
commander	NN	B-TITLE	124	nsubj	O
oversee	VBD	O	107	conj	O
the	DT	O	128	det	O
process.The	JJ	O	128	compound	O
new	JJ	O	128	amod	O
procedures	NNS	O	131	nsubjpass	O
will	MD	O	131	aux	O
be	VB	O	131	auxpass	O
bolstered	VBN	O	124	ccomp	O
later	RBR	B-DATE	134	advmod	O
this	DT	I-DATE	134	det	O
year	NN	I-DATE	131	nmod:tmod	O
when	WRB	O	143	advmod	O
the	DT	O	138	det	O
Veterans	NNP	B-MISC	138	compound	B-DOC
Opportunity	NNP	I-MISC	143	nsubjpass	I-DOC
to	TO	I-MISC	141	case	I-DOC
Work	NNP	I-MISC	141	compound	I-DOC
Act	NNP	I-MISC	138	nmod	I-DOC
is	VBZ	O	143	auxpass	O
implemented	VBN	O	131	advcl	O
Nov.	NNP	B-DATE	143	nmod:tmod	O
20	CD	I-DATE	144	nummod	O
for	IN	O	150	case	O
all	PDT	O	150	det:predet	O
the	DT	O	150	det	O
military	JJ	O	150	amod	O
services	NNS	O	143	nmod	O
.	.	O	1	punct	O

``	``	O	0	ROOT	O
From	IN	O	29	punct	O
the	DT	O	5	case	O
Army	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	5	det	O
standpoint	NN	O	5	compound	O
,	,	O	9	nmod	O
we	PRP	O	9	punct	O
are	VBP	O	9	nsubj	O
planning	VBG	O	9	aux	O
for	IN	O	29	ccomp	O
that	DT	O	12	case	O
mandate	NN	O	12	det	O
,	,	O	9	nmod	O
and	CC	O	9	punct	O
getting	VBG	O	9	cc	O
additional	JJ	O	9	conj	O
resources	NNS	O	17	amod	O
to	TO	O	15	dobj	O
support	VB	O	19	mark	O
implementation	NN	O	15	xcomp	O
across	IN	O	19	dobj	O
the	DT	O	26	case	O
active	JJ	O	26	det	O
and	CC	O	26	amod	O
reserve	JJ	O	23	cc	O
components	NNS	O	23	conj	O
,	,	O	19	nmod	O
''	''	O	29	punct	O
said	VBD	O	29	punct	O
Walter	NNP	B-PERSON	193	dep	B-P1
M.	NNP	I-PERSON	32	compound	I-P1
Herd	NNP	I-PERSON	32	compound	I-P1
,	,	O	43	nsubj	O
director	NN	B-TITLE	32	punct	B-REL
of	IN	O	32	appos	O
the	DT	O	38	case	O
Army	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	38	det	O
Career	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	38	compound	O
and	CC	O	34	nmod	O
Alumni	NNP	O	38	cc	O
Program.This	NNP	O	41	compound	O
will	MD	O	38	conj	O
result	VB	O	43	aux	O
in	IN	O	29	ccomp	O
about	IN	O	49	case	O
a	DT	O	49	advmod	O
300	CD	B-PERCENT	49	det	O
percent	NN	I-PERCENT	49	nummod	O
increase	NN	O	49	compound	O
in	IN	O	141	nmod	O
the	DT	O	52	case	O
number	NN	O	52	det	O
of	IN	O	49	nmod	O
soldiers	NNS	O	54	case	O
participating	VBG	O	52	nmod	O
in	IN	O	54	acl	O
transition	NN	O	58	case	B-PROG
services	NNS	O	58	compound	I-PROG
,	,	O	55	nmod	O
Herd	NNP	O	49	punct	O
said.ACAP	NN	O	61	compound	B-PROG
,	,	O	49	conj	O
a	DT	O	49	punct	O
longtime	JJ	O	66	det	B-PROG
Army	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	66	compound	I-PROG
program	NN	O	66	compound	I-PROG
,	,	O	49	appos	O
assists	VBZ	O	49	punct	B-REL
departing	VBG	O	103	csubjpass	B-P3
soldiers	NNS	O	70	amod	I-P3
,	,	O	68	dobj	O
family	NN	O	70	punct	O
members	NNS	O	73	compound	O
and	CC	O	70	conj	O
Army	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	70	cc	B-P3
career	NN	O	77	compound	I-P3
civilians	NNS	O	77	compound	I-P3
in	IN	O	70	conj	O
preparing	VBG	O	79	mark	O
for	IN	O	68	advcl	O
civilian	JJ	O	82	case	O
life	NN	O	82	amod	O
through	IN	O	79	nmod	O
myriad	JJ	O	85	case	O
counseling	NN	O	85	amod	O
,	,	O	79	nmod	O
education	NN	O	85	punct	O
,	,	O	85	conj	O
job-preparation	NN	O	85	punct	O
and	CC	O	85	conj	O
job-search	NN	O	85	cc	O
services	NNS	O	92	amod	O
at	IN	O	85	conj	O
54	CD	B-NUMBER	95	case	O
centers	NNS	O	95	nummod	O
in	IN	O	79	nmod	O
the	DT	O	98	case	O
U.S.	NNP	B-COUNTRY	98	det	O
and	CC	O	95	nmod	O
overseas.The	JJ	O	98	cc	O
centers	NNS	O	101	compound	O
are	VBP	O	98	conj	O
staffed	VBN	O	103	auxpass	O
by	IN	O	141	nsubj	O
counselors	NNS	O	105	case	O
who	WP	O	103	nmod	O
have	VBP	O	107	nsubj	B-REL
graduate	NN	O	105	acl:relcl	O
degrees	NNS	O	109	amod	O
in	IN	O	107	dobj	O
counseling	NN	O	111	case	O
and	CC	O	109	nmod	O
who	WP	O	107	cc	O
can	MD	O	115	nsubj	O
link	VB	O	115	aux	B-REL
up	RP	O	107	conj	I-REL
departing	VBG	O	115	compound:prt	B-P3
soldiers	NNS	O	118	amod	I-P3
with	IN	O	115	dobj	O
training	NN	O	120	case	B-REL
and	CC	O	115	nmod	I-REL
services	NNS	O	120	cc	I-REL
offered	VBN	O	120	conj	I-REL
by	IN	O	120	acl	I-REL
the	DT	O	126	case	O
Army	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	126	det	O
and	CC	O	123	nmod	O
other	JJ	O	126	cc	O
government	NN	O	130	amod	O
agencies	NNS	O	130	compound	O
,	,	O	126	conj	O
such	JJ	O	130	punct	O
as	IN	O	135	case	O
the	DT	O	132	mwe	O
Labor	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	135	det	O
and	CC	O	130	nmod	O
Veterans	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	135	cc	B-ORG
Affairs	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	139	compound	I-ORG
departments.ACAP	NN	I-ORGANIZATION	139	compound	B-PROG
also	RB	O	135	conj	O
operates	VBZ	O	141	advmod	B-REL
a	DT	O	43	ccomp	I-REL
new	JJ	O	148	det	I-REL
24-hour	JJ	B-DURATION	148	amod	O
,	,	O	148	amod	O
seven-day-a-week	JJ	B-DURATION	148	punct	O
call	NN	O	148	amod	O
center	NN	O	148	compound	O
here	RB	O	141	dobj	O
,	,	O	148	advmod	O
and	CC	O	141	punct	B-ORG
an	DT	O	141	cc	I-ORG
interactive	JJ	O	154	det	O
website	NN	O	154	amod	O
for	IN	O	173	nsubj	O
the	DT	O	158	case	O
virtual	JJ	O	158	det	O
delivery	NN	O	158	amod	O
of	IN	O	154	nmod	O
information	NN	O	160	case	O
and	CC	O	158	nmod	O
services	NNS	O	160	cc	O
,	,	O	160	conj	O
to	TO	O	154	punct	B-P3
include	VB	O	165	mark	I-P3
counseling.Regular	JJ	B-ORGANIZATION	154	acl	I-P3
Army	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	168	amod	O
soldiers	NNS	O	168	compound	O
leaving	VBG	O	165	dobj	O
active	JJ	O	168	acl	O
duty	NN	O	171	amod	O
should	MD	O	169	dobj	O
begin	VB	O	173	aux	O
their	PRP$	O	141	conj	O
transition	NN	O	175	nmod:poss	O
24	CD	B-DURATION	173	dobj	O
months	NNS	I-DURATION	177	nummod	O
in	IN	O	175	dep	O
advance	NN	O	179	case	O
of	IN	O	177	nmod	O
retirement	NN	O	181	case	O
and	CC	O	179	nmod	O
18	CD	B-DURATION	181	cc	O
to	TO	I-DURATION	185	compound	O
12	CD	I-DURATION	185	dep	O
months	NNS	I-DURATION	186	nummod	O
in	IN	O	181	conj	O
advance	NN	O	188	case	O
of	IN	O	177	nmod	O
separation	NN	O	190	case	O
,	,	O	188	nmod	O
Herd	NNP	B-PERSON	29	punct	O

``	``	O	0	ROOT	O
Ideally	RB	O	7	punct	O
,	,	O	7	advmod	O
the	DT	O	7	punct	O
soldier	NN	B-TITLE	5	det	O
should	MD	O	7	nsubj	O
go	VB	O	7	aux	O
to	TO	O	30	ccomp	O
an	DT	O	11	case	O
ACAP	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	11	det	B-PROG
center	NN	O	11	compound	O
,	,	O	7	nmod	O
receive	VB	O	7	punct	B-REL
a	DT	O	7	conj	O
pre-separation	NN	O	16	det	O
briefing	NN	O	16	amod	O
and	CC	O	13	dobj	O
begin	VB	O	7	cc	B-REL
to	TO	O	7	conj	I-REL
map	VB	O	20	mark	I-REL
out	RP	O	18	xcomp	I-REL
his	PRP$	O	20	compound:prt	O
or	CC	O	26	compound	O
her	PRP$	O	22	cc	O
transition	NN	O	22	conj	B-DOC
plan	NN	O	26	compound	I-DOC
,	,	O	20	dobj	O
''	''	O	30	punct	O
he	PRP	O	30	punct	O
said	VBD	O	30	nsubj	O
.	.	O	30	punct	O

``	``	O	0	ROOT	O
This	DT	O	7	nsubj	O
will	MD	O	7	aux	O
be	VB	O	7	cop	O
an	DT	O	7	det	O
individual	JJ	O	7	amod	O
plan	NN	O	1	root	O
to	TO	O	9	mark	O
lay	VB	O	7	acl	O
out	RP	O	9	compound:prt	O
how	WRB	O	15	advmod	O
the	DT	O	13	det	O
person	NN	O	15	nsubj	O
will	MD	O	15	aux	O
transition	VB	O	9	ccomp	O
from	IN	O	19	mark	O
being	VBG	O	19	cop	O
a	DT	O	19	det	O
soldier	NN	B-TITLE	15	advcl	O
to	TO	O	23	mark	O
being	VBG	O	23	cop	O
a	DT	O	23	det	O
civilian	NN	O	19	acl	O
.	.	O	7	punct	O

``	``	O	0	ROOT	O
The	DT	O	3	det	O
plan	NN	O	5	nsubj	O
will	MD	O	5	aux	O
include	VB	O	1	root	O
what	WP	O	7	det	O
classes	VBZ	O	11	dobj	O
the	DT	O	9	det	O
soldier	NN	B-TITLE	11	nsubj	O
will	MD	O	11	aux	O
attend	VB	O	5	ccomp	O
,	,	O	5	punct	O
and	CC	O	5	cc	O
specifically	RB	O	19	advmod	O
what	WP	O	16	det	O
preparations	NNS	O	19	nsubjpass	O
should	MD	O	19	aux	O
be	VB	O	19	auxpass	O
made	VBN	O	5	conj	O
,	,	O	19	punct	O
whether	IN	O	24	mark	O
he	PRP	O	24	nsubj	O
is	VBZ	O	24	aux	O
leaving	VBG	O	19	ccomp	O
service	NN	O	24	dobj	O
for	IN	O	27	case	O
college	NN	O	25	nmod	O
or	CC	O	24	cc	O
to	TO	O	30	mark	O
enter	VB	O	24	conj	O
the	DT	O	34	det	O
civilian	JJ	O	34	amod	O
work	NN	O	34	compound	O
force.ACAP	NN	O	30	dobj	B-PROG
works	VBZ	O	24	dep	B-REL
closely	RB	O	35	advmod	I-REL
with	IN	O	42	case	I-REL
the	DT	O	42	det	O
Army	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	42	compound	O
Continuing	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	42	compound	O
Education	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	42	compound	O
System	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	35	nmod	O
and	CC	O	35	cc	O
can	MD	O	45	aux	B-REL
coordinate	VB	O	35	conj	I-REL
services	NNS	O	45	dobj	I-REL
for	IN	O	49	case	I-REL
departing	VBG	O	49	amod	B-P3
soldiers	NNS	O	45	nmod	I-P3
who	WP	O	51	nsubj	O
plan	VBP	O	49	acl:relcl	O
to	TO	O	53	mark	O
attend	VB	O	51	xcomp	O
college	NN	O	53	dobj	O
or	CC	O	54	cc	O
who	WP	O	57	nsubj	O
require	VBP	O	54	conj	O
professional	JJ	O	60	amod	O
accreditation.For	NN	O	60	compound	O
example	NN	O	57	dobj	O
,	,	O	19	punct	O
if	IN	O	65	mark	O
a	DT	O	64	det	O
soldier	NN	B-TITLE	65	nsubj	O
wants	VBZ	O	19	advcl	O
to	TO	O	67	mark	O
become	VB	O	65	xcomp	O
a	DT	O	69	det	O
plumber	NN	B-TITLE	67	xcomp	O
after	IN	O	71	mark	O
leaving	VBG	O	67	advcl	O
the	DT	O	73	det	O
Army	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	71	dobj	O
,	,	O	73	punct	O
ACAP	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	73	conj	B-PROG
and	CC	O	73	cc	O
ACES	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	78	compound	O
counselors	NNS	O	73	conj	O
can	MD	O	80	aux	O
assist	VB	O	65	ccomp	O
the	DT	O	82	det	O
soldier	NN	B-TITLE	80	dobj	O
in	IN	O	84	mark	O
becoming	VBG	O	80	advcl	O
professionally	RB	O	87	advmod	O
accredited.Herd	VBN	O	87	nsubj	O
said	VBD	O	84	ccomp	O
reservists	NNS	O	91	nsubjpass	O
normally	RB	O	91	advmod	O
are	VBP	O	91	auxpass	O
mobilized	VBN	O	87	ccomp	O
for	IN	O	94	case	O
a	DT	B-DURATION	94	det	O
year	NN	I-DURATION	91	nmod	O
,	,	O	91	punct	O
so	IN	O	98	mark	O
they	PRP	O	98	nsubj	O
need	VBP	O	91	advcl	O
to	TO	O	100	mark	O
begin	VB	O	98	xcomp	O
their	PRP$	O	103	nmod:poss	O
transition	NN	O	103	compound	O
processing	NN	O	100	dobj	O
immediately	RB	O	100	advmod	O
upon	IN	O	106	mark	O
coming	VBG	O	100	advcl	O
on	IN	O	109	case	O
active	JJ	O	109	amod	O
duty	NN	O	106	nmod	O
.	.	O	5	punct	O

``	``	O	0	ROOT	O
For	IN	O	23	punct	O
most	JJS	O	3	case	O
of	IN	O	23	nmod	O
the	DT	O	7	case	O
Reserve	NNP	O	7	det	B-P3
soldiers	NNS	O	7	compound	I-P3
who	WP	O	3	nmod	O
are	VBP	O	10	nsubj	O
going	VBG	O	10	aux	O
back	RB	O	7	acl:relcl	O
to	TO	O	10	advmod	O
the	DT	O	15	case	O
same	JJ	O	15	det	O
job	NN	O	15	amod	O
they	PRP	O	11	nmod	O
left	VBD	O	17	nsubj	O
,	,	O	15	acl:relcl	O
the	DT	O	23	punct	O
transition	NN	O	20	det	O
will	MD	O	23	nsubj	O
be	VB	O	23	aux	O
simpler	JJR	O	23	cop	O
than	IN	O	47	dep	O
for	IN	O	26	case	O
those	DT	O	26	case	O
who	WP	O	23	nmod	O
do	VBP	O	30	nsubj	O
n't	RB	O	30	aux	O
have	VB	O	30	neg	O
an	DT	O	26	acl:relcl	O
existing	VBG	O	33	det	O
job	NN	O	33	amod	O
,	,	O	30	dobj	O
''	''	O	23	punct	O
Herd	NNP	O	23	punct	O
said.Commanders	NNS	O	37	compound	O
'	POS	O	42	nmod:poss	O
roleA	NN	O	37	case	O
second	JJ	B-ORDINAL	42	compound	O
major	JJ	O	42	amod	O
goal	NN	O	42	amod	O
of	IN	O	47	nsubj	O
the	DT	O	46	case	O
execution	NN	B-CAUSE_OF_DEATH	46	det	O
order	NN	O	46	compound	O
requires	VBZ	O	42	nmod	O
commanders	NNS	O	47	dobj	O
to	TO	O	51	mark	O
be	VB	O	51	cop	O
responsible	JJ	O	47	xcomp	O
for	IN	O	53	mark	O
ensuring	VBG	O	51	advcl	O
that	DT	O	59	mark	O
their	PRP$	O	56	nmod:poss	O
soldiers	NNS	O	59	nsubjpass	O
are	VBP	O	59	auxpass	O
successfully	RB	O	59	advmod	O
transitioned	VBN	O	53	ccomp	O
.	.	O	47	punct	O

``	``	O	0	ROOT	O
This	DT	O	34	punct	O
is	VBZ	O	7	nsubj	O
really	RB	O	7	cop	O
a	DT	O	7	advmod	O
big	JJ	O	7	det	O
change	NN	O	7	amod	O
,	,	O	34	ccomp	O
as	IN	O	7	punct	O
in	IN	O	12	case	O
the	DT	B-DATE	12	case	O
past	NN	I-DATE	12	det	O
,	,	O	7	nmod	O
transition	NN	O	7	punct	O
processing	NN	O	15	compound	O
really	RB	O	20	nsubj	O
was	VBD	O	20	advmod	O
a	DT	O	20	cop	O
staff	NN	O	20	det	O
issue	NN	O	20	compound	O
,	,	O	7	parataxis	O
rather	RB	O	7	punct	O
than	IN	O	7	cc	O
a	DT	O	22	mwe	O
commander	NN	B-TITLE	26	det	O
responsibility	NN	O	26	compound	O
,	,	O	7	conj	O
''	''	O	34	punct	O
Herd	NNP	O	34	punct	O
said.The	VBD	O	32	compound	O
new	JJ	O	32	compound	O
system	NN	O	32	amod	O
is	VBZ	O	34	nsubjpass	O
designed	VBN	O	34	auxpass	O
so	RB	O	40	mark	O
that	IN	O	35	mwe	O
commanders	NNS	O	40	nsubjpass	O
will	MD	O	40	aux	O
be	VB	O	40	auxpass	O
notified	VBN	O	34	advcl	O
when	WRB	O	44	advmod	O
their	PRP$	O	43	nmod:poss	O
soldiers	NNS	O	44	nsubj	O
begin	VBP	O	40	advcl	O
transitioning	VBG	O	44	xcomp	O
processing	NN	O	45	dobj	O
.	.	O	34	punct	O

``	``	O	0	ROOT	O
The	DT	O	44	punct	O
commander	NN	B-TITLE	3	det	O
can	MD	O	5	nsubj	O
delegate	VB	O	5	aux	O
the	DT	O	44	ccomp	O
monitoring	NN	O	7	det	O
of	IN	O	5	dobj	O
a	DT	O	12	case	O
soldier	NN	B-TITLE	10	det	O
's	POS	O	12	nmod:poss	O
transition	NN	O	10	case	O
to	TO	O	7	nmod	O
subordinate	VB	O	14	mark	O
officers	NNS	O	12	acl	O
and	CC	O	14	dobj	O
-LSB-	NN	O	5	cc	O
noncommissioned	JJ	O	19	punct	O
officers	NNS	O	19	amod	O
-RSB-	VBP	O	5	conj	O
,	,	O	19	punct	O
but	CC	O	5	punct	O
he	PRP	O	5	cc	O
is	VBZ	O	25	nsubj	O
responsible	JJ	O	25	cop	O
for	IN	O	5	conj	O
making	VBG	O	27	mark	O
sure	JJ	O	25	advcl	O
that	IN	O	27	xcomp	O
the	DT	O	32	mark	O
soldiers	NNS	O	31	det	O
start	VBP	O	32	nsubj	O
the	DT	O	28	ccomp	O
process	NN	O	34	det	O
at	IN	B-DURATION	32	dobj	O
least	JJS	I-DURATION	36	case	O
12	CD	I-DURATION	37	nmod:npmod	O
months	NNS	I-DURATION	38	nummod	O
out	RP	O	39	nmod:npmod	O
,	,	O	32	advmod	O
''	''	O	44	punct	O
Herd	NNP	O	44	punct	O
said.Officials	NNS	O	43	compound	O
expect	VBP	O	44	nsubj	O
that	IN	O	54	mark	O
first	JJ	B-ORDINAL	47	amod	O
sergeants	NNS	O	54	nsubj	O
and	CC	O	47	cc	O
squad	JJ	O	50	compound	O
leaders	NNS	O	47	conj	O
will	MD	O	54	aux	O
be	VB	O	54	cop	O
major	JJ	O	54	amod	O
players	NNS	O	61	csubj	O
in	IN	O	58	case	O
this	DT	O	58	det	O
process.The	NN	O	58	compound	O
commander	NN	B-TITLE	54	nmod	O
will	MD	O	61	aux	O
then	RB	O	61	advmod	O
get	VB	O	44	ccomp	O
periodic	JJ	O	63	amod	O
reports	NNS	O	61	dobj	O
showing	VBG	O	63	acl	O
how	WRB	O	66	advmod	O
many	JJ	O	68	amod	O
transitioning	VBG	O	68	amod	O
soldiers	NNS	O	77	nsubj	O
in	IN	O	71	case	O
the	DT	O	71	det	O
company	NN	O	68	nmod	O
,	,	O	71	punct	O
battalion	NN	O	71	conj	O
or	CC	O	71	cc	O
brigade	NN	O	71	conj	O
have	VBP	O	77	aux	B-REL
completed	VBN	O	64	ccomp	I-REL
pre-separation	NN	O	79	amod	O
counseling	NN	O	77	dobj	O
,	,	O	44	punct	O
prepared	VBD	O	44	conj	O
a	DT	O	83	det	O
résumé	NN	O	81	dobj	O
,	,	O	44	punct	O
attended	VBD	O	44	dep	O
briefings	NNS	O	85	dobj	O
and	CC	O	86	cc	O
other	JJ	O	90	amod	O
ACAP	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	90	compound	B-PROG
activities	NNS	O	86	conj	O
.	.	O	44	punct	O

``	``	O	0	ROOT	O
The	DT	O	4	det	O
long-term	JJ	O	4	amod	O
plan	NN	O	5	nsubj	O
is	VBZ	O	1	root	O
to	TO	O	7	mark	O
monitor	VB	O	5	xcomp	O
a	DT	O	9	det	O
soldier	NN	B-TITLE	12	nmod:poss	B-REL
's	POS	O	9	case	I-REL
transition	NN	O	12	compound	I-REL
processing	NN	O	7	dobj	I-REL
through	IN	O	16	case	O
Army	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	16	compound	B-PROG
Career	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	16	compound	I-PROG
Tracker	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	7	nmod	O
,	,	O	16	punct	B-REL
a	DT	O	19	det	I-REL
system	NN	O	16	appos	I-REL
for	IN	O	22	case	O
enlisted	JJ	O	22	amod	O
soldiers	NNS	O	19	nmod	O
,	,	O	22	punct	O
officers	NNS	O	22	conj	O
and	CC	O	22	cc	O
Army	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	27	compound	O
civilians	NNS	O	22	conj	O
to	TO	O	29	mark	O
plot	VB	O	19	acl	O
their	PRP$	O	32	nmod:poss	O
career	NN	O	32	compound	O
milestones	NNS	O	29	dobj	O

``	``	O	0	ROOT	O
We	PRP	O	6	nsubj	O
are	VBP	O	6	cop	O
n't	RB	O	6	neg	O
quite	RB	O	6	advmod	O
there	RB	O	1	root	O
yet	RB	O	6	advmod	O
,	,	O	6	punct	O
but	CC	O	6	cc	O
we	PRP	O	13	nsubjpass	O
will	MD	O	13	aux	O
get	VB	O	13	auxpass	O
plugged	VBN	O	29	csubj	O
into	IN	O	16	case	O
Career	NNP	O	16	compound	B-PROG
Tracker	NNP	O	13	nmod	I-PROG
''	''	O	16	punct	O
Herd	NNP	O	19	compound	O
said.Herd	NN	O	16	dep	O
,	,	O	19	punct	O
a	DT	O	23	det	O
retired	JJ	O	23	amod	B-P2
colonel	NN	B-TITLE	19	appos	I-P2
and	CC	O	23	cc	O
former	JJ	O	27	amod	B-P2
brigade	NN	O	27	compound	I-P2
commander	NN	B-TITLE	23	conj	I-P2
,	,	O	19	punct	O
acknowledged	VBD	O	6	conj	O
that	IN	O	52	mark	O
with	IN	O	35	case	O
the	DT	O	35	det	O
ongoing	JJ	O	35	amod	O
force	NN	O	35	compound	B-PROG
alignment	NN	O	52	nmod	I-PROG
and	CC	O	35	cc	I-PROG
drawdown	JJ	O	38	compound	I-PROG
programs	NNS	O	35	conj	I-PROG
,	,	O	35	punct	O
such	JJ	O	46	case	O
as	IN	O	40	mwe	O
the	DT	O	46	det	O
Qualitative	NNP	O	46	compound	B-PROG
Service	NNP	O	46	compound	I-PROG
Program	NNP	O	46	compound	I-PROG
boards	NNS	O	35	conj	O
,	,	O	35	punct	O
some	DT	O	49	det	O
soldiers	NNS	O	52	nsubjpass	O
will	MD	O	52	aux	O
be	VB	O	52	auxpass	O
required	VBN	O	29	ccomp	O
to	TO	O	54	mark	O
leave	VB	O	52	xcomp	O
active	JJ	O	56	amod	O
duty	NN	O	54	dobj	O
early	JJ	O	54	advmod	O
,	,	O	6	punct	O
and	CC	O	6	cc	O
will	MD	O	62	aux	O
not	RB	O	62	neg	O
have	VB	O	6	conj	O
a	DT	O	65	det	O
full	JJ	O	65	amod	O
year	NN	B-DURATION	62	dobj	O
for	IN	O	68	case	O
transitioning	VBG	O	68	amod	O
processing	NN	O	65	nmod	O
.	.	O	6	punct	O

30	CD	B-NUMBER	0	ROOT	O
,	,	O	1	punct	O
2012	CD	B-DATE	9	nummod	O
-	:	O	9	punct	O
British	JJ	B-NATIONALITY	9	amod	B-P1
military	JJ	O	9	amod	I-P1
historian	NN	B-TITLE	9	compound	I-P1
John	NNP	B-PERSON	9	compound	I-P1
Keegan	NNP	I-PERSON	11	nsubj	I-P1
once	RB	B-DATE	11	advmod	O
said	VBD	O	1	dep	O
,	,	O	11	punct	O
``	``	O	11	punct	O
It	PRP	O	18	nsubj	O
's	VBZ	O	18	cop	O
a	DT	O	18	det	O
necessary	JJ	O	18	amod	O
quality	NN	O	11	ccomp	O
of	IN	O	21	case	O
a	DT	O	21	det	O
diplomat	NN	B-TITLE	18	nmod	O
or	CC	O	21	cc	O
a	DT	O	24	det	O
politician	NN	B-TITLE	21	conj	O
that	IN	O	28	dobj	O
he	PRP	O	28	nsubj	O
will	MD	O	28	aux	O
compromise	VB	O	18	acl:relcl	O
.	.	O	1	punct	O

Uncompromising	VBG	O	0	ROOT	O
politicians	NNS	O	2	amod	O
or	CC	O	5	nsubj	O
diplomats	NNS	O	2	cc	O
get	VBP	O	2	conj	O
you	PRP	O	5	dobj	O
into	IN	O	11	case	O
the	DT	O	11	det	O
most	RBS	O	10	advmod	O
terrible	JJ	O	11	amod	O
trouble	NN	O	5	nmod	O
.	.	O	5	punct	O

``	``	O	0	ROOT	O
That	DT	O	7	nsubj	O
may	MD	O	7	aux	O
never	RB	O	7	neg	O
have	VB	O	7	aux	O
been	VBN	O	7	cop	O
truer	JJR	B-TITLE	1	root	O
than	IN	O	10	mark	O
it	PRP	O	10	nsubj	O
is	VBZ	O	7	ccomp	O
today	NN	B-DATE	10	nmod:tmod	O
,	,	O	7	punct	O
as	IN	O	15	mark	O
Congress	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	15	nsubj	B-ORG
struggles	VBZ	O	37	csubj	O
to	TO	O	17	mark	O
come	VB	O	15	xcomp	O
up	RP	O	17	compound:prt	O
with	IN	O	21	case	O
a	DT	O	21	det	O
deal	NN	O	17	nmod	O
to	TO	O	23	mark	O
avoid	VB	O	17	xcomp	O
sending	VBG	O	23	xcomp	O
our	PRP$	O	26	nmod:poss	O
country	NN	O	24	dobj	O
over	IN	O	30	case	O
the	DT	O	30	det	O
fiscal	JJ	O	30	amod	O
cliff	NN	O	24	nmod	O
at	IN	O	34	case	O
year	NN	B-DURATION	34	nmod:poss	O
's	POS	O	32	case	O
end.It	NN	O	24	nmod	O
would	MD	O	37	aux	O
be	VB	O	37	cop	O
nice	JJ	O	7	ccomp	O
if	IN	O	45	mark	O
Congress	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	45	nsubjpass	B-ORG
and	CC	O	39	cc	O
the	DT	O	42	det	O
president	NN	B-TITLE	39	conj	O
would	MD	O	45	aux	O
be	VB	O	45	auxpass	O
inspired	VBN	O	37	advcl	O
to	TO	O	47	mark	O
take	VB	O	45	xcomp	O
defense	NN	O	47	dobj	O
of	IN	O	51	case	O
the	DT	O	51	det	O
homeland	NN	O	48	nmod	O
more	JJR	O	53	amod	O
seriously.Perhaps	NNS	O	63	nsubj	O
most	RBS	O	55	advmod	O
concerning	VBG	O	53	acl	O
are	VBP	O	63	cop	O
the	DT	O	63	det	O
draconian	JJ	O	63	amod	O
defense	NN	O	63	compound	O
``	``	O	63	punct	O
sequestration	NN	O	63	compound	O
''	''	O	63	punct	O
cuts	NNS	O	47	ccomp	O
that	WDT	O	66	nsubjpass	O
are	VBP	O	66	auxpass	O
set	VBN	O	63	acl:relcl	O
to	TO	O	68	mark	O
take	VB	O	66	xcomp	O
effect	NN	O	68	dobj	O
January	NNP	B-DATE	68	nmod:tmod	O
2	CD	I-DATE	70	nummod	O
,	,	I-DATE	70	punct	O
2013	CD	I-DATE	70	nummod	O
.	.	O	7	punct	O

The	DT	O	0	ROOT	O
$	$	B-MONEY	5	det	O
500	CD	I-MONEY	5	amod	O
billion	CD	I-MONEY	4	compound	O
reduction	NN	O	2	nummod	O
in	IN	O	18	nsubjpass	O
military	JJ	O	8	case	O
spending	NN	O	8	amod	O
triggered	VBN	O	5	nmod	O
by	IN	O	8	acl	O
2011	CD	B-DATE	15	case	O
's	POS	O	15	nmod:poss	O
Budget	NNP	O	11	case	B-DOC
Control	NNP	O	15	compound	I-DOC
Act	NNP	O	15	compound	I-DOC
would	MD	O	9	nmod	O
be	VB	O	18	aux	O
added	VBN	O	18	auxpass	O
to	TO	O	21	case	O
the	DT	O	21	det	O
$	$	B-MONEY	18	nmod	O
487	CD	I-MONEY	23	compound	O
billion	CD	I-MONEY	21	nummod	O
the	DT	O	26	det	O
Obama	NNP	B-PERSON	26	compound	B-ORG
administration	NN	O	21	dep	I-ORG
already	RB	O	28	advmod	O
eliminated	VBN	O	26	acl	O
in	IN	O	35	case	O
this	DT	B-DATE	31	det	O
year	NN	I-DATE	35	nmod:poss	O
's	POS	O	31	case	O
budget	NN	O	35	compound	O
request.For	NN	O	35	compound	O
months	NNS	B-DURATION	28	nmod	O
,	,	O	26	punct	O
lawmakers	NNS	O	40	nsubjpass	O
have	VBP	O	40	aux	O
been	VBN	O	40	auxpass	O
warned	VBN	O	26	acl:relcl	O
of	IN	O	45	case	O
the	DT	O	45	det	O
potential	JJ	O	45	amod	O
economic	JJ	O	45	amod	O
impact	NN	O	40	nmod	O
of	IN	O	51	case	O
these	DT	O	51	det	O
indiscriminate	NN	O	51	amod	O
,	,	O	51	punct	O
across-the-board	JJ	O	51	amod	O
cuts	NNS	O	45	nmod	O
.	.	O	18	punct	O

A	DT	O	0	ROOT	O
joint	JJ	O	3	det	O
study	NN	O	3	amod	O
between	IN	O	18	nsubj	O
Dr.	NNP	O	8	case	B-P1
Stephen	NNP	B-PERSON	8	compound	I-P1
S.	NNP	I-PERSON	8	compound	I-P1
Fuller	NNP	I-PERSON	8	compound	I-P1
of	IN	O	3	nmod	I-P1
George	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	12	case	I-P1
Mason	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	12	compound	I-P1
University	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	12	compound	I-P1
and	CC	O	8	nmod	O
Chmura	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	8	cc	B-ORG
Economics	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	15	compound	I-ORG
and	CC	I-ORGANIZATION	8	conj	I-ORG
Analytics	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	15	cc	I-ORG
showed	VBD	O	15	conj	O
that	IN	O	22	mark	O
America	NNP	B-COUNTRY	22	nsubj	O
could	MD	O	22	aux	O
lose	VB	O	18	ccomp	O
an	DT	O	27	det	O
estimated	VBN	O	27	amod	O
2.14	CD	B-NUMBER	26	compound	O
million	CD	I-NUMBER	27	nummod	O
jobs	NNS	O	22	dobj	O
if	IN	O	30	mark	O
Congress	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	30	nsubj	B-ORG
does	VBZ	O	22	advcl	O
nothing	NN	O	30	dobj	O
to	TO	O	33	mark	O
prevent	VB	O	31	acl	O
the	DT	O	37	det	O
automatic	JJ	O	37	amod	O
sequestration	NN	O	37	compound	O
cuts.But	VBD	O	33	dobj	O
the	DT	O	39	det	O
effects	NNS	O	37	dep	O
of	IN	O	41	case	O
sequestration	NN	O	39	nmod	O
-	:	O	39	punct	O
on	IN	O	44	case	O
top	NN	O	39	nmod	O
of	IN	O	49	case	O
already	RB	O	47	advmod	O
reduced	VBN	O	49	amod	O
military	JJ	O	49	amod	O
spending	NN	O	44	nmod	O
on	IN	O	54	case	O
the	DT	O	52	det	O
president	NN	B-TITLE	54	nmod:poss	O
's	POS	O	52	case	O
watch	NN	O	49	nmod	O
-	:	O	39	punct	O
extend	VB	O	39	acl	O
well-beyond	JJ	O	60	amod	O
our	PRP$	O	60	nmod:poss	O
fragile	JJ	O	60	amod	O
economy	NN	O	56	dobj	O
.	.	O	18	punct	O

Military	JJ	O	0	ROOT	O
brass	NN	O	2	amod	O
and	CC	O	6	nsubj	O
defense	NN	O	2	cc	O
experts	NNS	O	5	compound	O
agree	VBP	O	2	conj	O
that	IN	O	12	mark	O
such	JJ	O	10	amod	O
haphazard	NN	O	10	amod	O
cuts	NNS	O	12	nsubj	O
would	MD	O	12	aux	O
gut	VB	O	6	ccomp	O
critical	JJ	O	15	amod	O
defense	NN	O	15	compound	O
programs	NNS	O	12	dobj	O
that	WDT	O	17	nsubj	O
protect	VBP	O	15	acl:relcl	O
this	DT	O	19	det	O
nation	NN	O	17	dobj	O
and	CC	O	12	cc	O
our	PRP$	O	22	nmod:poss	O
troops	NNS	O	30	nsubj	O
from	IN	O	24	case	O
harm.Secretary	NN	O	22	nmod	B-P1
of	IN	O	28	case	I-P1
Defense	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	28	compound	I-P1
Leon	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	28	compound	I-P1
Panetta	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	24	nmod	I-P1
has	VBZ	O	30	aux	O
said	VBD	O	12	conj	O
that	IN	O	46	mark	O
``	``	O	46	punct	O
if	IN	O	37	mark	O
additional	JJ	O	35	amod	O
efforts	NNS	O	37	nsubjpass	O
are	VBP	O	37	auxpass	O
made	VBN	O	46	advcl	O
to	TO	O	39	mark	O
go	VB	O	37	xcomp	O
after	IN	O	43	case	O
the	DT	O	43	det	O
defense	NN	O	43	compound	O
budget	NN	O	39	nmod	O
,	,	O	46	punct	O
I	PRP	O	46	nsubj	O
think	VBP	O	30	ccomp	O
it	PRP	O	49	nsubj	O
could	MD	O	49	aux	O
have	VB	O	46	ccomp	O
a	DT	O	52	det	O
serious	JJ	O	52	amod	O
impact	NN	O	49	dobj	O
in	IN	O	54	case	O
terms	NNS	O	52	nmod	O
of	IN	O	57	case	O
our	PRP$	O	57	nmod:poss	O
ability	NN	O	54	nmod	O
to	TO	O	59	mark	O
implement	VB	O	57	acl	O
''	''	O	59	punct	O
the	DT	O	62	det	O
Pentagon	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	66	nmod:poss	O
's	POS	O	62	case	O
stated	VBN	O	66	amod	O
defense	NN	O	66	compound	O
strategy	NN	O	59	dobj	O
.	.	O	6	punct	O

This	DT	O	0	ROOT	O
is	VBZ	O	4	nsubj	O
especially	RB	O	4	cop	O
true	JJ	O	4	advmod	O
in	IN	O	6	case	O
light	NN	O	4	nmod	O
of	IN	O	9	case	O
significant	JJ	O	9	amod	O
cuts	NNS	O	6	nmod	O
already	RB	O	11	advmod	O
imposed	VBN	O	9	acl	O
.	.	O	4	punct	O

As	IN	O	0	ROOT	O
these	DT	O	6	mark	O
cuts	NNS	O	3	det	O
are	VBP	O	6	nsubj	O
beyond	IN	O	6	cop	O
flesh	JJ	O	6	case	O
and	CC	O	6	cc	O
into	IN	O	10	case	O
the	DT	O	10	det	O
bone	NN	O	6	conj	O
.	.	O	6	punct	O

Further	JJ	O	0	ROOT	O
cuts	NNS	O	2	amod	O
now	RB	B-DATE	5	nsubj	O
are	VBP	O	5	advmod	O
threatening	VBG	O	5	aux	O
to	TO	O	20	csubj	O
become	VB	O	7	mark	O
reckless	JJ	O	5	xcomp	O
endangerment	NN	O	9	amod	O
of	IN	O	7	xcomp	O
the	DT	O	15	case	O
American	NNP	B-NATIONALITY	15	det	O
people.One	NN	O	15	amod	O
urgent	JJ	O	15	compound	O
area	NN	O	15	amod	O
of	IN	O	9	nmod	O
concern	NN	O	17	case	O
is	VBZ	O	15	nmod	O
missile	JJ	O	20	cop	O
defense	NN	O	20	compound	O
,	,	O	20	punct	O
particularly	RB	O	24	advmod	B-REL
in	IN	O	24	case	I-REL
light	NN	O	20	nmod	I-REL
of	IN	O	32	case	I-REL
North	NNP	B-COUNTRY	27	compound	O
Korea	NNP	I-COUNTRY	32	nmod:poss	O
's	POS	O	27	case	O
successful	JJ	O	32	amod	O
long-range	NN	O	32	amod	O
rocket	NN	O	32	compound	O
test	NN	O	24	nmod	O
earlier	RBR	B-DATE	35	advmod	O
this	DT	I-DATE	35	det	O

While	IN	O	0	ROOT	O
the	DT	O	5	mark	O
White	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	4	det	B-ORG
House	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	4	compound	I-ORG
deemed	VBD	O	5	nsubj	O
the	DT	O	19	advcl	O
launch	NN	O	7	det	O
a	DT	O	12	nsubj	O
``	``	O	12	det	O
highly	RB	O	12	punct	O
provocative	JJ	O	11	advmod	O
act	NN	O	12	amod	O
,	,	O	5	xcomp	O
''	''	O	19	punct	O
it	PRP	O	19	punct	O
was	VBD	O	19	nsubj	O
a	DT	O	19	cop	O
stark	JJ	O	19	det	O
reminder	NN	O	19	amod	O
of	IN	O	22	case	O
the	DT	O	22	det	O
importance	NN	O	19	nmod	O
of	IN	O	24	mark	O
investing	VBG	O	22	acl	O
in	IN	O	27	case	O
defensive	JJ	O	27	amod	O
systems	NNS	O	24	nmod	O
that	WDT	O	31	nsubj	O
can	MD	O	31	aux	O
both	DT	O	31	dep	O
deter	VB	O	27	acl:relcl	O
attacks	NNS	B-CAUSE_OF_DEATH	31	dobj	O
and	CC	O	31	cc	O
protect	VBP	O	31	conj	O
us	PRP	O	34	dobj	O
increasing	VBG	O	37	amod	O
threats	NNS	O	34	dobj	O
from	IN	O	40	case	O
rogue	NN	O	40	amod	O
nations.Time	NN	O	37	nmod	O
and	CC	O	37	cc	O
again	RB	O	48	advmod	O
our	PRP$	O	46	nmod:poss	O
``	``	O	46	punct	O
Cold	NNP	B-TITLE	46	compound	O
War	NNP	B-CAUSE_OF_DEATH	48	nsubj	O
''	''	O	46	punct	O
focused	VBD	O	37	conj	O
defense	NN	O	54	compound	O
,	,	O	49	punct	O
diplomatic	JJ	O	49	conj	O
and	CC	O	49	cc	O
intelligence	NN	O	49	conj	O
apparatus	NN	O	48	dobj	O
and	CC	O	48	cc	O
intelligentsia	NN	O	60	nsubj	O
have	VBP	O	60	aux	O
been	VBN	O	60	cop	O
``	``	O	60	punct	O
surprised	JJ	O	48	conj	O
''	''	O	60	punct	O
by	IN	O	64	case	O
global	JJ	O	64	amod	O
events	NNS	O	60	nmod	O
empowered	VBN	O	64	acl	O
by	IN	O	69	case	O
new	JJ	O	69	amod	O
social	JJ	O	69	amod	O
media	NNS	O	65	nmod	O
.	.	O	19	punct	O

Witness	NNP	O	0	ROOT	O
Tunisia	NNP	B-COUNTRY	1	dobj	O
,	,	O	2	punct	O
Egypt	NNP	B-COUNTRY	2	conj	O
,	,	O	2	punct	O
Yemen	NNP	B-COUNTRY	2	conj	O
,	,	O	2	punct	O
Syria	NNP	B-COUNTRY	2	conj	O
,	,	O	2	punct	O
Libya	NNP	B-LOCATION	2	conj	O
and	CC	O	2	cc	O
tumult	NN	O	2	conj	O
in	IN	O	14	case	O
Mali	NNP	B-COUNTRY	1	nmod	O
.	.	O	1	punct	O

One	CD	B-NUMBER	0	ROOT	O
of	IN	O	10	nsubj	O
the	DT	O	6	case	O
U.S.	NNP	B-COUNTRY	6	det	O
top	JJ	O	6	compound	O
defense	NN	O	6	amod	O
and	CC	O	1	nmod	O
intelligence	NN	O	6	cc	O
priorities	NNS	O	9	compound	O
is	VBZ	O	6	conj	O
to	TO	O	12	mark	O
prevent	VB	O	10	xcomp	O
strategic	JJ	O	14	amod	O
surprise	NN	O	12	dobj	O
.	.	O	10	punct	O

And	CC	O	0	ROOT	O
yet	RB	O	8	cc	O
the	DT	O	8	advmod	O
collective	JJ	O	7	det	O
political	JJ	O	7	amod	O
group	NN	O	7	amod	O
think	NN	O	7	compound	O
is	VBZ	O	8	nsubj	O
to	TO	O	11	mark	O
apparently	RB	O	11	advmod	O
allow	VB	O	8	xcomp	O
these	DT	O	15	det	O
multiple	NNS	O	15	amod	O
layered	VBD	O	15	amod	O
cuts	NNS	O	11	dobj	O
to	TO	O	17	mark	O
happen	VB	O	11	xcomp	O
.	.	O	8	punct	O

It	PRP	O	0	ROOT	O
is	VBZ	O	5	nsubj	O
unconscionable.An	JJ	O	5	cop	O
immediate	JJ	O	5	amod	O
problem	NN	O	5	amod	O
is	VBZ	O	15	cop	O
that	IN	O	15	mark	O
our	PRP$	O	12	nmod:poss	O
current	JJ	B-DATE	12	amod	B-DOC
missile	NN	O	12	compound	I-DOC
defense	NN	O	12	compound	I-DOC
budget	NN	O	15	nsubj	I-DOC
is	VBZ	O	15	cop	O
woefully	RB	O	15	advmod	O
inadequate	JJ	O	5	dep	O
.	.	O	5	punct	O

In	IN	O	0	ROOT	O
total	JJ	O	2	case	O
,	,	O	6	nmod	O
the	DT	O	6	punct	O
president	NN	B-TITLE	5	det	O
lopped	VBD	O	6	nsubj	O
$	$	B-MONEY	6	dobj	O
3.6	CD	I-MONEY	9	compound	O
billion	CD	I-MONEY	7	nummod	O
off	IN	O	13	case	O
the	DT	O	13	det	O
projected	JJ	O	13	amod	O
budget	NN	O	6	nmod	O
for	IN	O	18	case	O
the	DT	O	18	det	O
Missile	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	18	compound	B-ORG
Defense	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	18	compound	I-ORG
Agency	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	13	nmod	I-ORG
-LRB-	NNP	O	20	punct	O
MDA	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	18	appos	B-ORG
-RRB-	NNP	O	20	punct	O
over	IN	O	26	case	O
the	DT	B-DURATION	26	det	O
next	JJ	I-DURATION	26	amod	O
4	CD	I-DURATION	26	nummod	O
years	NNS	I-DURATION	6	nmod	O
.	.	O	6	punct	O

This	DT	O	0	ROOT	O
is	VBZ	O	4	nsubj	O
in	IN	O	4	cop	O
addition	NN	O	4	case	O
to	TO	O	10	case	O
the	DT	O	10	det	O
$	$	B-MONEY	10	amod	O
1.4	CD	I-MONEY	9	compound	O
billion	CD	I-MONEY	7	nummod	O
reduction	NN	O	4	nmod	O
for	IN	O	12	case	O
MDA	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	10	nmod	B-ORG
from	IN	O	14	case	O
2009	CD	B-DATE	10	nmod	O
to	TO	I-DATE	16	case	O
2013	CD	I-DATE	14	nmod	O
.	.	O	4	punct	O

``	``	O	0	ROOT	O
I	PRP	O	57	punct	O
'm	VBP	O	4	nsubj	O
disappointed	JJ	O	4	cop	O
,	,	O	57	ccomp	O
very	RB	O	4	punct	O
much	JJ	O	7	advmod	O
,	,	O	4	advmod	O
in	IN	O	4	punct	O
the	DT	O	11	case	O
reductions	NNS	O	11	det	O
to	TO	O	4	nmod	O
the	DT	O	16	case	O
missile	NN	O	16	det	O
defense	NN	O	16	compound	O
budget	NN	O	16	compound	O
over	IN	O	11	nmod	O
the	DT	B-DURATION	21	case	O
last	JJ	B-DATE	21	det	O
four	CD	I-DATE	21	amod	O
years	NNS	I-DATE	21	nummod	O
,	,	O	11	nmod	O
much	RB	O	4	punct	O
of	IN	O	27	nsubj	O
which	WDT	O	25	case	O
has	VBZ	O	23	nmod	O
come	VBN	O	27	aux	O
at	IN	O	4	ccomp	O
the	DT	O	30	case	O
expense	NN	O	30	det	O
of	IN	O	27	nmod	O
our	PRP$	O	34	case	O
homeland	NN	O	34	nmod:poss	O
defense	NN	O	34	compound	O
as	RB	O	30	nmod	O
well	RB	O	30	cc	O
as	IN	O	35	mwe	O
the	DT	O	35	mwe	O
development	NN	O	39	det	O
of	IN	O	30	conj	O
next-generation	NN	O	44	case	O
missile	NN	O	44	amod	O
defense	NN	O	44	compound	O
systems	NNS	O	44	compound	B-P1
,	,	O	39	nmod	I-P1
''	''	O	57	punct	I-P1
retiring	VBG	O	57	punct	I-P1
Sen.	NNP	O	50	amod	O
Jon	NNP	B-PERSON	50	compound	O
Kyl	NNP	I-PERSON	50	compound	O
,	,	O	57	nsubj	O
a	DT	O	50	punct	O
noted	JJ	O	55	det	O
defense	NN	O	55	amod	B-REL
hawk	NN	O	55	compound	I-REL
,	,	O	50	appos	I-REL
told	VBD	O	50	punct	I-REL
a	DT	O	60	det	I-REL
recent	JJ	O	60	amod	I-REL
forum	NN	O	57	dobj	O
sponsored	VBN	O	60	acl	B-ORG
by	IN	O	68	case	I-ORG
the	DT	O	68	det	I-ORG
American	JJ	B-NATIONALITY	68	compound	I-ORG
Foreign	NNP	B-MISC	68	compound	O
Policy	NNP	I-MISC	68	compound	O
Council.For	NNP	I-MISC	68	compound	O
example	NN	O	61	nmod	O
,	,	O	57	punct	O
the	DT	O	71	det	O
president	NN	B-TITLE	74	nmod:poss	O
's	POS	O	71	case	O
2013	CD	B-DATE	74	nummod	O
budget	NN	O	75	nsubj	O
slashed	VBD	O	57	dep	O
the	DT	O	77	det	O
number	NN	O	75	dobj	O
of	IN	O	80	case	O
Ground-Based	JJ	O	80	amod	O
Interceptors	NNS	O	77	nmod	O
-LRB-	VBP	O	82	punct	O
GBIs	NNP	O	80	appos	O
-RRB-	NNP	O	82	punct	B-REL
-	:	O	75	punct	I-REL
our	PRP$	O	87	nmod:poss	I-REL
first	JJ	B-ORDINAL	87	amod	I-REL
line	NN	O	75	dobj	I-REL
of	IN	O	89	case	I-REL
defense	NN	O	87	nmod	O
against	IN	O	94	case	O
a	DT	O	94	det	O
long-range	JJ	O	94	amod	O
missile	NN	O	94	compound	O
attack	NN	B-CAUSE_OF_DEATH	87	nmod	O
from	IN	O	97	case	O
North	NNP	B-COUNTRY	97	compound	O
Korea	NNP	I-COUNTRY	94	nmod	O
-	:	O	87	punct	O
from	IN	O	101	case	O
44	CD	B-NUMBER	101	nummod	O
interceptors	NNS	O	87	nmod	O

A	DT	O	0	ROOT	O
third	JJ	B-ORDINAL	4	det	O
GBI	NNP	O	4	amod	O
site	NN	O	4	compound	O
along	IN	O	9	nsubj	O
the	DT	O	8	case	O
East	NNP	B-LOCATION	8	det	O
Coast	NNP	I-LOCATION	8	compound	O
continues	VBZ	O	4	nmod	B-REL
to	TO	O	14	mark	I-REL
be	VB	O	14	cop	I-REL
a	DT	O	14	det	I-REL
hot	JJ	O	14	amod	I-REL
topic	NN	O	9	xcomp	I-REL
on	IN	O	17	case	I-REL
Capitol	NNP	B-LOCATION	17	compound	B-ORG
Hill	NNP	I-LOCATION	14	nmod	I-ORG
,	,	O	9	punct	O
but	CC	O	9	cc	O
the	DT	O	21	det	O
potential	NN	O	27	nsubj	O
for	IN	O	23	mark	O
funding	NN	O	21	acl	O
such	JJ	O	26	det:predet	O
a	DT	O	26	det	O
program	NN	O	23	dobj	O
appears	VBZ	O	9	conj	O
dim	JJ	O	27	xcomp	O
considering	VBG	O	28	acl	O
we	PRP	O	34	nsubj	O
are	VBP	O	34	aux	O
n't	RB	O	34	neg	O
properly	RB	O	34	advmod	O
supporting	VBG	O	29	ccomp	O
the	DT	O	36	det	O
sites	NNS	O	34	dobj	O
we	PRP	O	39	nsubj	O
already	RB	O	39	advmod	O
have	VBP	O	36	acl:relcl	O
in	IN	O	41	case	O
Alaska	NNP	B-STATE_OR_PROVINCE	39	nmod	O
and	CC	O	41	cc	O
California	NNP	B-STATE_OR_PROVINCE	41	conj	O
.	.	O	9	punct	O

As	IN	O	0	ROOT	O
Sen.	NNP	O	5	mark	B-P1
Kyl	NNP	B-PERSON	3	compound	I-P1
aptly	RB	O	5	nsubj	O
noted	VBD	O	5	advmod	O
in	IN	O	16	advcl	O
his	PRP$	O	8	case	O
comments	NNS	O	8	nmod:poss	O
to	TO	O	5	nmod	O
AFPC	NNP	O	10	case	B-ORGC
,	,	O	8	nmod	O
funding	NN	O	16	punct	O
for	IN	O	16	nsubj	O
GBIs	NNP	O	14	case	O
has	VBZ	O	12	nmod	O
decreased	VBN	O	16	aux	O
from	IN	O	18	case	O
$	$	B-MONEY	16	nmod	O
2.5	CD	I-MONEY	20	compound	O
billion	CD	I-MONEY	18	nummod	O
annually	RB	B-SET	18	advmod	O
under	IN	O	24	case	O
President	NNP	B-TITLE	24	compound	B-P1
Bush	NNP	B-PERSON	16	nmod	I-P1
to	TO	O	27	case	O
only	RB	O	27	advmod	O
$	$	B-MONEY	16	nmod	O
1	CD	I-MONEY	29	compound	O
billion	CD	I-MONEY	27	nummod	O
under	IN	O	36	case	O
the	DT	O	36	det	O
Obama	NNP	B-PERSON	36	compound	O
administration.The	VBZ	O	36	compound	O
next-generation	JJ	O	36	amod	O
Standard	NNP	O	36	compound	O
Missile-3	NNP	O	27	nmod	O
-LRB-	NNP	O	38	punct	O
SM-3	NNP	O	36	appos	O
-RRB-	NNP	O	38	punct	O
has	VBZ	O	44	aux	O
also	RB	O	44	advmod	O
been	VBN	O	44	cop	O
a	DT	O	44	det	O
target	NN	O	16	dobj	O
of	IN	O	47	case	O
significant	JJ	O	47	amod	O
cuts	NNS	O	44	nmod	O
,	,	O	44	punct	O
this	DT	O	70	nsubj	O
despite	IN	O	55	case	O
two	CD	B-NUMBER	55	nummod	O
high-profile	NN	O	55	amod	O
,	,	O	55	punct	O
successful	JJ	O	55	amod	O
tests	NNS	O	70	nmod	O
of	IN	O	58	case	O
the	DT	O	58	det	O
interceptor	NN	O	55	nmod	O
this	DT	B-DATE	60	det	O
spring	NN	I-DATE	55	dep	O
and	CC	O	60	cc	O
summer.Currently	RB	O	60	conj	O
,	,	O	70	punct	O
the	DT	O	65	det	O
U.S.	NNP	B-COUNTRY	70	nsubj	O
and	CC	O	65	cc	O
Japanese	JJ	B-NATIONALITY	68	compound	O
navies	NNS	O	65	conj	O
are	VBP	O	70	aux	O
employing	VBG	O	44	acl:relcl	O
more	JJR	O	73	advmod	O
than	IN	O	71	mwe	O
130	CD	B-NUMBER	75	nummod	O
first-generation	JJ	O	75	amod	O
SM-3s	NNP	O	70	dobj	O
,	,	O	70	punct	O
but	CC	O	70	cc	B-WEA
the	DT	O	80	det	I-WEA
upgraded	JJ	O	80	amod	O
missile	NN	O	93	nsubj	O
,	,	O	80	punct	O
which	WDT	O	84	nsubjpass	O
is	VBZ	O	84	auxpass	O
set	VBN	O	80	acl:relcl	O
to	TO	O	86	mark	O
roll	VB	O	84	xcomp	O
off	RP	O	86	compound:prt	O
production	NN	O	89	compound	O
lines	NNS	O	86	dobj	O
in	IN	O	91	case	O
2015	CD	B-DATE	86	nmod	O
,	,	O	80	punct	O
offers	VBZ	O	70	conj	O
enhanced	JJ	O	95	amod	O
capabilities	NNS	O	93	dobj	O
to	TO	O	97	mark	O
protect	VB	O	95	acl	O
America	NNP	B-COUNTRY	97	dobj	O
and	CC	O	98	cc	B-ORG
its	PRP$	O	101	nmod:poss	O
allies.MDA	NN	O	104	nmod:poss	O
's	POS	O	101	case	O
original	JJ	O	104	amod	O
plan	NN	O	98	conj	O
was	VBD	O	93	dep	O
to	TO	O	107	mark	O
buy	VB	O	105	xcomp	O
62	CD	B-NUMBER	111	nummod	O
SM-3	JJ	O	111	compound	O
``	``	O	111	punct	O
I-Bs	JJ	O	107	dobj	O
''	''	O	107	punct	O
but	CC	O	107	cc	O
in	IN	O	119	case	O
his	PRP$	O	119	nmod:poss	O
2013	CD	B-DATE	119	nummod	B-P1
budget	NN	O	119	compound	I-P1
President	NNP	B-TITLE	119	compound	O
Obama	NNP	B-PERSON	120	nmod	O
cut	VBD	O	107	conj	O
that	DT	O	122	det	O
number	NN	O	120	dobj	O
to	TO	O	126	case	O
a	DT	O	126	det	O
meager	NN	O	126	amod	O
29	CD	B-NUMBER	120	nmod	O
and	CC	O	120	cc	O
sliced	VBD	O	120	conj	O
the	DT	O	131	det	O
I-B	NNP	O	131	compound	O
budget	NN	O	128	dobj	O

The	DT	O	0	ROOT	O
timing	NN	O	2	det	O
could	MD	O	6	nsubj	O
not	RB	O	6	aux	O
be	VB	O	6	neg	O
worse	JJR	O	6	cop	O
considering	VBG	O	6	xcomp	O
that	IN	O	14	mark	O
commanders	NNS	O	14	nsubj	O
in	IN	O	12	case	O
the	DT	O	12	det	O
field	NN	O	9	nmod	O
are	VBP	O	14	aux	O
saying	VBG	O	7	ccomp	O
that	IN	O	26	mark	O
our	PRP$	O	18	nmod:poss	O
current	JJ	B-DATE	18	amod	O
inventories	NNS	O	26	nsubj	O
of	IN	O	20	case	O
SM-3s	NNP	O	18	nmod	O
aboard	IN	O	23	case	O
Aegis	NNP	O	23	compound	O
ships	NNS	O	20	nmod	O
are	VBP	O	26	cop	O

A	DT	O	0	ROOT	O
recent	JJ	O	5	det	O
classified	JJ	O	5	amod	O
STRATCOM	NNP	O	5	amod	O
exercise	NN	O	5	compound	O
,	,	O	11	nsubj	O
reported	VBN	O	5	punct	O
by	IN	O	5	acl	O
InsideDefense.com	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	9	case	O
,	,	O	7	nmod	O
confirmed	VBD	O	5	punct	B-REL
the	DT	O	13	det	I-REL
assertion	NN	O	11	dobj	I-REL
of	IN	O	18	case	I-REL
a	DT	O	18	det	O
ballistic	JJ	O	18	amod	B-WEA
missile	NN	O	18	compound	I-WEA
shortfall.Most	NN	O	13	nmod	O
significantly	RB	O	11	advmod	O
,	,	O	11	punct	O
these	DT	O	22	det	O
cuts	NNS	O	29	nsubj	O
to	TO	O	24	case	O
GBIs	NNP	O	22	nmod	O
and	CC	O	24	cc	O
SM-3s	NNP	O	24	conj	O
do	VBP	O	29	aux	O
not	RB	O	29	neg	O
take	VB	O	11	ccomp	O
into	IN	O	31	case	O
account	NN	O	29	nmod	O
the	DT	O	33	det	O
prospect	NN	O	29	dobj	O
of	IN	O	35	case	O
sequestration	NN	O	33	nmod	O
.	.	O	11	punct	O

In	IN	O	0	ROOT	O
a	DT	O	3	case	O
letter	NN	O	3	det	O
to	TO	O	10	nmod	O
Congress	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	5	case	B-ORG
last	JJ	B-DATE	3	nmod	O
month	NN	I-DATE	7	amod	O
,	,	O	3	nmod:tmod	O
Panetta	NNP	B-PERSON	10	punct	O
warned	VBD	O	10	nsubj	O
that	IN	O	14	mark	O
sequestration	NN	O	14	nsubj	O
would	MD	O	14	aux	O
result	VB	O	10	ccomp	O
in	IN	O	21	case	O
an	DT	O	21	det	O
additional	JJ	O	21	amod	O
``	``	O	21	punct	O
23	CD	B-PERCENT	21	nummod	O
percent	NN	I-PERCENT	21	compound	O
cut	NN	O	14	nmod	O
in	IN	O	24	case	O
weapons	NNS	O	24	compound	B-PROG
program	NN	O	21	nmod	I-PROG
would	MD	O	26	aux	O
drive	VB	O	14	ccomp	O
up	RP	O	26	compound:prt	O
unit	NN	O	29	compound	O
costs	NNS	O	26	dobj	O
and	CC	O	26	cc	O
lead	VB	O	26	conj	O
to	TO	O	33	case	O
reductions	NNS	O	31	nmod	O
in	IN	O	35	case	O
quantity	NN	O	33	nmod	O
of	IN	O	38	case	O
one	CD	B-NUMBER	38	nummod	O
third	NN	B-ORDINAL	35	nmod	O
or	CC	O	40	cc	O
more	JJR	O	38	nummod	O
.	.	O	10	punct	O

``	``	O	0	ROOT	O
While	IN	O	8	mark	O
both	DT	O	4	cc:preconj	O
Democrats	NNPS	B-IDEOLOGY	8	nsubj	O
and	CC	O	4	cc	O
Republicans	NNPS	B-MISC	4	conj	O
can	MD	O	8	aux	O
agree	VB	O	31	advcl	O
that	DT	O	14	mark	O
current	JJ	B-DATE	12	amod	O
budget	NN	O	12	compound	O
deficits	NNS	O	14	nsubj	O
are	VBP	O	14	cop	O
unsustainable	JJ	O	8	ccomp	O
,	,	O	31	punct	O
shrinking	VBG	O	31	csubj	O
the	DT	O	21	det	O
U.S.	NNP	B-COUNTRY	21	compound	B-DOC
missile	NN	O	21	compound	I-DOC
defense	NN	O	21	compound	I-DOC
budget	NN	O	16	dobj	I-DOC
at	IN	O	24	case	O
a	DT	O	24	det	O
time	NN	O	16	nmod	O
when	WRB	O	29	advmod	O
threats	NNS	O	29	nsubj	O
are	VBP	O	29	aux	O
exponentially	RB	O	29	advmod	O
increasing	VBG	O	24	acl:relcl	O
could	MD	O	31	aux	O
prove	VB	O	1	root	O
pennywise	NN	O	31	xcomp	O
but	CC	O	32	cc	O
pound	NN	O	32	conj	O
foolish	NN	O	32	dep	O
.	.	O	31	punct	O

After	IN	O	0	ROOT	O
all	DT	O	2	case	O
,	,	O	12	nmod	O
North	NNP	B-COUNTRY	12	punct	O
Korea	NNP	I-COUNTRY	5	compound	O
is	VBZ	O	12	nsubj	O
far	RB	O	12	cop	O
from	IN	O	12	advmod	O
the	DT	O	12	case	O
only	JJ	O	12	det	O
hostile	JJ	O	12	amod	O
nation	NN	O	12	amod	O
on	IN	O	15	case	O
our	PRP$	O	15	nmod:poss	O
radar	NN	O	12	nmod	O
.	.	O	12	punct	O

Iran	NNP	B-COUNTRY	0	ROOT	O
and	CC	O	4	nsubj	O
Syria	NNP	B-COUNTRY	1	cc	O
remain	VBP	O	1	conj	O
aggressive	JJ	O	4	xcomp	O
,	,	O	4	punct	O
and	CC	O	4	cc	O
the	DT	O	9	det	O
threat	NN	O	21	nsubj	O
of	IN	O	13	case	O
Syria	NNP	B-COUNTRY	13	nmod:poss	O
's	POS	O	11	case	O
weapons	NNS	O	9	nmod	O
falling	VBG	O	13	acl	O
into	IN	O	17	case	O
the	DT	O	17	det	O
hands	NNS	O	14	nmod	O
of	IN	O	20	case	O
jihadi-minded	JJ	O	20	amod	O
militias	NN	O	17	nmod	O
poses	VBZ	O	4	conj	O
a	DT	O	25	det	O
very	RB	O	24	advmod	O
real	JJ	O	25	amod	O
threat	NN	O	21	dobj	O
to	TO	O	28	case	O
global	JJ	O	28	amod	O
security.Avoiding	NN	O	25	nmod	O
such	PDT	O	31	amod	O
a	DT	O	31	det	O
fate	NN	O	33	nsubj	O
will	MD	O	33	aux	O
take	VB	O	28	acl:relcl	O
real	JJ	O	35	amod	O
compromise	NN	O	33	dobj	O
from	IN	O	37	case	B-ORG
Congress	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	33	nmod	O
and	CC	O	33	cc	O
the	DT	O	40	det	O
president	NN	B-TITLE	33	conj	O
over	IN	O	45	case	O
the	DT	B-DURATION	45	det	O
next	JJ	I-DURATION	45	amod	O
few	JJ	I-DURATION	45	amod	O
days	NNS	I-DURATION	40	nmod	O

Without	IN	O	0	ROOT	O
a	DT	O	3	case	O
deal	NN	O	3	det	O
to	TO	O	24	nmod	O
avoid	VB	O	5	mark	O
even	RB	O	3	acl	O
more	RBR	O	8	advmod	O
severe	JJ	O	8	advmod	O
cuts	NNS	O	9	amod	O
to	TO	O	5	dobj	O
defense	NN	O	11	case	O
,	,	O	9	nmod	O
the	DT	O	24	punct	O
American	JJ	B-NATIONALITY	15	det	O
people	NNS	O	15	amod	O
may	MD	O	24	nsubj	O
well	RB	O	24	aux	O
be	VB	O	24	advmod	O
in	IN	O	24	cop	O
``	``	O	24	case	O
the	DT	O	24	punct	O
most	RBS	O	24	det	O
terrible	JJ	O	23	advmod	O
trouble	NN	O	24	amod	O
.	.	O	24	punct	O

``	``	O	0	ROOT	O
One	CD	B-NUMBER	18	punct	O
thing	NN	O	3	nummod	O
that	WDT	O	18	ccomp	O
should	MD	O	7	nsubj	O
be	VB	O	7	aux	O
clear	JJ	O	7	cop	O
to	TO	O	3	acl:relcl	O
the	DT	O	11	case	O
collective	JJ	O	11	det	O
intelligentsia	NN	O	11	amod	O
and	CC	O	7	nmod	O
politicians	NNS	O	11	cc	O
,	,	O	11	conj	O
strategic	JJ	O	18	punct	O
surprise	NN	O	16	amod	O
will	MD	O	18	nsubj	O
happen	VB	O	18	aux	O
.	.	O	18	punct	O

The	DT	O	0	ROOT	O
American	JJ	B-NATIONALITY	3	det	O
people	NNS	O	3	amod	O
and	CC	O	10	nsubj	O
our	PRP$	O	3	cc	O
allies	NNS	O	6	nmod:poss	O
just	RB	O	3	conj	O
do	VBP	O	10	advmod	O
n't	RB	O	10	aux	O
deserve	VB	O	10	neg	O
to	TO	O	12	mark	O
have	VB	O	10	xcomp	O
a	DT	O	15	det	O
North	JJ	B-NATIONALITY	15	amod	O
Korean	JJ	I-NATIONALITY	12	dobj	O
or	CC	O	15	cc	O
Iranian	JJ	B-NATIONALITY	19	amod	O
missile	NN	O	19	compound	O
land	NN	O	15	conj	O
on	IN	O	22	case	O
our	PRP$	O	22	nmod:poss	O
heads	NNS	O	12	nmod	O
because	IN	O	25	mark	O
we	PRP	O	25	nsubj	O
failed	VBD	O	36	csubj	O
to	TO	O	28	mark	O
properly	VB	O	28	advmod	O
fund	NN	O	25	xcomp	O
missile	NN	O	31	compound	O
defense.Randy	JJ	O	31	compound	O
Duncan	NNP	B-PERSON	28	dobj	O
is	VBZ	O	36	cop	O
a	DT	O	36	det	O
retired	JJ	O	36	amod	O
Navy	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	36	compound	B-ORG
captain	NN	B-TITLE	10	ccomp	O
who	WP	O	38	nsubj	O
served	VBD	O	36	acl:relcl	B-REL
at	IN	O	42	case	I-REL
the	DT	O	42	det	O
Defense	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	42	compound	B-ORG
Missile	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	38	nmod	I-ORG
and	CC	I-ORGANIZATION	42	cc	I-ORG
Space	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	46	compound	I-ORG
Intelligence	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	46	compound	I-ORG
Center	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	42	conj	I-ORG
and	CC	O	42	cc	O
the	DT	O	52	det	O
Defense	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	52	compound	O
Intelligence	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	52	compound	O
Agency.This	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	52	compound	O
entry	NN	O	42	conj	O
was	VBD	O	54	auxpass	O
posted	VBN	O	36	acl	O
in	IN	O	56	case	O
Publications	NNP	O	54	nmod	O
and	CC	O	36	cc	O
tagged	VBD	O	36	conj	O
Ground-Based	JJ	B-MISC	60	compound	O
Interceptor	NNP	I-MISC	58	dobj	O
-LRB-	NNP	O	62	punct	O
GBI	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	60	appos	O
-RRB-	NNP	O	62	punct	O
,	,	O	60	punct	O
Iran	NNP	B-COUNTRY	60	appos	O
,	,	O	60	punct	O
Jon	NNP	B-PERSON	68	compound	O
Kyl	NNP	I-PERSON	60	appos	O
,	,	O	60	punct	O
Leon	NNP	B-PERSON	71	compound	O
Panetta	NNP	I-PERSON	60	appos	O
,	,	O	60	punct	O
North	NNP	B-COUNTRY	74	compound	O
Korea	NNP	I-COUNTRY	60	appos	O
,	,	O	60	punct	O
Standard	NNP	O	77	compound	O
Missile-3	NNP	O	60	conj	O
-LRB-	NNP	O	79	punct	O
SM-3	NNP	O	77	appos	O
-RRB-	NNP	O	79	punct	O
,	,	O	60	punct	O
Syria	NNP	B-COUNTRY	60	conj	O
,	,	O	60	punct	O
Budget	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	60	conj	O
,	,	O	60	punct	O
Missile	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	88	compound	O
Defense	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	88	compound	B-ORG
Agency	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	60	appos	I-ORG
by	IN	O	90	case	I-ORG
editor	NN	B-TITLE	88	nmod	O
.	.	O	10	punct	O

Bookmark	NNP	O	0	ROOT	O
the	DT	O	3	nsubj	O
permalink	NN	O	3	det	O
.	.	O	3	punct	O
Last	JJ	O	0	ROOT	O
updated	JJ	O	2	advmod	O
:	:	O	2	punct	O
December	NNP	B-DATE	2	dep	O
31	CD	I-DATE	4	nummod	O
,	,	I-DATE	4	punct	O
2012	CD	I-DATE	4	nummod	O
at	IN	B-TIME	10	case	O
12:14	CD	I-TIME	10	nummod	O
pmdocno	NN	O	4	nmod	O
:	:	O	4	punct	O
112713	CD	B-NUMBER	15	nummod	O
Missile	NNP	O	15	compound	B-PROG
ThreatA	NNP	O	15	compound	I-PROG
Project	NNP	O	4	dep	I-PROG
of	IN	O	20	case	O
the	DT	O	20	det	O
George	NNP	B-PERSON	20	compound	O
C.	NNP	I-PERSON	20	compound	O
Marshall	NNP	I-PERSON	15	nmod	O
and	CC	O	20	cc	O
Claremont	NNP	B-CITY	24	compound	O
InstitutesMaking	NNP	B-MISC	24	compound	O
Sense	NNP	I-MISC	20	conj	O
of	IN	I-MISC	28	case	O
Ballistic	NNP	I-MISC	28	compound	B-PROG
Missile	NNP	I-MISC	28	compound	I-PROG
Defense	NNP	I-MISC	20	nmod	I-PROG
:	:	O	4	punct	O
An	DT	O	31	det	O
Assessment	NN	O	73	nsubj	B-TECH
of	IN	O	33	case	I-TECH
Concepts	NNP	O	31	nmod	I-TECH
and	CC	O	33	cc	I-TECH
Systems	NNP	O	33	conj	I-TECH
for	IN	O	40	case	O
U.S.	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	40	compound	O
Boost-Phase	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	40	compound	O
Missile	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	40	compound	O
Defense	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	31	nmod	O
in	IN	O	42	case	O
Comparison	NNP	O	31	nmod	B-ORG
to	TO	O	47	case	I-ORG
Other	JJ	O	47	amod	O
AlternativesNational	NNP	O	47	compound	O
Academies	NNP	O	47	compound	O
PressPosted	NNP	O	42	nmod	O
on	IN	O	49	case	O
January	NNP	B-DATE	42	nmod	O
3	CD	I-DATE	49	nummod	O
,	,	I-DATE	49	punct	O
2013	CD	I-DATE	49	nummod	O
by	IN	O	55	case	O
editor0309216109The	JJ	O	55	compound	O
Committee	NNP	O	42	nmod	B-TECH
on	IN	O	58	case	I-TECH
an	DT	O	58	det	I-TECH
Assessment	NN	O	55	nmod	I-TECH
of	IN	O	60	case	I-TECH
Concepts	NNP	O	58	nmod	B-REL
and	CC	O	60	cc	O
Systems	NNP	O	60	conj	O
for	IN	O	67	case	O
U.S.	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	67	compound	O
Boost-Phase	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	67	compound	O
Missile	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	67	compound	O
Defense	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	58	nmod	O
in	IN	O	69	case	O
Comparison	NNP	O	31	nmod	O
to	TO	O	72	case	O
Other	JJ	O	72	amod	O
Alternatives	NNS	O	69	nmod	O
set	VBD	O	4	parataxis	O
forth	NN	O	73	advmod	O
to	TO	O	76	mark	O
provide	VB	O	73	xcomp	O
an	DT	O	78	det	O
assessment	NN	O	76	dobj	O
of	IN	O	81	case	O
the	DT	O	81	det	O
feasibility	NN	O	78	nmod	O
,	,	O	81	punct	O
practicality	NN	O	81	conj	B-REL
,	,	O	81	punct	I-REL
and	CC	O	81	cc	I-REL
affordability	NN	O	81	conj	I-REL
of	IN	O	91	case	O
U.S.	NNP	B-COUNTRY	91	compound	O
boost-phase	NN	O	91	amod	O
missile	NN	O	91	compound	O
defense	NN	O	86	nmod	O
compared	VBN	O	94	case	O
with	IN	O	94	case	O
that	DT	O	140	nmod	O
of	IN	O	100	case	O
the	DT	O	100	det	O
U.S.	NNP	B-COUNTRY	100	compound	O
non-boost	JJ	O	100	amod	O
missile	NN	O	100	compound	B-WEA
defense	NN	O	94	nmod	I-WEA
when	WRB	O	102	advmod	O
countering	VBG	O	140	csubj	O
short	JJ	O	106	amod	O
-	:	O	106	punct	O
,	,	O	106	punct	O
medium	NN	O	102	dobj	O
-	:	O	106	punct	O
,	,	O	106	punct	O
and	CC	O	106	cc	O
intermediate-range	JJ	O	113	amod	O
ballistic	JJ	O	113	amod	O
missile	NN	O	113	compound	O
threats	NNS	O	106	conj	O
from	IN	O	116	case	O
rogue	NN	O	116	amod	O
states	NNS	O	113	nmod	O
to	TO	O	119	case	O
deployed	VB	O	119	amod	O
forces	NNS	O	113	nmod	O
of	IN	O	123	case	O
the	DT	O	123	det	O
United	NNP	B-COUNTRY	123	compound	O
States	NNPS	I-COUNTRY	119	nmod	O
and	CC	O	119	cc	O
its	PRP$	O	126	nmod:poss	B-WEA
allies	NNS	O	119	conj	I-WEA
and	CC	O	126	cc	O
defending	VBG	O	126	conj	O
the	DT	O	130	det	O
territory	NN	O	128	dobj	O
of	IN	O	134	case	O
the	DT	O	134	det	O
United	NNP	B-COUNTRY	134	compound	O
States	NNPS	I-COUNTRY	130	nmod	O
against	IN	O	139	case	O
limited	VBN	O	139	amod	O
ballistic	JJ	O	139	amod	O
missile	NN	O	139	compound	O
attack.To	NN	O	126	nmod	O
provide	VBP	O	73	parataxis	O
a	DT	O	142	det	O
context	NN	O	140	dobj	O
for	IN	O	145	case	O
this	DT	O	145	det	O
analysis	NN	O	142	nmod	O
of	IN	O	147	case	O
present	JJ	B-DATE	145	nmod	O
and	CC	O	147	cc	O
proposed	JJ	O	151	amod	O
U.S.	NNP	B-COUNTRY	151	compound	O
boost-phase	NN	O	147	conj	O
and	CC	O	147	cc	O
non-boost	JJ	O	147	conj	B-WEA
missile	NN	O	156	compound	I-WEA
defense	NN	O	156	compound	O
concepts	NNS	O	147	dep	O
and	CC	O	147	cc	O
systems	NNS	O	147	conj	O
,	,	O	140	punct	O
the	DT	O	161	det	O
committee	NN	O	162	nsubj	O
considered	VBD	O	140	parataxis	O
the	DT	O	164	det	O
following	VBG	O	162	xcomp	O
to	TO	O	168	mark	O
be	VB	O	168	cop	B-WEA
the	DT	O	168	det	I-WEA
missions	NNS	O	164	xcomp	O
for	IN	O	172	case	O
ballistic	JJ	O	172	amod	O
missile	NN	O	172	compound	O
defense	NN	O	168	nmod	O
-LRB-	NN	O	174	punct	O
BMD	NNP	O	172	appos	O
-RRB-	NN	O	174	punct	O
:	:	O	168	punct	O
protecting	NN	O	168	dep	O
of	IN	O	181	case	O
the	DT	O	181	det	B-WEA
U.S.	NNP	B-COUNTRY	181	compound	I-WEA
homeland	NN	O	177	nmod	O
against	IN	O	184	case	O
nuclear	JJ	O	184	amod	O
weapons	NNS	O	181	nmod	O
and	CC	O	184	cc	O
other	JJ	O	187	amod	O
weapons	NNS	O	184	conj	O
of	IN	O	190	case	B-REL
mass	NN	O	190	compound	O
destruction	NN	O	187	nmod	O
-LRB-	NNP	O	192	punct	O
WMD	NNP	O	190	appos	B-ORG
-RRB-	NNP	O	192	punct	O
;	:	O	177	punct	B-WEA
or	CC	O	177	cc	I-WEA
conventional	JJ	O	199	amod	I-WEA
ballistic	JJ	O	199	amod	I-WEA
missile	NN	O	199	compound	O
attacks	NNS	B-CAUSE_OF_DEATH	177	conj	O
;	:	O	168	punct	O
protection	NN	O	168	dep	O
of	IN	O	204	case	O
U.S.	NNP	B-COUNTRY	204	compound	B-REL
forces	NNS	O	201	nmod	O
,	,	O	204	punct	O
including	VBG	O	208	case	O
military	JJ	O	208	amod	B-ORG
bases	NNS	O	204	nmod	O
,	,	O	208	punct	O
logistics	NNS	O	208	conj	B-WEA
,	,	O	208	punct	I-WEA
command	NN	O	208	conj	I-WEA
and	CC	O	208	cc	I-WEA
control	NN	O	215	compound	O

They	PRP	O	0	ROOT	O
also	RB	O	3	nsubj	O
considered	VBD	O	3	advmod	O
deployed	JJ	O	5	amod	O
forces	NNS	O	3	dobj	O
themselves	PRP	O	5	nmod:npmod	O
in	IN	O	8	case	O
theaters	NNS	O	5	nmod	O
of	IN	O	10	case	O
operation	NN	O	8	nmod	O
against	IN	O	14	case	O
ballistic	JJ	O	14	amod	B-WEA
missile	NN	O	14	compound	I-WEA
attacks	NNS	B-CAUSE_OF_DEATH	8	nmod	O
armed	VBN	O	14	acl	B-REL
with	IN	O	17	case	I-REL
WMD	NNP	O	15	nmod	O
or	CC	O	17	cc	O
conventional	JJ	O	20	amod	B-WEA
munitions	NNS	O	17	conj	I-WEA
,	,	O	5	punct	O
and	CC	O	5	cc	O
protection	NN	O	5	conj	O
of	IN	O	26	case	O
U.S.	NNP	B-COUNTRY	26	compound	B-ORG
allies	NNS	O	23	nmod	I-ORG
,	,	O	26	punct	O
partners	NNS	O	26	conj	O
,	,	O	26	punct	O
and	CC	O	26	cc	O
host	NN	B-TITLE	32	compound	B-ORG
nations	NNS	O	26	conj	I-ORG
against	IN	O	35	case	O
ballistic-missile-delivered	JJ	O	35	amod	O
WMD	NNP	O	23	nmod	O
and	CC	O	35	cc	O
conventional	JJ	O	38	amod	O
weapons.Consistent	NN	O	35	conj	B-DOC
with	IN	O	41	case	I-DOC
U.S.	NNP	B-COUNTRY	41	compound	O
policy	NN	O	23	nmod	O
and	CC	O	41	cc	O
the	DT	O	45	det	O
congressional	JJ	O	45	amod	O
tasking	NN	O	41	conj	O
,	,	O	45	punct	O
the	DT	O	48	det	O
committee	NN	O	49	nsubj	O
conducted	VBD	O	45	acl:relcl	O
its	PRP$	O	51	nmod:poss	O
analysis	NN	O	49	dobj	O
on	IN	O	54	case	O
the	DT	O	54	det	O
basis	NN	O	51	nmod	O
that	IN	O	60	mark	O
it	PRP	O	60	nsubj	O
is	VBZ	O	60	cop	O
not	RB	O	60	neg	O
a	DT	O	60	det	O
mission	NN	O	54	ccomp	B-WEA
of	IN	O	64	case	I-WEA
U.S.	NNP	B-COUNTRY	64	compound	I-WEA
BMD	NNP	O	64	compound	O
systems	NNS	O	60	nmod	O
to	TO	O	66	mark	O
defend	VB	O	60	xcomp	O
against	IN	O	71	case	O
large-scale	JJ	O	71	amod	O
deliberate	NN	O	71	amod	O
nuclear	JJ	O	71	amod	O
attacks	NNS	B-CAUSE_OF_DEATH	66	nmod	O
by	IN	O	73	case	O
Russia	NNP	B-COUNTRY	71	nmod	O
or	CC	O	73	cc	O

Making	VBG	O	0	ROOT	O
Sense	NN	O	1	dobj	O
of	IN	O	6	case	O
Ballistic	NNP	O	6	compound	B-PROG
Missile	NNP	O	6	compound	I-PROG
Defense	NNP	O	2	nmod	I-PROG
:	:	O	1	punct	O
An	DT	O	9	det	O
Assessment	NN	O	24	nsubj	B-TECH
of	IN	O	11	case	I-TECH
Concepts	NNP	O	9	nmod	I-TECH
and	CC	O	11	cc	I-TECH
Systems	NNP	O	11	conj	I-TECH
for	IN	O	18	case	O
U.S.	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	18	compound	O
Boost-Phase	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	18	compound	O
Missile	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	18	compound	O
Defense	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	9	nmod	O
in	IN	O	20	case	O
Comparison	NNP	O	9	nmod	O
to	TO	O	23	case	O
Other	JJ	O	23	amod	O
Alternatives	NNS	O	20	nmod	O
suggests	VBZ	O	1	parataxis	O
that	IN	O	30	mark	O
great	JJ	O	27	amod	O
care	NN	O	30	nsubjpass	O
should	MD	O	30	aux	O
be	VB	O	30	auxpass	O
taken	VBN	O	24	ccomp	O
by	IN	O	33	case	O
the	DT	O	33	det	O
U.S.	NNP	B-COUNTRY	30	nmod	O
in	IN	O	35	mark	O
ensuring	VBG	O	30	advcl	O
that	IN	O	46	mark	B-DOC
negotiations	NNS	O	46	nsubj	I-DOC
on	IN	O	40	case	O
space	NN	O	40	compound	O
agreements	NNS	O	37	nmod	O
not	RB	O	46	neg	O
adversely	RB	O	46	advmod	O
impact	JJ	O	46	compound	O
missile	NN	O	46	compound	O

This	DT	O	0	ROOT	O
report	NN	O	2	det	O
also	RB	O	4	nsubj	O
explains	VBZ	O	4	advmod	O
in	IN	O	7	case	O
further	JJ	O	7	amod	O
detail	NN	O	4	nmod	O
the	DT	O	9	det	O
findings	NNS	O	14	nsubj	O
of	IN	O	12	case	O
the	DT	O	12	det	O
committee	NN	O	9	nmod	O
,	,	O	9	punct	O
makes	VBZ	O	4	ccomp	O
recommendations	NNS	O	14	dobj	O
,	,	O	4	punct	O
and	CC	O	4	cc	O
sets	NNS	O	31	csubjpass	O
guidelines	NNS	O	18	dobj	O
for	IN	O	22	case	O
the	DT	B-DATE	22	det	O
future	NN	I-DATE	19	nmod	O
of	IN	O	29	case	O
ballistic	JJ	O	29	amod	B-WEA
missile	NN	O	29	compound	I-WEA
defense	NN	O	29	compound	O
research.Download	NN	O	29	compound	O
PDFThis	NNP	O	29	compound	O
entry	NN	O	22	nmod	O
was	VBD	O	31	auxpass	O
posted	VBN	O	4	conj	O
in	IN	O	33	case	O
Publications	NNP	O	31	nmod	O
and	CC	O	31	cc	O
tagged	VBD	O	31	conj	O
Boost	NNP	O	37	compound	O
Phase	NNP	O	35	dobj	O
by	IN	O	39	case	O
editor	NN	B-TITLE	35	nmod	O
.	.	O	4	punct	O

6	CD	B-NUMBER	0	ROOT	O
,	,	O	82	dep	O
2013	CD	B-DATE	1	punct	O
-	:	O	6	nummod	O
Amid	CC	O	6	punct	O
reports	NNS	O	6	case	O
that	IN	O	1	appos	O
China	NNP	B-COUNTRY	10	mark	O
is	VBZ	O	10	nsubj	O
gearing	VBG	O	10	aux	O
up	RP	O	6	ccomp	O
to	TO	O	10	compound:prt	O
conduct	VB	O	13	mark	O
one	CD	B-NUMBER	10	xcomp	O
more	JJR	O	18	nummod	O
anti-satellite	JJ	O	18	amod	O
weapons	NNS	O	18	amod	O
test	VBP	O	18	compound	O
-LRB-	NN	O	13	dobj	O
ASAT	NNP	O	20	punct	O
-RRB-	NNP	O	18	appos	O
putting	VBG	O	20	punct	O
US	NNP	B-COUNTRY	18	acl	O
Global	NNP	O	26	compound	O
Positioning	NNP	O	26	amod	O
System	NNP	O	26	compound	O
-LRB-	NNP	O	22	dobj	O
GPS	NNP	O	28	punct	O
-RRB-	NNP	O	26	appos	O
at	IN	O	28	punct	O
risk	NN	O	31	case	O
,	,	O	22	nmod	B-ORG
Chinese	JJ	B-NATIONALITY	1	punct	I-ORG
state	NN	O	35	amod	I-ORG
media	NNS	O	35	compound	O
today	NN	B-DATE	37	nsubj	O
asserted	VBD	O	37	nmod:tmod	O
that	IN	O	1	acl:relcl	O
Beijing	NNP	B-CITY	40	mark	O
had	VBD	O	40	nsubj	O
the	DT	O	37	ccomp	O
right	NN	O	42	det	O
to	TO	O	60	nsubj	O
carry	VB	O	44	mark	O
out	RP	O	42	acl	O
the	DT	O	44	compound:prt	O
test	NN	O	47	det	O
as	IN	O	44	dobj	O
it	PRP	O	54	mark	O
is	VBZ	O	54	nsubj	O
a	DT	O	54	cop	O
``	``	O	54	det	O
trump	JJ	O	54	punct	O
card	NN	O	54	amod	O
''	''	O	44	advcl	O
against	IN	O	54	punct	O
Washington.China	NNP	O	57	case	O
may	MD	O	54	nmod	O
be	VB	O	60	aux	O
gearing	VBG	O	60	aux	O
up	RP	O	40	ccomp	O
to	TO	O	60	compound:prt	O
perform	VB	O	63	mark	O
a	DT	O	60	xcomp	O
controversial	JJ	O	67	det	B-PROG
ASAT	NNP	O	67	amod	I-PROG
test	NN	O	67	compound	O
this	DT	B-DATE	63	dobj	O
month	NN	I-DATE	69	det	O
,	,	O	63	nmod:tmod	O
perhaps	RB	O	63	punct	O
in	IN	O	75	advmod	O
the	DT	B-DATE	75	case	O
next	JJ	I-DATE	75	det	O
week	NN	I-DATE	75	amod	O
or	CC	O	63	nmod	O
two	CD	B-NUMBER	75	cc	O
,	,	O	75	conj	B-DOC
US	PRP	B-COUNTRY	1	punct	I-DOC
media	NNS	O	81	compound	I-DOC
report	NN	O	81	compound	O
said	VBD	O	82	nsubj	O

``	``	O	0	ROOT	O
In	IN	O	3	case	O
2007	CD	B-DATE	8	nmod	O
and	CC	O	3	cc	O
2010	CD	B-DATE	3	conj	O
,	,	O	8	punct	O
China	NNP	B-COUNTRY	8	nsubj	O
conducted	VBD	O	1	root	O
anti-satellite	JJ	O	14	amod	O
-LRB-	NNP	O	11	punct	O
ASAT	NNP	O	9	dep	O
-RRB-	NNP	O	11	punct	O
weapons	NNS	O	14	compound	O
tests	NNS	O	8	dobj	B-PROG
,	,	O	14	punct	I-PROG
both	DT	O	18	cc:preconj	I-PROG
on	IN	O	18	case	O
January	NNP	B-DATE	14	nmod	O
11	CD	I-DATE	18	nummod	O
.	.	O	8	punct	O

Rumours	NNP	O	0	ROOT	O
circulating	VBG	O	2	nsubj	O
for	IN	O	8	csubj	O
the	DT	B-DURATION	7	case	O
past	JJ	I-DURATION	7	det	O
few	JJ	I-DURATION	7	amod	O
months	NNS	I-DURATION	7	amod	O
suggest	VBP	O	2	nmod	O
that	IN	O	43	ccomp	O
some	DT	O	18	mark	O
within	IN	O	18	nsubj	O
the	DT	O	14	case	O
US	NNP	B-COUNTRY	14	det	B-ORG
defence	NN	O	14	compound	I-ORG
and	CC	O	10	nmod	I-ORG
intelligence	NN	O	14	cc	I-ORG
community	NN	O	17	compound	I-ORG
believe	VBP	O	14	conj	O
China	NNP	B-COUNTRY	8	ccomp	O
is	VBZ	O	21	nsubj	O
preparing	VBG	O	21	aux	O
to	TO	O	18	ccomp	O
conduct	VB	O	23	mark	O
another	DT	O	21	xcomp	O
ASAT	NNP	O	26	det	B-PROG
test	NN	O	26	compound	I-PROG
,	,	O	23	dobj	O
''	''	O	43	punct	O
Union	NNP	O	43	punct	B-ORG
of	IN	O	43	nsubj	I-ORG
Concerned	NNP	O	32	case	I-ORG
Scientists	NNP	O	32	compound	I-ORG
,	,	O	29	nmod	O
a	DT	O	29	punct	O
Cambridge-based	JJ	B-MISC	36	det	O
body	NN	O	36	amod	O
of	IN	O	29	appos	O
scientists	NNS	O	42	case	O
reported.China	VBP	O	39	compound	O
's	POS	O	42	nmod:poss	O
previous	JJ	O	39	case	O
tests	NNS	O	42	amod	O
caused	VBD	O	36	nmod	O
concern	NN	O	43	dobj	O
in	IN	O	46	case	O
India	NNP	B-COUNTRY	44	nmod	O
too	RB	O	49	advmod	O
with	IN	O	49	case	O
assertions	NNS	O	43	nmod	O
by	IN	O	54	case	O
the	DT	O	54	det	O
Indian	JJ	B-NATIONALITY	54	amod	O
defence	NN	O	54	compound	O
officials	NNS	O	49	nmod	O
that	WDT	O	60	mark	O
New	NNP	B-CITY	57	compound	O
Delhi	NNP	I-CITY	60	nsubj	O
also	RB	O	60	advmod	O
should	MD	O	60	aux	O
acquire	VB	O	54	ccomp	O
such	PDT	O	63	det:predet	O
a	DT	O	63	det	O
capability	NN	O	60	dobj	O
.	.	O	43	punct	O

``	``	O	0	ROOT	O
Just	RB	O	11	punct	O
before	RB	O	4	advmod	O
Christmas	NNP	B-DATE	4	case	O
,	,	O	11	nmod	O
a	DT	O	11	punct	O
high-ranking	JJ	O	10	det	O
US	NNP	B-COUNTRY	10	amod	O
defence	NN	O	10	compound	O
official	NN	O	10	compound	O
told	VBD	O	11	nsubj	O
us	PRP	O	40	dep	O
that	IN	O	11	dobj	O
the	DT	O	19	mark	O
Obama	NNP	B-PERSON	16	det	B-ORG
administration	NN	O	16	compound	I-ORG
was	VBD	O	19	nsubj	B-REL
very	RB	O	19	cop	I-REL
concerned	JJ	O	19	advmod	I-REL
about	IN	O	11	ccomp	I-REL
an	DT	O	25	case	O
imminent	JJ	O	25	det	O
Chinese	JJ	B-NATIONALITY	25	amod	O
ASAT	NNP	O	25	amod	B-PROG
test	NN	O	25	compound	I-PROG
,	,	O	19	nmod	O
''	''	O	11	punct	O
Gregory	NNP	B-PERSON	11	punct	B-P1
Kulacki	NNP	I-PERSON	29	compound	I-P1
,	,	O	40	nsubj	O
China	NNP	B-COUNTRY	29	punct	B-P2
project	NN	B-TITLE	33	compound	I-P2
manager	NN	I-TITLE	33	compound	I-P2
of	IN	O	29	conj	O
the	DT	O	36	case	O
group	NN	O	36	det	O
and	CC	O	33	nmod	O
senior	JJ	O	29	cc	B-P2
analyst	NN	B-TITLE	39	amod	I-P2
reported	VBD	O	29	conj	O
two	CD	B-DATE	42	nummod	O
days	NNS	I-DATE	43	nmod:npmod	O
ago	RB	I-DATE	40	advmod	O
.	.	O	40	punct	O

``	``	O	0	ROOT	O
Given	VBN	O	14	punct	O
these	DT	O	6	case	O
high-level	JJ	O	6	det	O
administration	NN	O	6	amod	O
concerns	NNS	O	6	compound	O
,	,	O	14	nmod	O
and	CC	O	6	punct	O
past	IN	B-DATE	6	cc	O
Chinese	JJ	B-NATIONALITY	11	amod	O
practice	NN	O	11	amod	O
,	,	O	6	conj	O
there	EX	O	14	punct	O
seems	VBZ	O	14	expl	O
to	TO	O	19	mark	O
be	VB	O	19	cop	O
a	DT	O	19	det	O
strong	JJ	O	19	amod	O
possibility	NN	O	14	xcomp	O
China	NNP	B-COUNTRY	22	nsubj	O
will	MD	O	22	aux	O
conduct	VB	O	19	ccomp	O
an	DT	O	25	det	O
ASAT	NNP	O	25	compound	B-PROG
test	NN	O	22	dobj	I-PROG
within	IN	O	30	case	O
the	DT	B-DURATION	30	det	O
next	JJ	I-DURATION	30	amod	O
few	JJ	I-DURATION	30	amod	O
weeks	NNS	I-DURATION	22	nmod	O
.	.	O	14	punct	O

What	WP	O	0	ROOT	O
kind	NN	O	2	det	O
of	IN	O	16	dep	O
test	NN	O	4	case	O
and	CC	O	2	nmod	O
what	WP	O	2	cc	O
the	DT	O	12	dobj	O
target	NN	O	8	det	O
might	MD	O	12	nsubj	O
be	VB	O	12	aux	O
is	VBZ	O	12	cop	O
unclear	JJ	O	12	cop	O
,	,	O	2	conj	O
''	''	O	16	punct	O
Kulacki	NNP	B-PERSON	16	punct	O
wrote	VBD	O	16	nsubj	O
in	IN	O	19	case	O
his	PRP$	O	19	nmod:poss	O
report.Reacting	NN	O	16	nmod	O
to	TO	O	22	case	O
the	DT	O	22	det	O
report	NN	O	19	nmod	O
,	,	O	19	punct	O
an	DT	O	25	det	O
editorial	NN	O	32	nsubj	O
in	IN	O	31	case	O
China	NNP	B-COUNTRY	31	nmod:poss	O
's	POS	O	27	case	O
state-run	NN	O	31	amod	O
Global	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	31	compound	O
Times	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	25	nmod	O
said	VBD	O	19	acl:relcl	O
today	NN	B-DATE	32	nmod:tmod	O
that	IN	O	35	nsubj	O
concerns	VBZ	O	50	csubjpass	O
that	IN	O	40	mark	O
the	DT	O	38	det	O
test	NN	O	40	nsubj	O
will	MD	O	40	aux	O
put	VB	O	35	ccomp	B-WEA
the	DT	O	44	det	I-WEA
US	NNP	B-COUNTRY	44	compound	I-WEA
strategic	JJ	O	44	amod	O
satellites	NNS	O	40	dobj	O
at	IN	O	46	case	O
risk	NN	O	40	nmod	O
is	VBZ	O	50	auxpass	O
``	``	O	50	punct	O
over	IN	O	50	advmod	O
blown	NN	O	32	ccomp	O

``	``	O	0	ROOT	O
China	NNP	B-COUNTRY	4	nsubj	O
reportedly	RB	O	4	advmod	O
conducted	VBD	O	1	root	O
an	DT	O	7	det	O
anti-satellite	JJ	O	7	amod	O
test	NN	O	4	dobj	O
in	IN	O	10	case	O
early	JJ	B-DATE	10	amod	O
2007	CD	I-DATE	4	nmod	O
,	,	O	10	punct	O
which	WDT	O	13	nsubj	O
caused	VBD	O	10	acl:relcl	O
a	DT	O	16	det	O
great	JJ	O	16	amod	O
uproar	NN	O	13	dobj	O

Some	DT	O	0	ROOT	O
analysts	NNS	O	2	det	O
said	VBD	O	3	nsubj	O
that	IN	O	28	ccomp	O
even	RB	O	18	mark	O
if	IN	O	11	advmod	O
China	NNP	B-COUNTRY	11	mark	O
really	RB	O	11	nsubj	O
once	RB	B-DATE	10	advmod	O
again	RB	O	10	advmod	O
launches	VBZ	O	11	advmod	O
a	DT	O	18	advcl	O
test	NN	O	13	det	O
,	,	O	11	dobj	O
it	PRP	O	18	punct	O
will	MD	O	18	nsubj	O
not	RB	O	18	aux	O
strike	VB	O	18	neg	O
down	RP	O	3	ccomp	O
satellites	NNS	O	18	compound:prt	O
,	,	O	18	dobj	O
but	CC	O	18	punct	O
invalidate	VB	O	18	cc	O
them	PRP	O	18	conj	O
,	,	O	23	dobj	O
''	''	O	28	punct	O
it	PRP	O	28	punct	O
said	VBD	O	28	nsubj	O
without	IN	O	30	mark	O
stating	VBG	O	28	advcl	O
whether	IN	O	36	mark	O
the	DT	O	33	det	O
test	NN	O	36	nsubjpass	O
would	MD	O	36	aux	O
be	VB	O	36	auxpass	O
conducted	VBN	O	30	ccomp	O
.	.	O	28	punct	O

``	``	O	0	ROOT	O
Whether	PRP$	O	11	punct	O
China	NNP	B-COUNTRY	5	mark	O
will	MD	O	5	nsubj	O
launch	VB	O	5	aux	O
new	JJ	O	11	csubj	O
anti-satellite	JJ	O	8	amod	O
test	NN	O	8	amod	O
is	VBZ	O	5	dobj	O
still	RB	O	11	cop	O
unknown	JJ	O	11	advmod	O

However	RB	O	0	ROOT	O
China	NNP	B-COUNTRY	4	advmod	O
should	MD	O	4	nsubj	O
continue	VB	O	4	aux	O
substantive	JJ	O	6	amod	O
research	NN	O	4	dobj	O
on	IN	O	9	case	O
striking	VBG	O	9	amod	O
satellites	NNS	O	6	nmod	O
.	.	O	4	punct	O

In	IN	O	0	ROOT	O
the	DT	O	4	case	O
foreseeable	JJ	O	4	det	O
future	NN	B-DATE	4	amod	O
,	,	O	15	nmod	O
gap	NN	O	15	punct	O
between	IN	O	15	nsubjpass	O
China	NNP	B-COUNTRY	8	case	O
and	CC	O	6	nmod	O
the	DT	O	8	cc	O
US	NNP	B-COUNTRY	11	det	O
can	MD	O	8	conj	O
not	RB	O	15	aux	O
be	VB	O	15	neg	O
eliminated	VBN	O	15	auxpass	O
by	IN	O	27	ccomp	O
China	NNP	B-COUNTRY	19	case	O
's	POS	O	19	nmod:poss	O
development	NN	O	17	case	O
of	IN	O	15	nmod	O
space	NN	O	22	case	B-WEA
weapons	NNS	O	22	compound	I-WEA
,	,	O	19	nmod	O
''	''	O	27	punct	O
the	DT	O	27	punct	O
editorial	NN	O	26	det	O
said	VBD	O	27	nsubj	O
.	.	O	27	punct	O

``	``	O	0	ROOT	O
The	DT	O	6	punct	O
US	NNP	B-COUNTRY	4	det	O
advantage	NN	O	4	compound	O
is	VBZ	O	6	nsubj	O
overwhelming	JJ	O	6	cop	O
.	.	O	6	punct	O

Before	IN	O	0	ROOT	O
strategic	JJ	O	3	case	O
uncertainties	NNS	O	3	amod	O
between	IN	O	10	nmod	O
China	NNP	B-COUNTRY	5	case	O
and	CC	O	3	nmod	O
the	DT	O	5	cc	O
US	NNP	B-COUNTRY	8	det	O
can	MD	O	5	conj	O
disappear	VB	O	10	aux	O
,	,	O	25	ccomp	O
China	NNP	B-COUNTRY	10	punct	O
urgently	RB	O	14	nsubj	O
needs	VBZ	O	14	advmod	O
to	TO	O	10	ccomp	O
have	VB	O	16	mark	O
an	DT	O	14	xcomp	O
outer	JJ	O	21	det	O
space	NN	O	21	amod	O
trump	NN	O	21	compound	O
card	NN	O	21	compound	O
''	''	O	16	dobj	O
,	,	O	10	punct	O
it	PRP	O	25	punct	O
said	VBD	O	25	nsubj	O
.	.	O	25	punct	O

``	``	O	0	ROOT	O
China	NNP	B-COUNTRY	5	nmod:poss	O
's	POS	O	2	case	O
public	JJ	O	5	amod	B-DOC
policy	NN	O	8	nsubj	I-DOC
is	VBZ	O	8	cop	I-DOC
peaceful	JJ	O	8	amod	O
use	NN	O	1	root	O
of	IN	O	10	case	O
space	NN	O	8	nmod	O
,	,	O	8	punct	O
which	WDT	O	18	nsubj	O
is	VBZ	O	18	cop	O
also	RB	O	18	advmod	O
China	NNP	B-COUNTRY	18	nmod:poss	O
's	POS	O	15	case	O
real	JJ	O	18	amod	O
desire	NN	O	8	acl:relcl	O
.	.	O	8	punct	O

China	NNP	B-COUNTRY	0	ROOT	O
has	VBZ	O	2	nsubj	O
no	DT	O	4	neg	O
interest	NN	O	2	dobj	O
in	IN	O	6	mark	O
launching	VBG	O	4	acl	O
a	DT	O	10	det	O
large-scale	JJ	O	10	amod	O
space	NN	O	10	compound	O
race	NN	O	6	dobj	O
with	IN	O	13	case	O
the	DT	O	13	det	O

China	NNP	B-COUNTRY	0	ROOT	O
and	CC	O	5	nsubj	O
Russia	NNP	B-COUNTRY	1	cc	O
jointly	RB	O	1	conj	O
initiated	VBD	O	5	advmod	O
a	DT	O	30	ccomp	O
programme	NN	O	7	det	O
to	TO	O	5	dobj	O
avoid	VB	O	9	mark	O
an	DT	O	7	acl	O
arms	NNS	O	12	det	O
race	NN	O	12	compound	O
in	IN	O	9	dobj	B-REL
outer	JJ	O	15	case	O
space	NN	O	15	amod	O
in	IN	O	12	nmod	O
2008	CD	B-DATE	17	case	O
,	,	O	9	nmod	O
but	CC	O	5	punct	O
this	DT	O	5	cc	O
proposal	NN	O	21	det	O
was	VBD	O	23	nsubjpass	O
refused	VBN	O	23	auxpass	O
by	IN	O	5	conj	O
the	DT	O	26	case	O
US	NNP	B-COUNTRY	26	det	O
''	''	O	23	nmod	O
,	,	O	26	punct	O
it	PRP	O	30	punct	O
said	VBD	O	30	nsubj	O
.	.	O	30	punct	O

``	``	O	0	ROOT	O
Against	IN	O	4	case	O
this	DT	O	4	det	O
background	NN	O	8	nmod	O
,	,	O	8	punct	O
it	PRP	O	8	nsubj	O
is	VBZ	O	8	cop	O
necessary	JJ	O	1	root	O
for	IN	O	12	mark	O
China	NNP	B-COUNTRY	12	nsubj	O
to	TO	O	12	mark	O
have	VB	O	8	advcl	O
the	DT	O	14	det	O
ability	NN	O	12	dobj	O
to	TO	O	16	mark	O
strike	VB	O	14	acl	O
US	NNP	B-COUNTRY	18	compound	O
satellites	NNS	O	16	dobj	O
.	.	O	8	punct	O

This	DT	O	0	ROOT	O
deterrent	NN	O	2	det	O
can	MD	O	4	nsubj	O
provide	VB	O	4	aux	O
strategic	JJ	O	20	ccomp	O
protection	NN	O	6	amod	O
to	TO	O	4	dobj	O
Chinese	NNP	B-NATIONALITY	9	case	O
satellites	NNS	O	9	amod	O
and	CC	O	6	nmod	O
the	DT	O	9	cc	O
whole	JJ	O	13	det	O
country	NN	O	13	amod	O
's	POS	O	16	nmod:poss	O
national	JJ	O	13	case	O
security	NN	O	16	amod	O
''	''	O	9	conj	O
,	,	O	4	punct	O
it	PRP	O	20	punct	O
said	VBD	O	20	nsubj	O
.	.	O	20	punct	O

``	``	O	0	ROOT	O
The	DT	O	3	det	O
US	NNP	B-COUNTRY	5	nsubj	O
will	MD	O	5	aux	O
continue	VB	O	1	root	O
to	TO	O	7	mark	O
harass	VB	O	5	xcomp	O
and	CC	O	7	cc	O
even	RB	O	10	advmod	O
obstruct	VBP	O	7	conj	O
China	NNP	B-COUNTRY	13	nmod:poss	O
's	POS	O	11	case	O
developing	NN	O	7	dobj	O
of	IN	O	17	case	O
its	PRP$	O	17	nmod:poss	O
space	NN	O	17	compound	O
capabilities	NNS	O	13	nmod	O
.	.	O	5	punct	O

China	NNP	B-COUNTRY	0	ROOT	O
should	MD	O	3	nsubj	O
make	VB	O	3	aux	O
tactical	JJ	O	5	amod	O
adjustments	NNS	O	3	dobj	O
to	TO	O	7	mark	O
reduce	VB	O	5	acl	O
trouble	NN	O	7	dobj	O
.	.	O	3	punct	O

It	PRP	O	0	ROOT	O
is	VBZ	O	3	nsubj	O
key	JJ	O	3	cop	O
for	IN	O	7	mark	O
China	NNP	B-COUNTRY	7	nsubj	O
to	TO	O	7	mark	O
have	VB	O	3	advcl	O
the	DT	O	9	det	O
ability	NN	O	7	dobj	O
of	IN	O	12	case	O
strategic	JJ	O	12	amod	O
retaliation	NN	O	9	nmod	O
.	.	O	3	punct	O

It	PRP	O	0	ROOT	O
is	VBZ	O	4	nsubj	O
a	DT	O	4	cop	O
safeguard	NN	O	4	det	O
for	IN	O	28	ccomp	O
China	NNP	B-COUNTRY	8	mark	O
to	TO	O	8	nsubj	O
deter	VB	O	8	mark	O
the	DT	O	4	advcl	O
US	NNP	B-COUNTRY	10	det	O
from	IN	O	8	dobj	O
taking	VBG	O	12	mark	O
risky	JJ	O	8	advcl	O
action	NN	O	14	amod	O
against	IN	O	12	dobj	O
China	NNP	B-COUNTRY	16	case	O
in	IN	O	12	nmod	O
this	DT	O	19	case	O
period	NN	O	19	det	O
of	IN	O	12	nmod	O
great	JJ	O	22	case	O
transition	NN	O	22	amod	O
,	,	O	19	nmod	O
''	''	O	28	punct	O
it	PRP	O	28	punct	O
said.The	VBD	O	28	dep	O
planned	VBN	O	28	amod	O
test	NN	O	28	amod	O
by	IN	O	30	case	O
China	NNP	B-COUNTRY	28	nmod	O
comes	VBZ	O	28	dep	O
in	IN	O	34	case	O
the	DT	O	34	det	O
backdrop	NN	O	31	nmod	O
of	IN	O	37	case	O
the	DT	O	37	det	O
launch	NN	O	34	nmod	O
of	IN	O	42	case	O
China	NNP	B-COUNTRY	42	nmod:poss	O
's	POS	O	39	case	O
own	JJ	O	42	amod	O
GPS	NNP	O	37	nmod	O
called	VBD	O	42	acl	B-REL
BeiDou	NNP	O	47	compound	O
Navigation	NNP	O	47	compound	O
Satellite	NNP	O	47	compound	O
System	NNP	O	43	xcomp	O
-LRB-	NNP	O	49	punct	O
BDS	NNP	O	47	appos	O
-RRB-	NNP	O	49	punct	B-REL
currently	RB	B-DATE	53	advmod	I-REL
being	VBG	O	53	auxpass	I-REL
used	VBN	O	31	acl	I-REL
by	IN	O	56	case	B-ORG
Chinese	JJ	B-NATIONALITY	56	amod	I-ORG
military	JJ	O	53	nmod	O
and	CC	O	56	cc	O
a	DT	O	59	det	O
number	NN	O	56	conj	O
of	IN	O	63	case	O
official	JJ	O	63	amod	O
bodies.China	NN	O	63	compound	O
plans	NNS	O	59	nmod	O
to	TO	O	65	mark	O
launch	VB	O	63	acl	O
20	CD	B-NUMBER	68	nummod	O
more	JJR	O	68	amod	O
satellites	NNS	O	65	dobj	O
to	TO	O	70	mark	O
improve	VB	O	65	advcl	O
its	PRP$	O	74	nmod:poss	O
functioning.Some	JJ	O	74	compound	O
US	NNP	B-COUNTRY	74	compound	O
officials	NNS	O	75	nsubj	O
suspect	VBP	O	70	ccomp	O
China	NNP	B-COUNTRY	78	nsubj	O
may	MD	O	78	aux	O
want	VB	O	75	ccomp	O
to	TO	O	80	mark	O
go	VB	O	78	xcomp	O
higher	JJR	O	80	advmod	O
than	IN	O	84	mark	O
it	PRP	O	84	nsubj	O
did	VBD	O	81	advcl	O
in	IN	O	87	case	O
either	DT	O	87	cc:preconj	O
2007	CD	B-DATE	80	nmod	O
or	CC	O	87	cc	O
2010	CD	B-DATE	87	conj	O
,	,	O	31	punct	O
targeting	VBG	O	112	csubj	O
an	DT	O	93	det	O
object	NN	O	91	dobj	O
12,000	CD	B-NUMBER	95	nummod	O
miles	NNS	O	93	nmod	O
or	CC	O	95	cc	O
so	RB	O	95	conj	O
above	IN	O	95	case	O
Earth	NNP	B-LOCATION	102	nmod:poss	O
's	POS	O	99	case	O
surface.This	NN	O	102	compound	O
ability	NN	O	95	dep	O
to	TO	O	104	mark	O
reach	VB	O	102	acl	O
Medium-Earth	JJ	O	106	compound	O
Orbit	NNP	O	104	dobj	O
-LRB-	NNP	O	108	punct	O
MEO	NNP	O	106	appos	O
-RRB-	NNP	O	108	punct	O
could	MD	O	112	aux	B-REL
theoretically	RB	O	112	advmod	I-REL
put	VB	O	31	parataxis	I-REL
the	DT	O	114	det	I-REL
constellation	NN	O	112	dobj	I-REL
of	IN	O	121	case	I-REL
US	NNP	B-COUNTRY	121	compound	B-WEA
Global	NNP	O	121	compound	I-WEA
Positioning	NNP	O	121	compound	I-WEA
System	NNP	O	121	compound	I-WEA
navigational	JJ	O	121	amod	I-WEA
satellites	NNS	O	114	nmod	I-WEA
at	IN	O	123	case	O
risk	NN	O	112	nmod	O
,	,	O	112	punct	O
a	DT	O	126	det	O
report	NN	O	129	nsubj	O
in	IN	O	128	case	O
Space.Com	NNP	B-URL	126	nmod	O
said	VBD	O	112	parataxis	O
.	.	O	28	punct	O

``	``	O	0	ROOT	O
But	CC	O	4	punct	O
there	EX	O	4	cc	O
are	VBP	O	4	expl	O
good	JJ	O	31	dep	O
reasons	NNS	O	6	amod	O
for	IN	O	4	nsubj	O
China	NNP	B-COUNTRY	8	case	O
not	RB	O	6	nmod	O
to	TO	O	11	neg	O
destroy	VB	O	11	mark	O
a	DT	O	6	acl	O
satellite	NN	O	13	det	O
at	IN	O	11	dobj	O
this	DT	O	16	case	O
orbit	NN	O	16	det	O
,	,	O	11	nmod	O
including	VBG	O	6	punct	O
that	IN	O	6	acl	O
China	NNP	B-COUNTRY	21	mark	O
plans	VBZ	O	21	nsubj	O
to	TO	O	18	ccomp	O
use	VB	O	23	mark	O
this	DT	O	21	xcomp	O
part	NN	O	25	det	O
of	IN	O	23	dobj	O
space	NN	O	27	case	O
,	,	O	25	nmod	O
''	''	O	4	punct	O
Kulacki	NNP	B-PERSON	4	punct	O
wrote	VBD	O	31	nsubj	O
.	.	O	31	punct	O

``	``	O	0	ROOT	O
Creating	VBG	O	11	punct	O
debris	RB	O	3	amod	O
,	,	O	11	nsubj	O
as	IN	O	11	punct	O
it	PRP	O	8	mark	O
now	RB	B-DATE	8	nsubj	O
understands	VBZ	O	8	advmod	O
,	,	O	11	dep	O
would	MD	O	11	punct	O
threaten	VB	O	11	aux	O
its	PRP$	O	14	nmod:poss	O
own	JJ	O	14	amod	O
satellites	NNS	O	11	dobj	O
.	.	O	11	punct	O

Over	IN	O	0	ROOT	O
the	DT	B-DATE	5	case	O
next	JJ	I-DATE	5	det	O
several	JJ	I-DATE	5	amod	O
years	NNS	I-DATE	5	amod	O
,	,	O	8	nmod	O
China	NNP	B-COUNTRY	8	punct	O
plans	VBZ	O	8	nsubj	O
to	TO	O	23	ccomp	O
place	VB	O	10	mark	O
more	JJR	O	8	xcomp	O
than	IN	O	13	advmod	O
20	CD	B-NUMBER	11	mwe	O
new	JJ	O	16	nummod	O
navigational	JJ	O	16	amod	O
satellites	NNS	O	16	amod	O
in	IN	O	10	dobj	B-REL
MEO	NNP	O	18	case	O
,	,	O	10	nmod	O
''	''	O	23	punct	O
he	PRP	O	23	punct	O
wrote.Kulacki	VBZ	O	23	nsubj	O
urged	VBD	O	23	nsubj	B-REL
the	DT	O	56	ccomp	O
Obama	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	26	det	B-ORG
Administration	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	26	compound	I-ORG
to	TO	O	23	dobj	O
attempt	VB	O	28	mark	B-REL
to	TO	O	23	xcomp	I-REL
dissuade	VB	O	30	mark	I-REL
China	NNP	B-COUNTRY	28	xcomp	I-REL
from	IN	O	30	dobj	I-REL
conducting	VBG	O	33	mark	I-REL
any	DT	O	30	advcl	O
more	RBR	O	38	det	O
destructive	JJ	O	36	advmod	O
ASAT	NNP	O	38	amod	O
tests.Both	CC	O	38	compound	O
the	DT	O	33	dobj	O
United	NNP	B-COUNTRY	41	det	O
States	NNPS	I-COUNTRY	41	compound	O
and	CC	O	46	nsubj	O
the	DT	O	41	cc	O
Soviet	NNP	B-LOCATION	45	det	O
Union	NNP	B-CITY	45	compound	O
abandoned	VBD	O	41	conj	O
such	JJ	O	38	acl:relcl	O
tests	NNS	O	48	amod	O
as	IN	O	46	dobj	O
their	PRP$	O	53	mark	B-PROG
space	NN	O	52	nmod:poss	I-PROG
programmes	NNS	O	52	compound	O
matured	VBD	O	53	nsubj	O
,	,	O	48	acl:relcl	O
he	PRP	O	56	punct	O
notes	VBZ	O	56	nsubj	O

``	``	O	0	ROOT	O
Hopefully	RB	O	15	punct	O
,	,	O	7	advmod	O
China	NNP	B-COUNTRY	7	punct	O
will	MD	O	7	nsubj	O
eventually	RB	O	7	aux	O
come	VB	O	7	advmod	O
to	TO	O	15	ccomp	O
a	DT	O	11	case	O
similar	JJ	O	11	det	O
conclusion	NN	O	11	amod	O
,	,	O	7	nmod	O
''	''	O	15	punct	O
Kulacki	NNP	B-PERSON	15	punct	O
wrote	VBD	O	15	nsubj	O
adding	VBG	O	15	xcomp	O
that	IN	O	34	mark	O
``	``	O	34	punct	O
beginning	VBG	O	23	case	O
a	DT	O	23	det	O
meaningful	JJ	O	23	amod	O
bilateral	JJ	O	23	amod	O
dialogue	NN	O	34	nmod	O
on	IN	O	26	case	O
space	NN	O	26	compound	O
security	NN	O	23	nmod	O
between	IN	O	30	case	O
the	DT	O	30	det	O
United	NNP	B-COUNTRY	30	compound	O
States	NNPS	I-COUNTRY	26	nmod	O
and	CC	O	30	cc	O
China	NNP	B-COUNTRY	30	conj	O
could	MD	O	34	aux	O
hasten	VB	O	16	ccomp	O
the	DT	B-DATE	36	det	O
day	NN	I-DATE	34	nmod:tmod	O
.	.	O	15	punct	O

``	``	O	0	ROOT	O
This	DT	O	3	det	O
entry	NN	O	5	nsubjpass	O
was	VBD	O	5	auxpass	O
posted	VBN	O	1	root	O
in	IN	O	7	case	O
News	NNP	B-MISC	5	nmod	O
and	CC	O	5	cc	O
tagged	VBD	O	5	conj	O
China	NNP	B-COUNTRY	9	dobj	O
,	,	O	10	punct	O
India	NNP	B-COUNTRY	10	conj	O
,	,	O	10	punct	O
Russia	NNP	B-COUNTRY	10	conj	O
,	,	O	10	punct	O
anti-satellite	JJ	O	10	amod	O
,	,	O	10	punct	O
Testing	VBG	O	20	dep	O
-	:	O	20	punct	O
Foreign	NN	O	10	amod	O
by	IN	O	22	case	O
editor	NN	B-TITLE	20	nmod	O
.	.	O	5	punct	O

The	DT	O	0	ROOT	O
three	CD	B-NUMBER	4	det	O
Apollo	NNP	B-MISC	4	nummod	O
commanders	NNS	O	4	compound	O
,	,	O	25	nsubj	O
who	WP	O	4	punct	O
earlier	RBR	O	8	nsubj	O
urged	VBD	O	8	advmod	O
Congress	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	4	acl:relcl	O
to	TO	O	8	dobj	B-ORG
resist	VB	O	11	mark	O
White	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	8	xcomp	O
House	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	13	compound	REL>
plans	VBZ	O	14	nsubj	B-ORG
to	TO	O	11	ccomp	I-ORG
hand	NN	O	16	mark	O
off	RP	O	14	xcomp	O
human	JJ	O	16	compound:prt	O
access	NN	O	19	amod	O
to	TO	O	16	dobj	O
the	DT	O	23	case	O
private	JJ	O	23	det	O
sector	NN	O	23	amod	O
,	,	O	19	nmod	O
agreed	VBD	O	4	punct	O
that	IN	O	34	mark	O
a	DT	O	30	det	O
Space	NNP	B-MISC	30	compound	O
Act	NNP	I-MISC	30	compound	O
procurement	NN	O	34	nsubj	O
``	``	O	34	punct	O
would	MD	O	34	aux	O
be	VB	O	34	cop	O
unlikely	JJ	O	25	ccomp	O
to	TO	O	36	mark	O
provide	VB	O	34	xcomp	O
the	DT	O	38	det	O
documentation	NN	O	36	dobj	O
that	IN	O	42	dobj	O
we	PRP	O	42	nsubj	O
normally	RB	O	42	advmod	O
depend	VBP	O	38	acl:relcl	O
upon	IN	O	42	advmod	O
to	TO	O	45	mark	O
provide	VB	O	42	xcomp	O
high	JJ	O	47	amod	O
confidence	NN	O	45	dobj	O
in	IN	O	49	mark	O
reaching	VBG	O	47	acl	O
our	PRP$	O	52	nmod:poss	O
technical	JJ	O	52	amod	O
goals	NNS	O	49	dobj	O
.	.	O	25	punct	O

''	''	O	0	ROOT	O
``	``	O	5	punct	O
We	PRP	O	5	punct	O
all	DT	O	5	nsubj	O
agree	VBP	O	3	det	O
that	IN	O	46	dep	O
our	PRP$	O	10	mark	O
country	NN	O	8	nmod:poss	O
has	VBZ	O	10	nsubj	O
painted	VBN	O	10	aux	O
itself	PRP	O	5	ccomp	O
into	IN	O	10	dobj	O
a	DT	O	14	case	O
corner	NN	O	14	det	O
and	CC	O	10	nmod	O
does	VBZ	O	10	cc	O
not	RB	O	18	aux	O
now	RB	B-DATE	18	neg	O
,	,	O	10	conj	O
nor	CC	O	5	punct	O
will	MD	O	5	cc	O
for	IN	O	5	conj	O
many	JJ	O	24	case	O
years	NNS	B-DURATION	24	amod	O
,	,	O	21	nmod	O
have	VBP	O	5	punct	O
a	DT	O	5	conj	O
U.S.	NNP	B-COUNTRY	30	det	O
government	NN	O	30	compound	O
craft	NN	O	30	compound	O
suitable	NN	O	26	dobj	O
for	IN	O	30	amod	O
carrying	VBG	O	33	mark	O
cargo	NN	O	31	advcl	O
or	CC	O	33	dobj	O
crew	NN	O	34	cc	O
to	TO	O	34	conj	O
the	DT	O	41	case	O
International	NNP	O	41	det	B-ORG
Space	NNP	O	41	compound	I-ORG
Station	NNP	O	41	compound	I-ORG
,	,	O	33	nmod	O
''	''	O	5	punct	O
the	DT	O	5	punct	O
astronauts	JJ	O	45	det	O
wrote	VBD	O	46	nsubj	O
.	.	O	46	punct	O

``	``	O	0	ROOT	O
The	DT	O	3	det	O
reputation	NN	O	24	nsubj	O
of	IN	O	6	case	O
our	PRP$	O	6	nmod:poss	O
country	NN	O	3	nmod	O
and	CC	O	3	cc	O
the	DT	O	10	det	O
potential	JJ	O	10	amod	O
liability	NN	O	3	conj	O
associated	VBN	O	10	acl	O
with	IN	O	13	mark	O
carrying	VBG	O	11	advcl	O
United	NNP	B-COUNTRY	15	compound	O
States	NNPS	I-COUNTRY	13	dobj	O
and	CC	O	15	cc	O
international	JJ	O	18	amod	O
crews	NNS	O	15	conj	O
to	TO	O	23	case	O
and	CC	O	19	cc	O
from	IN	O	19	conj	O
the	DT	O	23	det	O
ISS	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	13	nmod	O
dictates	VBZ	O	1	root	O
that	IN	O	27	mark	O
we	PRP	O	27	nsubj	O
do	VBP	O	24	ccomp	O
everything	NN	O	27	dobj	O
possible	JJ	O	28	amod	O
to	TO	O	31	mark	O
ensure	VB	O	29	xcomp	O
that	IN	O	37	mark	O
any	DT	O	36	det	O
commercial	JJ	O	36	amod	O
crew	NN	O	36	compound	O
service	NN	O	37	nsubj	O
meets	NNS	O	31	ccomp	O
standards	NNS	O	37	dobj	O
equal	JJ	O	38	amod	O
to	TO	O	41	case	O
those	DT	O	39	nmod	O
that	IN	O	45	dobj	O
we	PRP	O	45	nsubj	O
would	MD	O	45	aux	O
enforce	VB	O	38	acl:relcl	O
would	MD	O	51	aux	O
the	DT	O	48	det	O
craft	NN	O	51	nsubjpass	O
be	VB	O	51	auxpass	O
government	NN	O	51	nmod:npmod	O
owned	VBN	O	45	ccomp	O
and	CC	O	51	cc	O
operated	VBN	O	51	conj	O
.	.	O	24	punct	O

Work	NN	O	0	ROOT	O
is	VBZ	O	3	nsubj	O
underway	RB	O	3	cop	O
simultaneously	RB	O	3	advmod	O
on	IN	O	8	case	O
two	CD	B-NUMBER	8	nummod	O
strategic	JJ	O	8	amod	B-WEA
missiles	NNS	O	3	nmod	I-WEA
of	IN	O	11	case	O
different	JJ	O	11	amod	O
classes.According	VBG	O	8	nmod	O
to	TO	O	14	case	O
Sergei	NNP	B-PERSON	14	compound	B-P1
Karakaev	NNP	I-PERSON	11	nmod	I-P1
,	,	O	14	punct	O
the	DT	O	17	det	O
commander	NN	B-TITLE	14	appos	B-REL
of	IN	O	23	case	O
Russiaa	NNP	O	23	amod	O
s	FW	O	23	compound	O
Strategic	NNP	O	23	amod	O
Missile	NNP	O	23	compound	O
Forces	NNS	O	17	nmod	O
,	,	O	3	punct	O
these	DT	O	27	nsubj	O
is	VBZ	O	27	cop	O
a	DT	O	3	parataxis	O
heavy	JJ	O	27	root	O
,	,	O	28	punct	O
100-ton	JJ	O	29	root	O
,	,	O	30	punct	O
liquid-propellant	JJ	O	35	amod	O
intercontinental	JJ	O	35	amod	O
ballistic	JJ	O	35	amod	B-WEA
missile	NN	O	31	root	I-WEA
-LRB-	NNP	O	37	punct	O
ICBM	NNP	O	35	appos	O
-RRB-	VBD	O	37	punct	O
that	DT	O	41	nsubj	O
should	MD	O	41	aux	B-REL
outperform	VB	O	35	acl:relcl	I-REL
the	DT	O	43	det	O
world	NN	O	48	nmod:poss	O
's	POS	O	43	case	O
most	RBS	O	46	advmod	O
powerful	JJ	O	48	amod	O
R-36M2	JJ	O	48	compound	O
Voevoda	NNP	O	41	dobj	O
-LRB-	NNP	O	52	punct	O
NATO	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	52	compound	B-ORG
reporting	VBG	O	52	amod	O
name	NN	O	35	dep	O
:	:	O	52	punct	O
SS-18	JJ	B-MISC	55	compound	O
Satan	NNP	I-MISC	52	dep	O
-RRB-	NNP	O	52	punct	O
,	,	O	35	punct	O
and	CC	O	35	cc	O
a	DT	O	61	det	O
solid-fuel	JJ	O	61	amod	O
ICBM	NNP	O	35	conj	O
scheduled	VBD	O	61	acl	B-REL
to	TO	O	64	mark	I-REL
replace	VB	O	62	xcomp	I-REL
the	DT	O	68	det	O
fifth-generation	NN	O	68	amod	O
Yars	NNP	B-MISC	68	compound	O
systems	NNS	O	64	dobj	O
-LRB-	VBD	O	71	punct	O
the	DT	O	71	det	O
RS-24	NNP	B-MISC	68	dep	O
and	CC	O	71	cc	O
the	DT	O	74	det	O
Topol-M	NNP	B-MISC	71	conj	O
-RRB-	NNP	O	71	punct	O
.	.	O	35	punct	O

`	``	O	0	ROOT	O
Since	IN	O	26	punct	O
the	DT	O	9	mark	O
potential	NN	O	4	det	O
of	IN	O	9	nsubj	O
solid-fuel	JJ	O	7	case	O
ICBMs	NNP	O	7	amod	B-REL
could	MD	O	4	nmod	I-REL
become	VB	O	9	aux	I-REL
insufficient	JJ	O	26	advcl	I-REL
for	IN	O	9	xcomp	O
overcoming	VBG	O	12	mark	O
the	DT	O	9	advcl	B-WEA
American	JJ	B-NATIONALITY	17	det	I-WEA
missile	NN	O	17	amod	I-WEA
defense	NN	O	17	compound	I-WEA
system	NN	O	17	compound	O
going	VBG	O	12	dobj	O
forward	RB	O	17	acl	O
,	,	O	18	advmod	O
a	DT	O	26	punct	O
heavy	JJ	O	24	det	O
liquid-propellant	JJ	O	24	amod	O
ICBM	NNP	O	24	amod	O
is	VBZ	O	26	nsubjpass	O
needed	VBN	O	26	auxpass	O
to	TO	O	28	mark	O
perform	VB	O	26	xcomp	O

Such	JJ	O	0	ROOT	O
an	DT	O	3	det:predet	O
ICBM	NNP	O	3	det	O
will	MD	O	5	nsubj	B-REL
allow	VB	O	5	aux	I-REL
the	DT	O	36	ccomp	I-REL
creation	NN	O	7	det	I-REL
of	IN	O	5	dobj	I-REL
a	DT	O	15	case	O
non-nuclear	JJ	O	15	det	O
,	,	O	15	amod	O
high-precision	NN	O	10	punct	O
,	,	O	10	dep	O
strategic	JJ	O	10	punct	O
weapon	NN	O	10	dep	B-WEA
with	IN	O	7	nmod	I-WEA
a	DT	O	20	case	I-WEA
practically	RB	O	20	det	O
global	JJ	O	19	advmod	O
range	NN	O	20	amod	O
,	,	O	15	nmod	O
unless	IN	O	5	punct	O
the	DT	O	26	mark	O
United	NNP	B-COUNTRY	25	det	O
States	NNPS	I-COUNTRY	25	compound	O
abandons	VBZ	O	26	nsubj	O
its	PRP$	O	5	advcl	O
program	NN	O	28	nmod:poss	O
,	,	O	26	dobj	O
'	''	O	36	punct	O
Karakaev	NNP	O	36	punct	O
said.This	NN	O	32	compound	O
is	VBZ	O	36	nsubj	O
the	DT	O	36	cop	O
first	JJ	B-ORDINAL	36	det	O
time	NN	O	36	amod	O
Russia	NNP	B-COUNTRY	39	nsubj	O
has	VBZ	O	39	aux	O
spoken	VBN	O	36	acl:relcl	O
about	IN	O	41	mark	O
creating	VBG	O	39	advcl	O
a	DT	O	45	det	O
new	JJ	O	45	amod	O
solid-fuel	JJ	O	45	compound	O
missile	NN	O	41	dobj	O
.	.	O	36	punct	O

According	VBG	O	0	ROOT	O
to	TO	O	4	case	O
Gen.	NNP	B-TITLE	1	mwe	B-P1
Karakaev	NNP	B-PERSON	4	compound	I-P1
,	,	O	14	nmod	O
several	JJ	O	14	punct	O
launches	NNS	O	7	amod	O
of	IN	O	14	nsubj	O
a	DT	O	10	case	O
prototype	NN	O	10	det	O
of	IN	O	7	nmod	O
this	DT	O	13	case	O
missile	NN	O	13	det	O
took	VBD	O	10	nmod	O
place	NN	O	14	dobj	O
in	IN	O	17	case	O
2012	CD	B-DATE	14	nmod	O
'	''	O	17	punct	O
most	RBS	O	20	advmod	O
recently	RB	B-DATE	17	advmod	O
on	IN	O	22	case	O
Oct.	NNP	B-DATE	14	nmod	O
24	CD	I-DATE	22	nummod	O
.	.	O	14	punct	O
This	DT	O	0	ROOT	O
puts	VBZ	O	2	nsubj	O
an	DT	O	4	det	O
end	NN	O	2	dobj	O
to	TO	O	7	case	O
the	DT	O	7	det	O
debate	NN	O	2	nmod	O
on	IN	O	15	mark	O
whether	IN	O	15	mark	O
Russia	NNP	B-COUNTRY	14	nmod:poss	O
's	POS	O	10	case	O
Strategic	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	14	compound	B-ORG
Missile	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	14	compound	I-ORG
Forces	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	15	nsubj	I-ORG
need	VBP	O	7	acl	I-ORG
a	DT	O	19	det	O
heavyweight	JJ	O	19	amod	O
liquid-propellant	JJ	O	19	compound	O
missile.Russia	NN	O	15	dobj	O
undertook	VBD	O	2	dep	O
a	DT	O	23	det	O
large-scale	JJ	O	23	amod	O
modernization	NN	B-IDEOLOGY	20	dobj	O
of	IN	O	27	case	O
the	DT	O	27	det	O
Topol	NNP	B-PERSON	27	compound	O
family	NN	O	23	nmod	B-WEA
in	IN	O	30	case	I-WEA
the	DT	B-DATE	30	det	O
1990s	CD	I-DATE	23	nmod	O
and	CC	O	20	cc	O
adopted	VBD	O	20	conj	O
the	DT	O	35	det	O
Topol-M	NNP	B-MISC	35	compound	O
silos	NN	O	32	dobj	O
-LRB-	NNP	O	39	punct	O
NATO	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	39	compound	B-ORG
reporting	VBG	O	39	amod	B-REL
name	NN	O	35	appos	I-REL
:	:	O	39	punct	O
SS-27	JJ	O	39	dep	O
-RRB-	NN	O	39	punct	O
in	IN	O	44	case	O
2000	CD	B-DATE	32	nmod	O
,	,	O	20	punct	O
followed	VBN	O	20	dep	B-REL
by	IN	O	50	case	I-REL
the	DT	O	50	det	O
mobile	JJ	B-TITLE	50	amod	O
Topol-M2	JJ	O	46	nmod	O
several	JJ	B-DATE	52	amod	O
years	NNS	I-DATE	53	nmod:npmod	O
ago	RB	I-DATE	46	advmod	O

It	PRP	O	0	ROOT	O
is	VBZ	O	5	nsubj	O
the	DT	O	5	cop	O
new	JJ	O	5	det	B-WEA
Topol	NNP	B-PERSON	5	amod	I-WEA
and	CC	O	5	cc	O
the	DT	O	11	det	O
newly	RB	O	9	advmod	O
adopted	VBN	O	11	amod	O
RS-24	JJ	B-MISC	11	compound	O
Yars	NNS	I-MISC	5	conj	O
that	WDT	O	16	nsubj	B-REL
will	MD	O	16	aux	I-REL
be	VB	O	16	aux	I-REL
gradually	RB	O	16	advmod	I-REL
replacing	VBG	O	11	acl:relcl	O
the	DT	O	25	det	O
decommissioned	VBN	O	25	amod	O
,	,	O	25	punct	O
first-generation	NN	O	25	amod	O
,	,	O	25	punct	O
solid-fuel	JJ	O	25	amod	O
missiles.But	NN	O	25	compound	O
liquid-propellant	JJ	O	25	compound	B-REL
missiles	NNS	O	16	dobj	I-REL
still	RB	O	27	advmod	I-REL
form	VBP	O	5	dep	I-REL
the	DT	O	29	det	I-REL
backbone	NN	O	27	dobj	O
of	IN	O	34	case	B-ORG
the	DT	O	34	det	I-ORG
strategic	JJ	O	34	amod	I-ORG
deterrence	NN	O	34	compound	O
forces	NNS	O	29	nmod	O
:	:	O	5	punct	O
the	DT	O	37	det	O
UR-100N	NNP	O	5	dep	B-ORG
-LRB-	NNP	O	41	punct	B-REL
NATO	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	41	compound	I-REL
reporting	VBG	O	41	amod	O
name	NN	O	37	dep	O
:	:	O	41	punct	O
SS-19	JJ	O	44	compound	O
Stiletto	NNP	O	41	dep	O
-RRB-	NNP	O	41	punct	O
and	CC	O	37	cc	O
the	DT	O	50	det	B-ORG
D	NNP	O	50	compound	I-ORG
-36	NNP	B-NUMBER	50	nummod	I-ORG
M	NNP	O	37	conj	I-ORG
-LRB-	NNP	O	53	punct	O
U.S.	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	53	compound	B-ORG
Department	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	50	dep	B-REL
of	IN	I-ORGANIZATION	55	case	I-REL
Defense	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	53	nmod	O
and	CC	O	53	cc	O
NATO	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	59	compound	O
reporting	NN	O	59	amod	O
name	NN	O	53	conj	O

These	DT	O	0	ROOT	O
,	,	O	6	nsubj	O
however	RB	O	6	punct	O
,	,	O	6	advmod	O
are	VBP	O	6	punct	O
obsolete	JJ	O	6	cop	O
and	CC	O	6	cc	O
will	MD	O	9	aux	O
have	VB	O	21	csubj	O
to	TO	O	12	mark	O
be	VB	O	12	auxpass	O
retired	VBN	O	9	xcomp	O
over	IN	O	18	case	O
the	DT	O	18	det	O
next	JJ	O	18	amod	O
few	JJ	O	18	amod	O
years.New	NN	O	18	compound	O
missiles	NNS	O	12	nmod	O
have	VBP	O	21	aux	O
been	VBN	O	21	cop	O
slow	JJ	O	6	conj	O
in	IN	O	23	mark	O
arriving	VBG	O	21	advcl	O
to	TO	O	29	case	O
the	DT	O	26	det	O
Russia	NNP	B-COUNTRY	29	nmod:poss	O
's	POS	O	26	case	O
armed	JJ	O	29	amod	B-ORG
forces	NNS	O	23	nmod	I-ORG
.	.	O	6	punct	I-ORG

According	VBG	O	0	ROOT	O
to	TO	O	4	case	O
an	DT	O	1	mwe	O
estimate	NN	O	4	det	O
by	IN	O	20	nmod	O
Leonid	NNP	B-PERSON	7	case	B-P1
Kalashnikov	NNP	I-PERSON	7	compound	I-P1
,	,	O	4	nmod	O
deputy	JJ	B-TITLE	20	punct	B-REL
chairman	NN	I-TITLE	10	compound	I-REL
of	IN	O	20	nsubj	O
the	DT	O	16	case	O
State	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	16	det	B-ORG
Duma	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	16	compound	I-ORG
Defense	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	16	compound	I-ORG
Committee	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	16	compound	I-ORG
,	,	O	10	nmod	O
Russia	NNP	B-COUNTRY	10	punct	O
could	MD	O	10	appos	O
receive	VB	O	20	aux	O
100-105	JJ	B-NUMBER	23	nummod	O
new	JJ	O	23	amod	O
ICBMs	NNP	O	20	dobj	O
by	IN	O	25	case	O
2015	CD	B-DATE	20	nmod	O
.	.	O	20	punct	O

If	IN	O	0	ROOT	O
the	DT	O	4	mark	O
bet	NN	O	3	det	O
remains	VBZ	O	4	nsubj	O
on	IN	O	16	advcl	O
,	,	O	4	advmod	O
the	DT	O	16	punct	O
single-warhead	JJ	O	9	det	O
Topol-M	NNP	O	9	amod	O
and	CC	O	16	nsubj	O
the	DT	O	9	cc	O
three-warhead	JJ	O	13	det	B-REL
Yars-24	NNP	O	13	amod	I-REL
would	MD	O	9	conj	I-REL
be	VB	O	16	aux	I-REL
able	JJ	O	16	cop	I-REL
to	TO	O	18	mark	O
carry	VB	O	16	xcomp	O
a	DT	O	20	det	O
total	NN	O	18	dobj	O
of	IN	O	23	case	B-WEA
110-115	JJ	B-NUMBER	23	nummod	O
