Penn	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	0	ROOT
State	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	2	compound
awarded	VBD	O	3	nsubj
$	$	B-MONEY	3	dobj
13	CD	I-MONEY	6	compound
million	CD	I-MONEY	4	nummod
for	IN	O	13	case
vertical	JJ	O	13	amod
lift	NN	O	13	compound
technology	NN	O	13	compound
research	NN	O	13	compound
UNIVERSITY	NNP	B-CITY	13	compound
PARK	NNP	I-CITY	30	nmod
,	,	O	13	punct
Pa.	NNP	B-STATE_OR_PROVINCE	13	appos
-	:	O	13	punct
The	DT	O	23	compound
Penn	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	23	compound
State	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	23	compound
Vertical	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	23	compound
Lift	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	23	compound
Research	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	23	compound
Center	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	30	nsubjpass
of	IN	O	25	case
Excellence	NNP	O	23	nmod
-LRB-	NNP	O	27	punct
VLRCOE	NNP	O	25	appos
-RRB-	NNP	O	27	punct
was	VBD	O	30	auxpass
awarded	VBN	O	4	acl:relcl
$	$	B-MONEY	32	dep
13,786,974	CD	I-MONEY	30	dobj
in	IN	O	34	mark
funding	NN	O	30	advcl
through	IN	O	38	case
a	DT	O	38	det
cooperative	JJ	O	38	amod
agreement	NN	O	34	nmod
with	IN	O	42	case
the	DT	O	42	det
U.S.	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	42	compound
Army	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	38	nmod
,	,	O	42	punct
U.S.	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	45	compound
Navy	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	42	conj
and	CC	O	42	cc
the	DT	O	49	det
National	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	49	compound
Aeronautics	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	42	conj
and	CC	I-ORGANIZATION	49	cc
Space	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	52	compound
Administration	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	49	conj
to	TO	O	54	mark
support	VB	O	38	acl
a	DT	O	57	det
wide	JJ	O	57	amod
range	NN	O	54	dobj
of	IN	O	60	case
fundamental	JJ	O	60	amod
research	NN	O	57	nmod
related	VBN	O	60	amod
to	TO	O	65	case
vertical	JJ	O	65	amod
lift	NN	O	65	compound
technology	NN	O	61	nmod
and	CC	O	65	cc
educational	JJ	O	68	amod
activities	NNS	O	65	conj
for	IN	O	70	case
students	NNS	O	65	nmod
.	.	O	3	punct

Vertical	JJ	O	0	ROOT
lift	NN	O	3	amod
technology	NN	O	3	compound
generally	RB	O	5	nsubj
covers	VBZ	O	5	advmod
the	DT	O	7	det
class	NN	O	5	dobj
of	IN	O	9	case
aircraft	NN	O	7	nmod
that	WDT	O	12	nsubj
can	MD	O	12	aux
land	VB	O	7	acl:relcl
and	CC	O	12	cc
take	VB	O	12	conj
off	RP	O	14	compound:prt
without	IN	O	18	case
a	DT	O	18	det
runway	NN	O	14	nmod
.	.	O	5	punct

Helicopters	NNS	O	0	ROOT
and	CC	O	18	nsubj
tiltrotors	NNS	O	1	cc
,	,	O	1	conj
such	JJ	O	1	punct
as	IN	O	12	case
the	DT	O	5	mwe
U.S.	NNP	B-COUNTRY	9	det
military	JJ	O	9	compound
's	POS	O	12	nmod:poss
V-22	NNP	B-MISC	9	case
Osprey	NNP	I-MISC	12	compound
,	,	O	1	nmod
are	VBP	O	1	punct
the	DT	O	18	cop
most	RBS	O	18	det
common	JJ	O	17	advmod
examples	NNS	O	18	amod
of	IN	O	22	case
vertical	JJ	O	22	amod
lift	NN	O	22	compound
aircraft	NN	O	18	nmod
.	.	O	18	punct

The	DT	O	0	ROOT
agreement	NN	O	2	det
,	,	O	13	nsubj
administered	VBN	O	2	punct
through	IN	O	2	acl
the	DT	O	11	case
U.S.	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	11	det
Army	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	11	compound
Aviation	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	11	compound
Development	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	11	compound
Directorate	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	11	compound
,	,	O	4	nmod
provides	VBZ	O	2	punct
funding	NN	O	13	dobj
for	IN	O	18	case
the	DT	O	18	det
VLRCOE	NNP	O	18	compound
program	NN	O	14	nmod
distributed	VBN	O	18	acl
over	IN	O	23	case
a	DT	O	23	det
five-year	JJ	B-DURATION	23	amod
period	NN	O	19	nmod
.	.	O	13	punct

The	DT	O	0	ROOT
award	NN	O	2	det
will	MD	O	4	nsubj
include	VB	O	4	aux
$	$	B-MONEY	6	dep
7,992,930	CD	I-MONEY	4	dobj
in	IN	O	10	case
government	NN	O	10	compound
funds	NNS	O	10	compound
contribution	NN	O	6	nmod
and	CC	O	6	cc
$	$	B-MONEY	13	dep
5,794,044	CD	I-MONEY	6	conj
in	IN	O	17	case
cost-sharing	JJ	O	17	amod
funds	NNS	O	17	compound
contribution	NN	O	13	nmod
shared	VBD	O	6	acl
between	IN	O	21	case
Penn	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	21	compound
State	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	18	nmod
and	CC	O	21	cc
industry	NN	O	21	conj
.	.	O	4	punct

``	``	O	0	ROOT
This	DT	O	41	punct
is	VBZ	O	7	nsubj
our	PRP$	O	7	cop
fifth	JJ	B-ORDINAL	7	nmod:poss
consecutive	JJ	O	7	amod
agreement	NN	O	7	amod
,	,	O	41	ccomp
and	CC	O	7	punct
we	PRP	O	7	cc
are	VBP	O	14	nsubjpass
more	JJR	O	14	auxpass
than	IN	O	14	advmod
thrilled	VBN	O	12	case
to	TO	O	7	conj
enter	VB	O	16	mark
into	IN	O	14	xcomp
another	DT	O	20	case
long-term	JJ	O	20	det
agreement	NN	O	20	amod
with	IN	O	16	nmod
our	PRP$	O	23	case
government	NN	O	23	nmod:poss
,	,	O	20	nmod
industry	NN	O	23	punct
and	CC	O	23	conj
university	NN	O	23	cc
partners	NNS	O	28	compound
that	WDT	O	23	conj
will	MD	O	31	nsubj
help	VB	O	31	aux
advance	VB	O	20	acl:relcl
the	DT	O	31	ccomp
frontiers	NNS	O	34	det
of	IN	O	32	dobj
vertical	JJ	O	38	case
lift	NN	O	38	amod
technology	NN	O	38	compound
,	,	O	34	nmod
''	''	O	41	punct
said	VBD	O	41	punct
Edward	NNP	B-PERSON	43	compound
Smith	NNP	I-PERSON	41	nsubj
,	,	O	43	punct
VLRCOE	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	46	compound
director	NN	B-TITLE	43	appos
and	CC	O	46	cc
professor	NN	B-TITLE	46	conj
of	IN	O	51	case
aerospace	NN	O	51	compound
engineering	NN	O	48	nmod
at	IN	O	54	case
Penn	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	54	compound
State	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	46	nmod
.	.	O	41	punct

``	``	O	0	ROOT
Over	IN	O	6	case
the	DT	B-DURATION	6	det
last	JJ	B-DATE	6	amod
20	CD	I-DATE	6	nummod
years	NNS	I-DATE	10	nmod
,	,	O	10	punct
we	PRP	O	10	nsubj
have	VBP	O	10	aux
built	VBN	O	1	root
an	DT	O	16	det
extremely	RB	O	13	advmod
strong	JJ	O	16	amod
,	,	O	16	punct
stable	JJ	O	16	amod
program	NN	O	10	dobj
and	CC	O	16	cc
faculty	NN	O	19	compound
base	NN	O	16	conj
,	,	O	16	punct
as	RB	O	16	cc
well	RB	O	21	mwe
as	IN	O	21	mwe
developed	VBN	O	27	amod
unique	NN	O	27	amod
experimental	NN	O	27	amod
facilities	NNS	O	16	conj
,	,	O	10	punct
that	IN	O	30	nsubj
enable	JJ	O	10	dep
successful	JJ	O	32	amod
transition	NN	O	30	dobj
of	IN	O	35	case
our	PRP$	O	35	nmod:poss
work	NN	O	32	nmod
to	TO	O	40	case
higher	JJR	O	40	amod
technical	JJ	O	40	amod
readiness	NN	O	40	compound
levels	NNS	O	32	nmod
for	IN	O	47	case
the	DT	O	47	det
military	JJ	O	47	amod
and	CC	O	43	cc
commercial	JJ	O	43	conj
aviation	NN	O	47	compound
communities	NNS	O	40	nmod
,	,	O	30	punct
and	CC	O	30	cc
the	DT	O	52	det
rotorcraft	NN	O	52	compound
industry	NN	O	30	conj
.	.	O	10	punct
''	''	O	10	punct

The	DT	O	0	ROOT
funding	NN	O	2	det
will	MD	O	5	nsubj
further	RBR	O	5	aux
collaborative	VB	O	5	advmod
,	,	O	5	punct
interdisciplinary	JJ	O	8	amod
research	NN	O	5	dobj
among	IN	O	12	case
approximately	RB	O	11	advmod
25-30	JJ	O	12	amod
faculty	NN	O	8	nmod
in	IN	O	17	case
several	JJ	O	17	amod
Penn	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	17	compound
State	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	17	compound
College	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	8	nmod
of	IN	I-ORGANIZATION	20	case
Engineering	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	20	compound
departments	NNS	O	17	nmod
,	,	O	17	punct
including	VBG	O	24	case
aerospace	NN	O	24	compound
engineering	NN	O	17	nmod
,	,	O	24	punct
mechanical	JJ	O	24	conj
and	CC	O	24	cc
nuclear	JJ	O	29	amod
engineering	NN	O	24	conj
,	,	O	17	punct
and	CC	O	17	cc
engineering	NN	O	33	compound
science	NN	O	17	conj
and	CC	O	33	cc
mechanics	NNS	O	33	conj
.	.	O	5	punct

Scientists	NNS	O	0	ROOT
and	CC	O	14	nsubjpass
engineers	NNS	O	1	cc
from	IN	O	1	conj
the	DT	O	10	case
Penn	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	10	det
State	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	10	compound
Applied	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	10	compound
Research	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	10	compound
Laboratory	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	10	compound
are	VBP	O	1	nmod
also	RB	O	14	auxpass
highly	RB	O	14	advmod
engaged	VBN	O	14	advmod
in	IN	O	17	case
the	DT	O	17	det
program	NN	O	14	nmod
.	.	O	14	punct

Although	IN	O	0	ROOT
the	DT	O	5	mark
VLRCOE	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	4	det
program	NN	O	4	compound
supports	VBZ	O	5	nsubj
leading-edge	NN	O	15	advcl
research	NN	O	8	amod
objectives	NNS	O	8	compound
of	IN	O	5	dobj
various	JJ	O	12	case
government	NN	O	12	amod
programs	NNS	O	12	compound
,	,	O	8	nmod
it	PRP	O	15	punct
places	VBZ	O	15	nsubj
equal	JJ	O	17	amod
importance	NN	O	15	dobj
on	IN	O	23	case
the	DT	O	23	det
educational	JJ	O	23	amod
and	CC	O	20	cc
technical	JJ	O	20	conj
development	NN	O	15	nmod
of	IN	O	26	case
aspiring	VBG	O	26	amod
engineers	NNS	O	23	nmod
across	IN	O	29	case
multiple	JJ	O	29	amod
disciplines	NNS	O	26	nmod
.	.	O	15	punct

Funding	VBG	O	0	ROOT
from	IN	O	6	nsubj
the	DT	O	4	case
agreement	NN	O	4	det
will	MD	O	1	nmod
support	VB	O	6	aux
approximately	RB	O	8	advmod
20	CD	B-NUMBER	10	nummod
graduate	NN	O	10	amod
students	NNS	O	6	dobj
and	CC	O	10	cc
six	CD	B-NUMBER	14	compound
to	TO	O	14	dep
eight	CD	B-NUMBER	17	nummod
undergraduate	JJ	O	17	amod
research	NN	O	17	compound
assistants	NNS	O	10	conj
annually	RB	B-SET	6	advmod
,	,	O	6	punct
and	CC	O	6	cc
also	RB	O	22	advmod
provide	VB	O	6	conj
support	NN	O	22	dobj
in	IN	O	26	case
the	DT	O	26	det
way	NN	O	22	nmod
of	IN	O	29	case
student	NN	B-TITLE	29	compound
travel	NN	O	26	nmod
to	TO	O	31	case
conferences	NNS	O	29	nmod
,	,	O	6	punct
seminar	NN	O	34	compound
speakers	NNS	O	32	root
and	CC	O	34	cc
an	DT	O	39	det
enhanced	JJ	O	39	amod
educational	JJ	O	39	amod
curriculum	NN	O	34	conj
.	.	O	34	punct

``	``	O	0	ROOT
One	CD	B-NUMBER	38	punct
of	IN	O	9	nsubj
our	PRP$	O	6	case
primary	JJ	O	6	nmod:poss
goals	NNS	O	6	amod
with	IN	O	2	nmod
VLRCOE	NNP	O	8	case
is	VBZ	O	6	nmod
to	TO	O	38	ccomp
educate	VB	O	11	mark
,	,	O	9	xcomp
inspire	NN	O	11	punct
and	CC	O	11	conj
recruit	VB	O	11	cc
the	DT	O	11	conj
next	JJ	O	18	det
generation	NN	O	18	amod
of	IN	O	15	dobj
engineers	NNS	O	20	case
for	IN	O	18	nmod
the	DT	O	25	case
vertical	JJ	O	25	det
flight	NN	O	25	amod
sector	NN	O	25	compound
,	,	O	18	nmod
whether	IN	O	9	punct
that	DT	O	31	mark
be	VB	O	31	nsubj
in	IN	O	31	cop
industry	NN	O	31	case
,	,	O	9	ccomp
academia	NN	O	31	punct
or	CC	O	31	conj
government	NN	O	31	cc
,	,	O	31	conj
''	''	O	38	punct
said	VBD	O	38	punct
Kenneth	NNP	B-PERSON	40	compound
Brentner	NNP	I-PERSON	38	nsubj
,	,	O	40	punct
VLRCOE	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	44	compound
administrative	JJ	O	44	amod
director	NN	B-TITLE	40	appos
and	CC	O	44	cc
professor	NN	B-TITLE	44	conj
of	IN	O	49	case
aerospace	NN	O	49	compound
engineering	NN	O	46	nmod
at	IN	O	52	case
Penn	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	52	compound
State	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	44	nmod
.	.	O	38	punct

``	``	O	0	ROOT
Almost	JJS	O	3	advmod
half	NN	O	8	nsubj
of	IN	O	7	case
the	DT	O	7	det
total	JJ	O	7	amod
funds	NNS	O	3	nmod
support	NN	O	1	root
students	NNS	O	8	dobj
,	,	O	9	punct
which	WDT	O	14	nsubj
is	VBZ	O	14	cop
very	RB	O	14	advmod
important	JJ	O	9	acl:relcl
to	TO	O	17	case
both	DT	O	17	cc:preconj
us	PRP	O	14	nmod
and	CC	O	17	cc
our	PRP$	O	21	nmod:poss
government	NN	O	21	compound
partners	NNS	O	17	conj
.	.	O	8	punct

The	DT	O	0	ROOT
funding	NN	O	2	det
helps	VBZ	O	3	nsubj
the	DT	O	5	det
University	NNP	O	6	nsubj
attract	VB	O	3	ccomp
the	DT	O	11	det
best	JJS	O	11	amod
and	CC	O	8	cc
brightest	JJS	O	8	conj
students	NNS	O	6	dobj
who	WP	O	13	nsubj
get	VBP	O	11	acl:relcl
more	JJR	O	13	dobj
than	IN	O	18	case
a	DT	O	18	det
classroom	NN	O	18	compound
experience	NN	O	14	nmod
;	:	O	3	punct
they	PRP	O	21	nsubj
get	VBP	O	3	parataxis
to	TO	O	23	mark
see	VB	O	21	xcomp
real	JJ	O	26	amod
technology	NN	O	26	compound
problems	NNS	O	23	dobj
we	PRP	O	29	nsubj
're	VBP	O	29	aux
working	VBG	O	26	acl:relcl
on	IN	O	29	nmod
and	CC	O	21	cc
have	VBP	O	21	conj
the	DT	O	34	det
opportunity	NN	O	32	dobj
to	TO	O	36	mark
contribute	VB	O	34	acl
to	TO	O	38	case
solutions	NNS	O	36	nmod
,	,	O	38	punct
which	WDT	O	43	nsubj
is	VBZ	O	43	cop
great	JJ	O	43	amod
experience	NN	O	38	acl:relcl
for	IN	O	45	case
them	PRP	O	43	nmod
.	.	O	3	punct
''	''	O	3	punct

The	DT	O	0	ROOT
cooperative	JJ	O	3	det
agreement	NN	O	3	amod
also	RB	O	5	nsubj
includes	VBZ	O	5	advmod
four	CD	B-NUMBER	8	nummod
university	NN	O	8	compound
partners	NNS	O	5	dobj
that	WDT	O	11	nsubjpass
are	VBP	O	11	auxpass
dedicated	VBN	O	8	acl:relcl
to	TO	O	13	mark
building	VBG	O	11	advcl
a	DT	O	17	det
world-class	NN	O	17	amod
integrated	JJ	O	17	amod
VLRCOE	NNP	O	13	dobj
:	:	O	17	punct
University	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	17	dep
of	IN	I-ORGANIZATION	21	case
Tennessee	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	19	nmod
;	:	O	19	punct
University	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	19	conj
of	IN	I-ORGANIZATION	25	case
California	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	23	nmod
,	,	O	23	punct
Davis	NNP	B-PERSON	23	appos
;	:	O	19	punct
Embry-Riddle	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	31	compound
Aeronautical	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	31	compound
University	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	19	conj
;	:	O	19	punct
and	CC	O	19	cc
Technion	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	36	compound
Israel	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	36	compound
Institute	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	19	conj
of	IN	I-ORGANIZATION	38	case
Technology	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	36	nmod
.	.	O	5	punct

``	``	O	0	ROOT
Partnering	VBG	O	6	punct
with	IN	O	6	csubj
other	JJ	O	5	case
universities	NNS	O	5	amod
allows	VBZ	O	2	nmod
us	PRP	O	36	dep
to	TO	O	6	dobj
expand	VB	O	9	mark
the	DT	O	6	xcomp
range	NN	O	11	det
of	IN	O	9	dobj
capabilities	NNS	O	13	case
and	CC	O	11	nmod
the	DT	O	11	cc
pool	NN	O	16	det
of	IN	O	11	conj
resources	NNS	O	18	case
we	PRP	O	16	nmod
can	MD	O	21	nsubj
bring	VB	O	21	aux
to	TO	O	11	acl:relcl
the	DT	O	26	case
14	CD	B-NUMBER	26	det
research	NN	O	26	nummod
projects	NNS	O	26	compound
that	WDT	O	21	nmod
are	VBP	O	29	nsubj
part	NN	O	29	cop
of	IN	O	26	acl:relcl
this	DT	O	33	case
new	JJ	O	33	det
agreement	NN	O	33	amod
,	,	O	29	nmod
''	''	O	6	punct
said	VBD	O	6	punct
Joseph	NNP	B-PERSON	38	compound
Horn	NNP	I-PERSON	36	nsubj
,	,	O	38	punct
VLRCOE	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	42	compound
deputy	NN	B-TITLE	42	compound
director	NN	I-TITLE	38	appos
and	CC	O	42	cc
professor	NN	B-TITLE	42	conj
of	IN	O	47	case
aerospace	NN	O	47	compound
engineering	NN	O	44	nmod
at	IN	O	50	case
Penn	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	50	compound
State	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	42	nmod
.	.	O	36	punct

``	``	O	0	ROOT
By	IN	O	3	mark
building	VBG	O	20	advcl
a	DT	O	6	det
critical	JJ	O	6	amod
mass	NN	O	3	dobj
of	IN	O	8	case
capabilities	NNS	O	6	nmod
,	,	O	8	punct
faculty	NN	O	8	conj
and	CC	O	8	cc
students	NNS	O	8	conj
in	IN	O	16	case
the	DT	O	16	det
rotorcraft	NN	O	16	compound
field	NN	O	3	nmod
,	,	O	20	punct
we	PRP	O	20	nsubj
're	VBP	O	20	cop
able	JJ	O	1	root
to	TO	O	22	mark
attract	VB	O	20	xcomp
experts	NNS	O	22	dobj
in	IN	O	26	case
related	JJ	O	26	amod
fields	NNS	O	23	nmod
such	JJ	O	29	case
as	IN	O	27	mwe
aeromechanics	NNS	O	26	nmod
,	,	O	29	punct
acoustics	NNS	O	29	conj
and	CC	O	29	cc
propulsion	NN	O	29	conj
,	,	O	22	punct
as	RB	O	22	cc
well	RB	O	35	mwe
as	IN	O	35	mwe
additional	JJ	O	39	amod
sources	NNS	O	22	conj
of	IN	O	41	case
funding	NN	O	39	nmod
related	VBN	O	41	amod
to	TO	O	45	case
rotorcraft	VB	O	45	compound
engineering	NN	O	42	nmod
.	.	O	20	punct
''	''	O	20	punct

Penn	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	0	ROOT
State	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	3	compound
VLRCOE	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	3	compound
is	VBZ	O	5	nsubj
one	CD	B-NUMBER	5	cop
of	IN	O	9	case
only	RB	O	8	advmod
three	CD	B-NUMBER	9	nummod
VLRCOEs	NNP	O	5	nmod
in	IN	O	13	case
the	DT	O	13	det
United	NNP	B-COUNTRY	13	compound
States	NNPS	I-COUNTRY	9	nmod
.	.	O	5	punct

Penn	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	0	ROOT
State	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	2	compound
was	VBD	O	5	nsubjpass
competitively	RB	O	5	auxpass
awarded	JJ	O	5	advmod
one	CD	B-NUMBER	5	dobj
of	IN	O	10	case
three	CD	B-NUMBER	10	nummod
Rotorcraft	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	10	compound
Centers	NNPS	I-ORGANIZATION	6	nmod
of	IN	I-ORGANIZATION	12	case
Excellence	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	10	nmod
-LRB-	NNP	O	14	punct
RCOE	NNP	O	12	appos
-RRB-	NNP	O	14	punct
cooperative	JJ	O	17	amod
agreements	NNS	O	12	dep
in	IN	O	19	case
1996	CD	B-DATE	5	nmod
by	IN	O	27	case
the	DT	O	27	det
newly	RB	O	23	advmod
formed	VBN	O	27	amod
National	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	27	compound
Rotorcraft	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	27	compound
Technology	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	27	compound
Center	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	5	nmod
-LRB-	NNP	O	29	punct
NRTC	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	27	appos
-RRB-	NNP	O	29	punct
.	.	O	5	punct

Since	IN	O	0	ROOT
then	RB	O	2	case
,	,	O	9	nmod
Penn	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	9	punct
State	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	5	compound
has	VBZ	O	9	nsubjpass
been	VBN	O	9	aux
competitively	RB	O	9	auxpass
awarded	VBN	O	9	advmod
RCOE	NNP	O	14	compound
and	CC	O	10	cc
VLRCOE	NNP	O	10	conj
cooperative	JJ	O	14	amod
agreements	NNS	O	9	dobj
from	IN	O	17	case
the	DT	O	17	det
NRTC	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	9	nmod
in	IN	O	19	case
2001	CD	B-DATE	9	nmod
,	,	O	19	punct
2006	CD	B-DATE	19	conj
and	CC	O	19	cc
2011	CD	B-DATE	19	conj
.	.	O	9	punct
Personal	NNP	O	0	ROOT
aircraft	NN	O	2	amod
aiming	VBG	O	20	nsubj
to	TO	O	2	acl
take	VB	O	5	mark
off	RP	O	3	xcomp
from	IN	O	5	compound:prt
your	PRP$	O	12	case
home	NN	O	12	nmod:poss
A	DT	O	12	compound
start-up	JJ	O	12	det
company	NN	O	12	amod
hosted	VBD	O	5	nmod
in	IN	O	5	dobj
an	DT	O	18	case
ESA	NNP	O	18	det
business	NN	O	18	compound
incubator	NN	O	18	compound
is	VBZ	O	13	nmod
developing	VBG	O	20	aux
the	DT	O	22	det
world	NN	O	26	nmod:poss
's	POS	O	22	case
first	JJ	B-ORDINAL	26	amod
vertical	JJ	O	26	amod
takeoff	NN	O	20	dobj
and	CC	O	26	cc
landing	NN	O	29	compound
aircraft	NN	O	26	conj
for	IN	O	32	case
personal	JJ	O	32	amod
use	NN	O	26	nmod
.	.	O	20	punct

The	DT	O	0	ROOT
electric	JJ	O	3	det
two-seater	NN	O	3	amod
will	MD	O	5	nsubj
open	VB	O	5	aux
the	DT	O	7	det
door	NN	O	5	dobj
to	TO	O	11	case
a	DT	O	11	det
new	JJ	O	11	amod
class	NN	O	5	nmod
of	IN	O	19	case
simpler	NN	O	19	amod
,	,	O	13	punct
quieter	NN	O	13	conj
and	CC	O	13	cc
environmentally	RB	O	18	advmod
friendly	JJ	O	13	conj
planes	NNS	O	11	nmod
available	JJ	O	19	amod
from	IN	O	22	case
2018	CD	B-DATE	20	nmod
.	.	O	5	punct

``	``	O	0	ROOT
Our	PRP$	O	4	punct
goal	NN	O	3	nmod:poss
is	VBZ	O	4	nsubj
to	TO	O	16	dep
develop	VB	O	6	mark
an	DT	O	4	xcomp
aircraft	NN	O	8	det
for	IN	O	6	dobj
use	NN	O	10	case
in	IN	O	8	nmod
everyday	JJ	O	13	case
life	NN	O	13	amod
,	,	O	10	nmod
''	''	O	4	punct
explains	VBZ	O	4	punct
Daniel	NNP	B-PERSON	18	compound
Wiegand	NNP	I-PERSON	16	nsubj
,	,	O	18	punct
CEO	NNP	B-TITLE	18	appos
and	CC	O	20	cc
one	CD	B-NUMBER	20	conj
of	IN	O	28	case
the	DT	O	25	det
company	NN	O	28	nmod:poss
's	POS	O	25	case
four	CD	B-NUMBER	28	nummod
founders	NNS	O	22	nmod
.	.	O	16	punct

``	``	O	0	ROOT
We	PRP	O	4	nsubj
are	VBP	O	4	aux
going	VBG	O	1	root
for	IN	O	7	case
a	DT	O	7	det
plane	NN	O	4	nmod
that	WDT	O	10	nsubj
can	MD	O	10	aux
take	VB	O	7	acl:relcl
off	RP	O	10	compound:prt
and	CC	O	10	cc
land	VB	O	10	conj
vertically	RB	O	13	advmod
and	CC	O	10	cc
does	VBZ	O	18	aux
not	RB	O	18	neg
need	VB	O	10	conj
the	DT	O	20	det
complex	JJ	O	18	dobj
and	CC	O	20	cc
expensive	JJ	O	23	amod
infrastructure	NN	O	20	conj
of	IN	O	26	case
an	DT	O	26	det
airport	NN	O	20	nmod
.	.	O	4	punct

``	``	O	0	ROOT
To	TO	O	3	mark
reduce	VB	O	10	advcl
noise	NN	O	3	dobj
and	CC	O	4	cc
pollution	NN	O	4	conj
,	,	O	10	punct
we	PRP	O	10	nsubj
are	VBP	O	10	aux
using	VBG	O	1	root
electric	JJ	O	12	amod
engines	NNS	O	10	dobj
so	IN	O	18	mark
it	PRP	O	18	nsubjpass
can	MD	O	18	aux
also	RB	O	18	advmod
be	VB	O	18	auxpass
used	VBN	O	10	advcl
close	RB	O	18	advmod
to	TO	O	22	case
urban	JJ	O	22	amod
areas	NNS	O	19	nmod
.	.	O	10	punct
''	''	O	10	punct

Lilium	NN	O	0	ROOT
aircraft	NN	O	2	compound
Founded	NNP	O	3	nsubj
in	IN	O	25	advcl
February	NNP	B-DATE	5	case
2015	CD	I-DATE	3	nmod
by	IN	O	5	nummod
four	CD	B-NUMBER	9	case
engineers	NNS	O	9	nummod
and	CC	O	3	nmod
doctoral	JJ	O	9	cc
students	NNS	O	12	amod
from	IN	O	9	conj
the	DT	O	16	case
Technical	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	16	det
University	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	16	compound
of	IN	I-ORGANIZATION	12	nmod
Munich	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	18	case
in	IN	O	16	nmod
Germany	NNP	B-COUNTRY	20	case
,	,	O	16	nmod
Lilium	NNP	B-LOCATION	25	punct
has	VBZ	O	25	nsubj
already	RB	O	25	aux
proved	VBN	O	25	advmod
the	DT	O	27	det
concept	NN	O	25	dobj
with	IN	O	30	case
several	JJ	O	30	amod
scale	NN	O	25	nmod
,	,	O	30	punct
25	CD	B-NUMBER	34	nummod
kg	NN	O	34	compound
prototypes	NNS	O	30	appos
and	CC	O	25	cc
is	VBZ	O	38	aux
now	RB	B-DATE	38	advmod
developing	VBG	O	25	conj
its	PRP$	O	43	nmod:poss
first	JJ	B-ORDINAL	43	amod
ultralight	JJ	O	43	compound
vertical	JJ	O	43	amod
takeoff	NN	O	38	dobj
and	CC	O	43	cc
landing	NN	O	46	compound
aircraft	NN	O	43	conj
.	.	O	25	punct

Simpler	NNP	O	0	ROOT
and	CC	O	5	amod
easier	JJR	O	1	cc
air	NN	O	1	conj
transportation	NN	O	5	compound
Today	NNP	B-DATE	11	nsubj
,	,	O	11	nmod:tmod
general	JJ	B-TITLE	11	punct
public	JJ	O	10	amod
aviation	NN	O	10	amod
offers	VBZ	O	11	nsubj
fixed-wing	JJ	O	13	amod
aircraft	NN	O	11	dobj
and	CC	O	13	cc
helicopters	NNS	O	13	conj
.	.	O	11	punct

Conventional	JJ	O	0	ROOT
aircraft	NN	O	2	amod
are	VBP	O	4	nsubj
efficient	JJ	O	4	cop
,	,	O	4	punct
fast	RB	O	4	conj
and	CC	O	4	cc
available	JJ	O	4	conj
in	IN	O	11	case
many	JJ	O	11	amod
sizes	NNS	O	8	nmod
but	CC	O	4	cc
require	VBP	O	4	conj
airports	NNS	O	13	dobj
often	RB	O	16	advmod
20-50	JJ	B-NUMBER	17	nummod
km	NNS	O	14	dobj
from	IN	O	20	case
city	NN	O	20	compound
centres	NNS	O	17	nmod
because	IN	O	25	case
of	IN	O	21	mwe
their	PRP$	O	25	nmod:poss
space-hungry	JJ	O	25	amod
runways	NNS	O	13	nmod
and	CC	O	25	cc
the	DT	O	30	det
high	JJ	O	30	amod
noise	NN	O	30	compound
levels	NNS	O	25	conj
.	.	O	4	punct

Airports	NNS	O	0	ROOT
are	VBP	O	4	nsubj
expensive	JJ	O	4	cop
bottlenecks	NNS	O	4	amod
for	IN	O	6	case
transportation	NN	O	4	nmod
.	.	O	4	punct

This	DT	O	0	ROOT
is	VBZ	O	1	dep
especially	RB	O	4	advmod
so	RB	O	2	advmod
for	IN	O	7	case
short-haul	JJ	O	7	amod
flights	NNS	O	4	nmod
,	,	O	7	punct
where	WRB	O	18	advmod
travel	NN	O	11	compound
time	NN	O	18	nsubj
to	TO	O	15	case
and	CC	O	12	cc
from	IN	O	12	conj
airports	NNS	O	11	nmod
can	MD	O	18	aux
easily	RB	O	18	advmod
double	VB	O	7	acl:relcl
the	DT	O	20	det
duration	NN	O	18	dobj
of	IN	O	23	case
a	DT	O	23	det
trip	NN	O	20	nmod
.	.	O	1	punct

This	DT	O	0	ROOT
is	VBZ	O	5	nsubj
not	RB	O	5	cop
a	DT	O	5	neg
problem	NN	O	5	det
for	IN	O	7	case
helicopters	NNS	O	5	nmod
,	,	O	7	punct
which	WDT	O	11	nsubj
can	MD	O	11	aux
take	VB	O	7	acl:relcl
off	RP	O	11	compound:prt
almost	RB	O	14	advmod
anywhere	RB	O	11	advmod
and	CC	O	11	cc
are	VBP	O	19	auxpass
therefore	RB	O	19	advmod
often	RB	O	19	advmod
used	VBN	O	11	conj
for	IN	O	23	case
short	JJ	O	23	amod
shuttle	JJ	O	23	compound
flights	NNS	O	19	nmod
and	CC	O	23	cc
special	JJ	O	26	amod
applications	NNS	O	23	conj
.	.	O	5	punct

However	RB	O	0	ROOT
,	,	O	6	advmod
helicopters	NNS	O	6	punct
are	VBP	O	6	nsubj
very	RB	O	6	cop
noisy	JJ	O	6	advmod
and	CC	O	6	cc
difficult	JJ	O	6	conj
to	TO	O	10	mark
fly	VB	O	6	xcomp
-	:	O	10	punct
which	WDT	O	13	nsubj
requires	VBZ	O	10	ccomp
expensive	JJ	O	15	amod
licences	NNS	O	13	dobj
.	.	O	6	punct

They	PRP	O	0	ROOT
also	RB	O	3	nsubj
have	VBP	O	3	advmod
no	DT	O	5	neg
backup	NN	O	3	dobj
in	IN	O	7	case
case	NN	O	5	nmod
of	IN	O	10	case
rotor	NN	O	10	compound
failure	NN	O	7	nmod
,	,	O	3	punct
making	VBG	O	3	advcl
them	PRP	O	14	nsubj
expensive	JJ	O	12	xcomp
to	TO	O	16	mark
build	VB	O	14	ccomp
and	CC	O	16	cc
maintain	VB	O	16	conj
.	.	O	3	punct

Access	IN	O	0	ROOT
the	DT	O	3	det
video	NN	O	1	dobj
The	DT	O	6	det
Lilium	NNP	O	6	compound
vehicle	NN	O	7	nsubj
combines	VBZ	O	3	acl:relcl
the	DT	O	9	det
benefits	NNS	O	7	dobj
of	IN	O	11	case
helicopters	NNS	O	9	nmod
and	CC	O	11	cc
fixed-wing	NN	O	14	amod
aircraft	NN	O	11	conj
while	IN	O	16	mark
avoiding	VBG	O	7	advcl
their	PRP$	O	18	nmod:poss
drawbacks	NNS	O	16	dobj
.	.	O	1	punct

While	IN	O	0	ROOT
initially	RB	O	3	mark
restricted	VBN	O	3	advmod
to	TO	O	9	advcl
airfields	NNS	O	5	case
,	,	O	3	nmod
the	DT	O	9	punct
goal	NN	O	8	det
is	VBZ	O	9	nsubj
for	IN	O	13	mark
it	PRP	O	13	nsubj
to	TO	O	13	mark
take	VB	O	73	advcl
off	RP	O	13	compound:prt
vertically	RB	O	13	advmod
from	IN	O	18	case
almost	RB	O	18	advmod
anywhere	SYM	O	13	nmod
-	:	O	18	punct
even	RB	O	23	advmod
from	IN	O	23	case
back	RB	O	23	advmod
gardens	VBZ	O	18	nmod
-	:	O	13	punct
it	PRP	O	26	nsubj
needs	VBZ	O	13	ccomp
only	RB	O	31	advmod
an	DT	O	31	det
open	JJ	O	31	amod
flat	JJ	O	31	amod
area	NN	O	26	dobj
of	IN	O	35	case
about	IN	O	35	case
15x15	CD	O	35	compound
m.	NNS	O	31	nmod
Although	IN	O	37	mark
taking	VBG	O	26	advcl
off	RP	O	37	compound:prt
and	CC	O	37	cc
landing	VBG	O	37	conj
like	IN	O	43	case
a	DT	O	43	det
helicopter	NN	O	40	nmod
,	,	O	37	punct
by	IN	O	46	mark
swivelling	VBG	O	37	advcl
its	PRP$	O	48	nmod:poss
engines	NNS	O	46	dobj
it	PRP	O	51	nsubj
also	RB	O	51	advmod
functions	VBZ	O	48	acl:relcl
as	IN	O	56	case
a	DT	O	56	det
very	RB	O	55	advmod
efficient	JJ	O	56	amod
aircraft	NN	O	51	nmod
that	WDT	O	59	nsubj
can	MD	O	59	aux
travel	VB	O	56	acl:relcl
at	IN	O	65	case
up	RB	O	63	advmod
to	TO	O	63	dep
400	CD	B-NUMBER	65	nummod
km	NNS	O	65	compound
h.	RBR	O	59	nmod
Entirely	RB	O	67	advmod
electric	JJ	O	65	amod
,	,	O	73	punct
the	DT	O	70	det
plane	NN	O	73	nsubj
is	VBZ	O	73	cop
much	JJ	O	73	advmod
quieter	NN	O	9	ccomp
during	IN	O	75	case
takeoff	NN	O	73	nmod
than	IN	O	77	case
helicopters	NNS	O	73	nmod
thanks	NNS	O	77	dep
to	TO	O	83	case
its	PRP$	O	83	nmod:poss
ducted	VBN	O	83	amod
fan	NN	O	83	compound
engines	NNS	O	78	nmod
.	.	O	9	punct

Its	PRP$	O	0	ROOT
batteries	NNS	O	2	nmod:poss
,	,	O	8	nsubj
engines	NNS	O	2	punct
and	CC	O	2	conj
controllers	NNS	O	2	cc
are	VBP	O	2	conj
redundant	JJ	O	8	cop
,	,	O	8	punct
making	VBG	O	8	xcomp
it	PRP	O	15	nsubj
a	DT	O	15	det
much	RB	O	14	advmod
safer	JJR	O	15	amod
design	NN	O	10	xcomp
than	IN	O	18	case
conventional	JJ	O	18	amod
helicopters	NNS	O	15	nmod
.	.	O	8	punct

Mountain	NN	O	0	ROOT
flight	NN	O	2	compound
The	DT	O	6	dep
plane	NN	O	4	det
is	VBZ	O	6	nsubjpass
classed	VBN	O	6	auxpass
as	IN	O	11	case
a	DT	O	11	det
Light	NNP	O	11	amod
Sport	NNP	O	11	compound
Aircraft	NNP	O	6	nmod
for	IN	O	14	case
two	CD	B-NUMBER	14	nummod
occupants	NNS	O	6	nmod
,	,	O	6	punct
with	IN	O	20	case
the	DT	O	18	det
pilot	NN	B-TITLE	20	nmod:poss
's	POS	O	18	case
licence	NN	O	6	nmod
requiring	VBG	O	20	acl
20	CD	B-DURATION	23	nummod
hours	NNS	I-DURATION	26	nmod:poss
'	POS	O	23	case
minimum	JJ	O	26	amod
training	NN	O	21	dobj
-	:	O	26	punct
almost	RB	O	30	advmod
like	IN	O	30	mark
taking	VBG	O	26	acl
a	DT	O	33	det
driving	NN	O	33	amod
licence	NN	O	30	dobj
.	.	O	6	punct

It	PRP	O	0	ROOT
is	VBZ	O	3	nsubjpass
intended	VBN	O	3	auxpass
for	IN	O	6	case
recreational	JJ	O	6	amod
flying	VBG	O	3	nmod
during	IN	O	8	case
daylight	NN	B-TIME	6	nmod
,	,	O	6	punct
in	IN	O	13	case
good	JJ	O	13	amod
weather	NN	O	13	compound
conditions	NNS	O	6	conj
and	CC	O	6	cc
in	IN	O	17	case
uncongested	JJ	O	17	amod
airspace	NN	O	6	conj
up	RB	O	20	advmod
to	TO	O	20	dep
3	CD	B-NUMBER	22	nummod
km	NNS	O	22	compound
altitude	NN	O	17	dep
.	.	O	3	punct

Using	VBG	O	0	ROOT
computer	NN	O	10	csubj
control	NN	O	3	compound
for	IN	O	1	dobj
vertical	JJ	O	6	case
takeoff	NN	O	6	amod
and	CC	O	3	nmod
landing	NN	O	6	cc
is	VBZ	O	6	conj
essential	JJ	O	10	cop
for	IN	O	13	case
a	DT	O	13	det
vehicle	NN	O	10	nmod
targeted	VBN	O	13	acl
at	IN	O	18	case
the	DT	O	18	det
consumer	NN	O	18	compound
market	NN	O	14	nmod
for	IN	O	21	mark
personal	JJ	O	21	amod
transportation.Addressing	VBG	O	14	advcl
the	DT	O	24	det
Safety	NNP	O	24	compound
Issues	NNP	O	21	dobj
of	IN	O	27	case
Air	NNP	O	27	compound
Transportation	NNP	O	24	nmod
of	IN	O	30	case
Lithium-ion	NNP	O	30	compound
Batteries	NNP	O	27	nmod
Using	NNP	O	21	xcomp
Thermal	NNP	O	34	amod
Management	NNP	O	34	compound
Solutions	NNP	O	31	dobj
The	DT	O	36	det
problems	NNS	O	34	dep
created	VBN	O	36	acl
by	IN	O	41	case
lithium	NN	O	41	compound
ion	NN	O	41	compound
batteries	NNS	O	37	nmod
Lithium-ion	NNP	B-MISC	43	amod
batteries	NNS	O	47	nsubj
are	VBP	O	47	cop
almost	RB	O	46	advmod
everywhere	RB	O	47	advmod
nowadays	JJ	O	41	acl:relcl
and	CC	O	47	cc
provide	JJ	O	47	conj
power	NN	O	49	dobj
for	IN	O	55	case
notebook	NN	O	55	compound
and	CC	O	52	cc
tablet	NN	O	52	conj
computers	NNS	O	50	nmod
,	,	O	10	punct
MP3	NNP	O	58	compound
players	NNS	O	56	root
,	,	O	58	punct
mobile	JJ	B-TITLE	61	amod
phones	NNS	O	58	conj
and	CC	O	58	cc
cameras	NNS	O	58	conj
,	,	O	58	punct
as	RB	O	58	cc
well	RB	O	65	mwe
as	IN	O	65	mwe
cordless	NN	O	69	amod
devices	NNS	O	58	conj
.	.	O	58	punct

This	DT	O	0	ROOT
means	VBZ	O	2	nsubj
that	IN	O	8	mark
many	JJ	O	6	amod
air	NN	O	6	compound
passengers	NNS	O	8	nsubj
will	MD	O	8	aux
carry	VB	O	2	ccomp
at	IN	O	10	case
least	JJS	O	11	nmod:npmod
one	CD	B-NUMBER	12	nummod
battery	NN	B-CRIMINAL_CHARGE	8	dobj
with	IN	O	14	case
them	PRP	O	8	nmod
as	IN	O	16	case
part	NN	O	8	nmod
of	IN	O	19	case
the	DT	O	19	det
items	NNS	O	16	nmod
they	PRP	O	21	nsubj
carry	VBP	O	19	acl:relcl
onto	IN	O	24	case
the	DT	O	24	det
aircraft	NN	O	21	nmod
.	.	O	2	punct

While	IN	O	0	ROOT
these	DT	O	6	mark
batteries	NNS	O	3	det
are	VBP	O	6	nsubj
generally	RB	O	6	cop
reliable	JJ	O	6	advmod
one	CD	B-NUMBER	8	nummod
issue	NN	O	13	nsubj
with	IN	O	10	case
them	PRP	O	8	nmod
is	VBZ	O	13	cop
their	PRP$	O	13	nmod:poss
ability	NN	O	6	ccomp
,	,	O	13	punct
in	IN	O	18	case
a	DT	O	18	det
small	JJ	O	18	amod
number	NN	O	13	nmod
of	IN	O	20	case
cases	NNS	O	18	nmod
,	,	O	13	punct
to	TO	O	23	mark
overheat	VB	O	13	acl
and	CC	O	23	cc
catch	VB	O	23	conj
fire	NN	B-CAUSE_OF_DEATH	23	dobj
.	.	O	6	punct

While	IN	O	0	ROOT
this	DT	B-DATE	5	mark
may	MD	I-DATE	5	nsubj
be	VB	O	5	aux
less	JJR	O	5	cop
of	IN	O	28	advcl
an	DT	O	8	case
issue	NN	O	8	det
and	CC	O	5	nmod
more	JJR	O	5	cc
easily	RB	O	11	advmod
contained	VBN	O	12	advmod
in	IN	O	5	conj
land-based	JJ	O	15	case
environments	NNS	O	15	amod
or	CC	O	12	nmod
other	JJ	O	15	cc
modes	NNS	O	18	amod
of	IN	O	15	conj
transport	NN	O	20	case
,	,	O	18	nmod
the	DT	O	28	punct
prospect	NN	O	23	det
of	IN	O	28	nsubj
a	DT	O	26	case
fire	NN	B-CAUSE_OF_DEATH	26	det
is	VBZ	O	23	nmod
something	NN	O	28	cop
which	WDT	O	34	nsubjpass
simply	RB	O	34	advmod
can	MD	O	34	aux
not	RB	O	34	neg
be	VB	O	34	auxpass
countenanced	VBN	O	28	acl:relcl
in	IN	O	38	case
the	DT	O	38	det
enclosed	JJ	O	38	amod
space	NN	O	34	nmod
of	IN	O	41	case
an	DT	O	41	det
aircraft	NN	O	38	nmod
,	,	O	41	punct
which	WDT	O	46	nsubj
may	MD	O	46	aux
be	VB	O	46	aux
carrying	VBG	O	41	acl:relcl
several	JJ	O	48	advmod
hundred	CD	B-NUMBER	49	nummod
passengers	NNS	O	46	dobj
,	,	O	41	punct
as	RB	O	41	cc
well	RB	O	51	mwe
as	IN	O	51	mwe
crew	NN	O	41	conj
.	.	O	28	punct

The	DT	O	0	ROOT
issue	NN	O	2	det
with	IN	O	5	nsubj
heat	NN	O	4	case
relates	NNS	O	2	nmod
to	TO	O	9	case
the	DT	O	9	det
potential	JJ	O	9	amod
creation	NN	O	5	nmod
of	IN	O	12	case
thermal	JJ	O	12	amod
runaway	NN	O	9	nmod
.	.	O	5	punct

This	DT	O	0	ROOT
can	MD	O	4	nsubjpass
be	VB	O	4	aux
defined	VBN	O	4	auxpass
as	IN	O	6	case
auto-acceleration	NN	O	4	nmod
of	IN	O	9	case
heat	NN	O	9	compound
generation	NN	O	6	nmod
,	,	O	4	punct
with	IN	O	15	case
a	DT	O	15	det
rapid	JJ	O	15	amod
temperature	NN	O	15	compound
increase	NN	O	4	nmod
,	,	O	15	punct
characterised	VBN	O	15	acl
by	IN	O	20	case
the	DT	O	20	det
expulsion	NN	O	17	nmod
of	IN	O	23	case
flammable	JJ	O	23	amod
gases	NNS	O	20	nmod
and	CC	O	23	cc
liquids	NNS	O	23	conj
from	IN	O	29	case
the	DT	O	29	det
product	NN	O	29	compound
casing	NN	O	20	nmod
.	.	O	4	punct

Put	VB	O	0	ROOT
simply	RB	O	1	advmod
,	,	O	1	punct
just	RB	O	5	advmod
one	CD	B-NUMBER	7	nummod
battery	NN	B-CRIMINAL_CHARGE	7	compound
overheating	NN	O	9	nsubj
can	MD	O	9	aux
result	VB	O	1	ccomp
in	IN	O	12	case
a	DT	O	12	det
matter	NN	O	9	nmod
of	IN	O	16	case
a	DT	B-DURATION	16	det
few	JJ	I-DURATION	16	amod
minutes	NNS	I-DURATION	12	nmod
in	IN	O	20	case
an	DT	O	20	det
uncontrollable	JJ	O	20	amod
fire	NN	B-CAUSE_OF_DEATH	16	nmod
,	,	O	20	punct
explosion	NN	B-CAUSE_OF_DEATH	20	conj
or	CC	O	20	cc
pressure	NN	O	25	compound
wave	VBP	O	20	conj
-	:	O	16	punct
or	CC	O	16	cc
even	RB	O	30	advmod
all	DT	O	30	det
three	CD	B-NUMBER	16	conj
.	.	O	1	punct

The	DT	O	0	ROOT
key	JJ	O	3	det
challenge	NN	O	3	amod
is	VBZ	O	4	nsubj
to	TO	O	6	mark
prevent	VB	O	4	xcomp
propagation	NN	O	6	dobj
between	IN	O	9	case
cells	NNS	O	7	nmod
,	,	O	9	punct
modules	NNS	O	9	conj
,	,	O	9	punct
packaging	NN	O	9	conj
and	CC	O	9	cc
surroundings	NNS	O	9	conj
-	:	O	6	punct
on	IN	O	19	case
an	DT	O	19	det
aircraft	NN	O	6	nmod
,	,	O	19	punct
the	DT	O	22	det
aim	NN	O	23	nsubj
is	VBZ	O	19	acl:relcl
to	TO	O	25	mark
extend	VB	O	23	xcomp
the	DT	O	27	det
time	NN	O	25	dobj
available	JJ	O	27	amod
for	IN	O	34	mark
emergency	NN	O	31	compound
measures	NNS	O	34	nsubjpass
to	TO	O	34	mark
be	VB	O	34	auxpass
employed	VBN	O	28	advcl
and	CC	O	34	cc
for	IN	O	38	case
safe	JJ	O	38	amod
landing	NN	O	34	conj
to	TO	O	40	mark
occur	VB	O	38	acl
.	.	O	4	punct

In	IN	O	0	ROOT
an	DT	O	4	case
ideal	JJ	O	4	det
world	NN	O	4	amod
,	,	O	8	nmod
manufacturers	NNS	O	8	punct
would	MD	O	8	nsubj
employ	VB	O	8	aux
chemistries	NNS	O	8	dobj
and	CC	O	9	cc
cell	NN	O	12	compound
structures	NNS	O	9	conj
which	WDT	O	14	nsubj
prevent	VBP	O	9	acl:relcl
thermal	JJ	O	16	amod
runaway	NN	O	14	dobj
from	IN	O	18	mark
occurring	VBG	O	14	advcl
.	.	O	8	punct

However	RB	O	0	ROOT
,	,	O	15	advmod
increasing	VBG	O	15	punct
energy	NN	O	5	amod
densities	NNS	O	5	compound
-	:	O	7	dep
batteries	NNS	O	7	punct
simply	RB	O	15	nsubj
required	VBD	O	9	advmod
to	TO	O	7	acl
hold	VB	O	11	mark
more	JJR	O	9	xcomp
charge	NN	O	13	amod
-	:	O	11	dobj
make	VB	O	7	punct
this	DT	O	18	nsubj
highly	RB	O	18	advmod
challenging	JJ	O	15	xcomp
,	,	O	18	punct
especially	RB	O	22	advmod
in	IN	O	22	case
applications	NNS	O	18	nmod
where	WRB	O	26	advmod
space	NN	O	26	nsubj
is	VBZ	O	26	cop
critical	JJ	O	22	acl:relcl
.	.	O	15	punct

Between	IN	O	0	ROOT
March	NNP	B-DATE	2	case
1991	CD	I-DATE	16	nmod
and	CC	O	2	nummod
January	NNP	B-DATE	2	cc
2016	CD	I-DATE	2	conj
,	,	O	5	nummod
the	DT	O	16	punct
US	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	12	det
Federal	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	12	compound
Aviation	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	12	compound
Administration	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	12	compound
-LRB-	NNP	O	16	nsubj
FAA	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	14	punct
-RRB-	NNP	O	12	appos
recorded	VBD	O	14	punct
a	DT	O	18	det
total	NN	O	24	nsubj
of	IN	O	21	case
171	CD	B-NUMBER	21	nummod
incidents	NNS	O	18	nmod
involving	VBG	O	21	acl
batteries	NNS	O	22	dobj
carried	VBD	O	16	ccomp
as	IN	O	26	case
baggage	NN	O	24	nmod
or	CC	O	26	cc
cargo	NN	O	26	conj
.	.	O	16	punct

As	IN	O	0	ROOT
the	DT	B-DURATION	5	mark
years	NNS	I-DURATION	3	det
have	VBP	O	5	nsubj
passed	VBN	O	5	aux
,	,	O	14	advcl
an	DT	O	14	punct
increasing	VBG	O	9	det
proportion	NN	O	9	amod
of	IN	O	14	nsubjpass
these	DT	O	12	case
incidents	NNS	O	12	det
are	VBP	O	9	nmod
created	VBN	O	14	auxpass
by	IN	O	17	case
lithium	NN	O	17	compound
batteries	NNS	O	14	nmod
.	.	O	14	punct

These	DT	O	0	ROOT
incidents	NNS	O	2	det
have	VBP	O	3	nsubj
in	IN	O	6	case
some	DT	O	6	det
cases	NNS	O	7	nmod
created	VBD	O	3	ccomp
a	DT	O	10	det
catastrophic	JJ	O	10	amod
effect	NN	O	7	dobj
.	.	O	3	punct

A	DT	O	0	ROOT
fire	NN	B-CAUSE_OF_DEATH	2	det
which	WDT	O	16	nsubj
broke	VBD	O	4	nsubj
out	RP	O	2	acl:relcl
on	IN	O	4	compound:prt
a	DT	O	11	case
UPS	NNP	B-MISC	11	det
DC-8	NNP	I-MISC	11	compound
cargo	NN	O	11	compound
plane	NN	O	11	compound
in	IN	O	4	nmod
Philadelphia	NNP	B-CITY	13	case
in	IN	O	11	nmod
2006	CD	B-DATE	15	case
saw	VBD	O	4	nmod
the	DT	O	18	det
aircraft	NN	O	20	nsubj
completely	RB	O	20	advmod
destroyed	VBN	O	16	ccomp
.	.	O	16	punct

Four	CD	B-DATE	0	ROOT
years	NNS	I-DATE	2	nummod
later	RB	I-DATE	3	nmod:npmod
,	,	O	15	advmod
another	DT	O	15	punct
aircraft	NN	O	6	det
laden	NN	O	15	nsubj
with	IN	O	6	amod
a	DT	O	10	case
cargo	NN	O	10	det
of	IN	O	7	nmod
81,000	CD	B-NUMBER	14	case
lithium	NN	O	14	nummod
batteries	NNS	O	14	compound
caught	VBD	O	10	nmod
fire	NN	B-CAUSE_OF_DEATH	15	dobj
and	CC	O	15	cc
crashed	VBN	O	15	conj
shortly	RB	O	18	advmod
after	IN	O	21	case
take-off	NN	O	18	nmod
from	IN	O	23	case
Dubai	NNP	B-CITY	21	nmod
,	,	O	15	punct
with	IN	O	27	case
two	CD	B-NUMBER	27	nummod
fatalities	NNS	O	15	nmod
.	.	O	15	punct

The	DT	B-DATE	0	ROOT
year	NN	I-DATE	2	det
after	IN	O	9	nmod:tmod
that	DT	O	4	case
,	,	O	2	nmod
two	CD	B-NUMBER	9	punct
crew	VBD	O	8	nummod
members	NNS	O	8	compound
lost	VBN	O	9	nsubj
their	PRP$	O	11	nmod:poss
lives	NNS	O	9	dobj
when	WRB	O	16	advmod
a	DT	O	15	det
cargo	NN	O	15	compound
jet	NN	O	16	nsubj
crashed	VBD	O	9	advcl
into	IN	O	21	case
the	DT	O	21	det
East	NNP	B-LOCATION	21	compound
China	NNP	B-COUNTRY	21	compound
Sea	NNP	B-LOCATION	16	nmod
,	,	O	9	punct
shortly	RB	O	28	advmod
after	IN	O	28	mark
a	DT	O	27	det
crew	NN	O	27	compound
member	NN	O	28	nsubj
reported	VBD	O	9	advcl
a	DT	O	30	det
fire	NN	B-CAUSE_OF_DEATH	28	dobj
on	IN	O	32	case
board	NN	O	30	nmod
.	.	O	9	punct

What	WP	O	0	ROOT
does	VBZ	O	5	dobj
the	DT	O	5	aux
law	NN	O	4	det
say	VBP	O	5	nsubj
?	.	O	5	punct

There	EX	O	0	ROOT
are	VBP	O	2	expl
two	CD	B-NUMBER	5	nummod
main	JJ	O	5	amod
types	NNS	O	2	nsubj
of	IN	O	8	case
lithium	NN	O	8	compound
batteries	NNS	O	5	nmod
-	:	O	5	punct
Primary	NNP	O	11	amod
Lithium	NNP	O	5	dep
-LRB-	NNP	O	13	punct
UN3090	NNP	O	11	appos
-RRB-	NNP	O	13	punct
and	CC	O	11	cc
Lithium-Ion	NNP	O	11	conj
-LRB-	NNP	O	18	punct
UN	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	16	appos
3480	CD	B-NUMBER	18	nummod
-RRB-	NNP	O	18	punct
.	.	O	2	punct

The	DT	O	0	ROOT
risk	NN	O	2	det
of	IN	O	15	nsubjpass
fire	NN	B-CAUSE_OF_DEATH	4	case
created	VBN	O	2	nmod
by	IN	O	4	acl
both	DT	O	7	case
of	IN	O	5	nmod
these	DT	O	11	case
battery	NN	B-CRIMINAL_CHARGE	11	det
types	NNS	O	11	compound
has	VBZ	O	7	nmod
long	RB	O	15	aux
been	VBN	O	15	advmod
recognised	VBN	O	15	auxpass
by	IN	O	18	case
the	DT	O	18	det
authorities	NNS	O	15	nmod
with	IN	O	21	mark
both	DT	O	21	nsubj
classified	VBN	O	15	advcl
as	IN	O	26	case
Class	NN	O	26	compound
9	CD	B-NUMBER	26	nummod
hazardous	JJ	O	26	amod
materials	NNS	O	21	nmod
in	IN	O	28	case
Title	NNP	O	21	nmod
49	CD	B-NUMBER	28	nummod
of	IN	O	32	case
the	DT	O	32	det
Code	NNP	O	28	nmod
of	IN	O	35	case
Federal	NNP	O	35	compound
Regulations	NNP	O	32	nmod
,	,	O	15	punct
the	DT	O	40	det
Hazardous	NNP	B-MISC	40	compound
Materials	NNP	I-MISC	40	compound
Regulations	NNP	I-MISC	36	root
and	CC	O	40	cc
the	DT	O	46	det
International	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	46	compound
Civil	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	46	compound
Aviation	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	46	compound
Organization	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	51	compound
-LRB-	NNP	O	48	punct
ICAO	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	51	appos
-RRB-	NNP	O	48	punct
Technical	NNP	O	51	compound
Instructions	NNP	O	40	conj
.	.	O	40	punct

A	DT	O	0	ROOT
fire	NN	B-CAUSE_OF_DEATH	2	det
at	IN	O	14	nsubj
Los	NNP	B-CITY	6	case
Angeles	NNP	I-CITY	6	compound
Airport	NNP	B-LOCATION	6	compound
in	IN	O	2	nmod
1999	CD	B-DATE	8	case
involving	VBG	O	2	nmod
120,000	CD	B-NUMBER	8	acl
lithium	JJ	O	13	nummod
primary	JJ	O	13	compound
cells	NNS	O	13	amod
resulted	VBD	O	9	dobj
in	IN	O	17	case
the	DT	O	17	det
issue	NN	O	14	nmod
of	IN	O	21	case
five	CD	B-NUMBER	21	nummod
separate	JJ	O	21	amod
fire	NN	B-CAUSE_OF_DEATH	17	nmod
and	CC	O	21	cc
safety	NN	O	24	compound
recommendations	NNS	O	21	conj
by	IN	O	30	case
the	DT	O	30	det
National	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	30	compound
Transportation	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	30	compound
Safety	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	30	compound
Board	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	17	nmod
which	WDT	O	32	nsubj
conducted	VBD	O	30	acl:relcl
an	DT	O	34	det
investigation	NN	O	32	dobj
,	,	O	14	punct
to	TO	O	38	case
the	DT	O	38	det
Research	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	14	nmod
&	CC	I-ORGANIZATION	38	cc
Special	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	42	amod
Programs	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	42	compound
Administration	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	38	conj
and	CC	O	38	cc
FAA	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	38	conj
,	,	O	14	punct
alongside	IN	O	48	case
the	DT	O	48	det
issue	NN	O	14	nmod
of	IN	O	54	case
FAA	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	54	compound
Dangerous	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	54	compound
Goods	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	54	compound
Advisory	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	54	compound
Bulletin	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	48	nmod
-LRB-	NNP	O	56	punct
DAGB	NNP	O	54	appos
-RRB-	NNP	O	56	punct
00-02	NN	B-NUMBER	48	dep
on	IN	O	61	case
this	DT	O	61	det
subject	NN	O	58	nmod
.	.	O	14	punct

With	IN	O	0	ROOT
subsequent	JJ	O	4	mark
studies	NNS	O	3	amod
demonstrating	VBG	O	4	nsubj
that	IN	O	14	mark
primary	JJ	O	9	amod
lithium	NN	O	9	compound
cell	NN	O	9	compound
fires	NNS	B-CAUSE_OF_DEATH	14	nsubjpass
can	MD	O	14	aux
not	RB	O	14	neg
be	VB	O	14	auxpass
adequately	RB	O	14	advmod
suppressed	VBN	O	4	ccomp
by	IN	O	16	case
halon	NN	O	14	nmod
,	,	O	16	punct
primary	JJ	O	20	amod
lithium	NN	O	20	compound
batteries	NNS	O	22	nsubjpass
were	VBD	O	22	auxpass
banned	VBN	O	16	acl:relcl
on	IN	O	25	case
passenger	NN	O	25	compound
aircraft	NN	O	22	nmod
by	IN	O	28	case
the	DT	O	28	det
FAA	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	22	nmod
in	IN	O	30	case
2005	CD	B-DATE	22	nmod
and	CC	O	22	cc
by	IN	O	37	case
the	DT	O	37	det
International	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	37	compound
Civil	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	37	compound
Aviation	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	37	compound
Organization	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	22	conj
-LRB-	NNP	O	39	punct
ICAO	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	37	appos
-RRB-	NN	O	39	punct
from	IN	O	43	case
the	DT	B-DATE	43	det
start	NN	I-DATE	37	nmod
of	IN	I-DATE	45	case
2015	CD	I-DATE	43	nmod
.	.	O	4	punct

Meanwhile	RB	O	0	ROOT
FAA	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	4	advmod
Safety	NNP	O	4	compound
Alert	NNP	O	4	compound
for	IN	O	6	case
Operators	NNP	O	4	nmod
-LRB-	NNP	O	8	punct
SAFO	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	6	appos
-RRB-	VBD	O	8	punct
16001	CD	B-NUMBER	6	nummod
:	:	O	4	punct
Risks	NNS	O	33	nsubj
of	IN	O	14	case
Fire	NNP	B-CAUSE_OF_DEATH	12	nmod
or	CC	O	14	cc
Explosion	NNP	B-CAUSE_OF_DEATH	14	conj
when	WRB	O	18	advmod
Transporting	VBG	O	12	acl:relcl
Lithium	NNP	O	20	compound
Ion	NNP	O	18	dobj
or	CC	O	20	cc
Lithium	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	24	compound
Metal	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	24	compound
Batteries	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	20	conj
as	IN	O	26	case
Cargo	NNP	O	18	nmod
on	IN	O	28	case
Passenger	NNP	O	26	nmod
and	CC	O	28	cc
Cargo	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	31	compound
Aircraft	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	28	conj
,	,	O	12	punct
supports	VBZ	O	4	parataxis
recommendations	NNS	O	33	dobj
that	IN	O	55	mark
before	IN	O	38	mark
operators	NNS	O	38	nsubj
engage	VBP	O	55	advcl
in	IN	O	41	case
the	DT	O	41	det
transport	NN	O	38	nmod
of	IN	O	44	case
lithium	JJ	O	44	compound
ion	NN	O	41	nmod
or	CC	O	44	cc
lithium	NN	O	48	compound
metal	NN	O	48	compound
batteries	NNS	O	44	conj
in	IN	O	51	case
cargo	NN	O	51	compound
aircraft	NN	O	41	nmod
they	PRP	O	55	nsubj
should	MD	O	55	aux
be	VB	O	55	cop
aware	JJ	O	34	ccomp
that	IN	O	62	mark
both	DT	O	58	cc:preconj
ICAO	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	62	nsubj
and	CC	O	58	cc
major	JJ	O	61	amod
airframe	NN	O	58	conj
manufactures	NNS	O	55	ccomp
-LRB-	VBP	O	64	punct
Boeing	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	55	dep
and	CC	O	64	cc
Airbus	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	64	conj
-RRB-	NNP	O	64	punct
have	VBP	O	69	aux
recommended	VBN	O	55	dep
that	IN	O	72	mark
operators	NNS	O	72	nsubj
perform	VBP	O	69	ccomp
risk	NN	O	74	compound
assessments	NNS	O	72	dobj
to	TO	O	76	mark
establish	VB	O	72	advcl
whether	IN	O	76	dobj
and	CC	O	77	cc
how	WRB	O	82	advmod
they	PRP	O	82	nsubj
can	MD	O	82	aux
manage	VB	O	77	conj
the	DT	O	84	det
risks	NNS	O	82	dobj
associated	VBN	O	84	acl
with	IN	O	88	case
the	DT	O	88	det
transportation	NN	O	85	nmod
of	IN	O	91	case
these	DT	O	91	det
items	NNS	O	88	nmod
.	.	O	4	punct

These	DT	O	0	ROOT
recommendations	NNS	O	2	det
only	RB	O	4	nsubj
go	VBP	O	4	advmod
so	RB	O	6	advmod
far	RB	O	4	advmod
,	,	O	4	punct
but	CC	O	4	cc
regulations	NNS	O	11	nsubj
are	VBP	O	11	aux
becoming	VBG	O	4	conj
much	RB	O	13	advmod
more	RBR	O	14	advmod
stringent	JJ	O	11	xcomp
.	.	O	4	punct

February	NNP	B-DATE	0	ROOT
22nd	CD	I-DATE	4	nsubj
2016	CD	I-DATE	3	amod
saw	VBD	O	1	nummod
the	DT	O	6	det
ICAO	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	7	nsubj
pass	NN	O	4	ccomp
a	DT	O	9	det
prohibition	NN	O	7	dobj
on	IN	O	12	case
the	DT	O	12	det
carrying	NN	O	9	nmod
of	IN	O	17	case
UN3480	NNP	O	17	compound
lithium	NN	O	17	compound
ion	NN	O	17	compound
batteries	NNS	O	12	nmod
as	IN	O	19	case
cargo	NN	O	7	nmod
on	IN	O	22	case
passenger	NN	O	22	compound
aircraft	NN	O	19	nmod
,	,	O	22	punct
which	WDT	O	25	nsubj
came	VBD	O	22	acl:relcl
into	IN	O	27	case
effect	NN	O	25	nmod
on	IN	O	30	case
1st	CD	B-DATE	30	amod
April	NNP	I-DATE	25	nmod
2016	CD	I-DATE	30	nummod
.	.	O	4	punct

As	RB	O	0	ROOT
well	RB	O	4	mark
as	IN	O	1	mwe
detailing	VBG	O	1	mwe
this	DT	O	6	det
requirement	NN	O	4	dobj
,	,	O	4	punct
ICAO	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	11	compound
`	``	O	11	punct
Technical	JJ	O	11	compound
Instructions	NNS	O	7	root
for	IN	O	15	case
the	DT	O	15	det
Safe	NNP	O	15	compound
Transport	NNP	O	11	nmod
of	IN	O	18	case
Dangerous	NNP	O	18	compound
Goods	NNP	O	15	nmod
by	IN	O	29	mark
Air	NNP	O	29	nsubj
'	POS	O	20	case
2015	CD	B-DATE	23	compound
16	CD	I-DATE	20	dep
-LRB-	CD	O	25	punct
Document	NN	O	23	appos
9284	CD	B-NUMBER	25	nummod
-RRB-	NN	O	25	punct
also	RB	O	29	advmod
stipulates	VBZ	O	11	acl:relcl
that	IN	O	38	mark
lithium	NN	O	33	compound
ion	NN	O	33	compound
cells	NNS	O	38	nsubjpass
and	CC	O	33	cc
batteries	NNS	O	33	conj
must	MD	O	38	aux
be	VB	O	38	auxpass
offered	VBN	O	29	ccomp
for	IN	O	40	case
transport	NN	O	38	nmod
as	IN	O	43	case
a	DT	O	43	det
state	NN	O	38	nmod
of	IN	O	45	case
charge	NN	O	43	nmod
-LRB-	NNP	O	47	punct
SoC	NNP	O	43	appos
-RRB-	NNP	O	47	punct
of	IN	O	54	case
no	DT	O	53	advmod
more	JJR	O	53	advmod
than	IN	O	51	mwe
30	CD	B-PERCENT	54	nummod
%	NN	I-PERCENT	43	nmod
of	IN	O	59	case
their	PRP$	O	59	nmod:poss
rated	VBN	O	59	amod
design	NN	O	59	compound
capacity	NN	O	54	nmod
,	,	O	38	punct
with	IN	O	62	case
details	NNS	O	38	nmod
relating	VBG	O	62	acl
to	TO	O	66	mark
what	WP	O	66	nsubj
constitutes	VBZ	O	63	advcl
acceptable	JJ	O	68	amod
packaging	NN	O	66	dobj
and	CC	O	68	cc
labelling	NN	O	68	conj
.	.	O	11	punct

While	IN	O	0	ROOT
the	DT	O	13	mark
carrying	NN	O	3	det
of	IN	O	13	nsubj
primary	JJ	O	6	case
lithium	NN	O	6	amod
and	CC	O	3	nmod
lithium	NN	O	6	cc
ion	NN	O	10	compound
batteries	NNS	O	10	compound
may	MD	O	6	conj
be	VB	O	13	aux
subject	JJ	O	13	cop
to	TO	O	25	advcl
increased	VBN	O	16	case
restriction	NN	O	16	amod
,	,	O	13	nmod
however	RB	O	25	punct
,	,	O	25	advmod
no	DT	O	25	punct
such	JJ	O	22	neg
limits	NNS	O	22	amod
have	VBP	O	25	nsubjpass
been	VBN	O	25	aux
placed	VBN	O	25	auxpass
on	IN	O	28	case
the	DT	O	28	det
transport	NN	O	25	nmod
of	IN	O	31	case
these	DT	O	31	det
products	NNS	O	28	nmod
within	IN	O	36	case
the	DT	O	36	det
main	JJ	O	36	amod
aircraft	NN	O	36	compound
cabin	NN	O	25	nmod
.	.	O	25	punct

Even	RB	O	0	ROOT
so	RB	O	2	advmod
,	,	O	7	advmod
airlines	NNS	O	7	punct
themselves	PRP	O	7	nsubj
have	VBP	O	4	nmod:npmod
recognised	VBN	O	7	aux
a	DT	O	9	det
need	NN	O	7	dobj
to	TO	O	11	mark
tackle	VB	O	9	acl
this	DT	O	13	det
issue	NN	O	11	dobj
.	.	O	7	punct

The	DT	O	0	ROOT
solution	NN	O	2	det
Recognising	VBG	O	26	ccomp
the	DT	O	2	acl
problems	NNS	O	5	det
associated	VBN	O	3	dobj
with	IN	O	5	acl
overheating	VBG	O	9	case
batteries	NNS	O	9	amod
and	CC	O	6	nmod
the	DT	O	9	cc
need	NN	O	12	det
to	TO	O	9	conj
minimise	VB	O	14	mark
fire	NN	B-CAUSE_OF_DEATH	12	acl
risk	NN	O	16	compound
and	CC	O	14	dobj
provide	VB	O	14	cc
insulation	NN	O	14	conj
to	TO	O	18	dobj
contain	VB	O	21	mark
heat	NN	O	18	advcl
spread	NN	O	23	compound
,	,	O	21	dobj
Morgan	NNP	B-PERSON	26	punct
set	VBD	O	26	nsubj
out	RP	O	26	compound:prt
to	TO	O	29	mark
harness	VB	O	26	xcomp
the	DT	O	31	det
capabilities	NNS	O	29	dobj
of	IN	O	35	case
its	PRP$	O	35	nmod:poss
extensive	JJ	O	35	amod
range	NN	O	31	nmod
of	IN	O	39	case
state-of-the-art	JJ	O	39	amod
insulation	NN	O	39	compound
technologies	NNS	O	35	nmod
to	TO	O	41	mark
develop	VB	O	29	advcl
a	DT	O	43	det
solution	NN	O	41	dobj
.	.	O	26	punct

Morgan	NNP	B-PERSON	0	ROOT
's	POS	O	3	nmod:poss
expertise	NN	O	1	case
in	IN	O	19	nsubjpass
the	DT	O	6	case
area	NN	O	6	det
of	IN	O	3	nmod
high-performance	NN	O	9	case
insulation	NN	O	9	amod
to	TO	O	6	nmod
prevent	VB	O	11	mark
the	DT	O	3	acl
spread	NN	O	13	det
of	IN	O	11	dobj
thermal	JJ	O	16	case
energy	NN	O	16	amod
is	VBZ	O	13	nmod
globally	RB	O	19	auxpass
renowned	VBN	O	19	advmod
,	,	O	19	punct
not	RB	O	22	neg
least	JJS	O	25	cc:preconj
in	IN	O	25	case
the	DT	O	25	det
supply	NN	O	19	nmod
of	IN	O	27	case
materials	NNS	O	25	nmod
used	VBN	O	27	acl
to	TO	O	30	mark
encapsulate	VB	O	28	xcomp
flight	NN	O	34	compound
data	NNS	O	34	compound
recorder	NN	B-TITLE	34	compound
FDR	NNP	O	30	dobj
and	CC	O	34	cc
cockpit	JJ	O	38	compound
voice	NN	O	38	compound
recorder	NN	B-TITLE	34	conj
-LRB-	NNP	O	40	punct
CVR	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	38	appos
-RRB-	NNP	O	40	punct
products	NNS	O	34	dep
,	,	O	25	punct
and	CC	O	25	cc
perhaps	RB	O	47	advmod
even	RB	O	47	advmod
more	RBR	O	48	advmod
so	RB	O	25	conj
in	IN	O	54	case
the	DT	O	54	det
Oil	NNP	O	54	compound
&	CC	O	51	cc
Gas	NNP	O	51	conj
sector	NN	O	48	nmod
where	WRB	O	61	advmod
its	PRP$	O	60	nmod:poss
FireMaster	NNP	O	60	compound
Marine	NNP	B-TITLE	60	compound
Plus	NNP	O	60	compound
Blanket	NNP	O	61	nsubj
used	VBD	O	54	acl:relcl
to	TO	O	63	mark
surround	VB	O	61	xcomp
the	DT	O	66	det
living	NN	O	66	compound
quarters	NNS	O	63	dobj
in	IN	O	70	case
offshore	JJ	O	70	amod
extraction	NN	O	70	compound
facilities	NNS	O	63	nmod
,	,	O	25	punct
protecting	VBG	O	25	acl
the	DT	O	74	det
structure	NN	O	72	dobj
to	TO	O	76	mark
allow	VB	O	72	advcl
sufficient	JJ	O	78	amod
time	NN	O	76	dobj
for	IN	O	80	case
those	DT	O	78	nmod
working	VBG	O	80	acl
on	IN	O	84	case
the	DT	O	84	det
rig	NN	O	81	nmod
to	TO	O	86	mark
escape	VB	O	81	xcomp
in	IN	O	88	case
case	NN	O	86	nmod
of	IN	O	92	case
a	DT	O	92	det
fire	NN	B-CAUSE_OF_DEATH	92	compound
outbreak	NN	O	88	nmod
.	.	O	19	punct

Various	JJ	O	0	ROOT
configurations	NNS	O	2	amod
and	CC	O	11	nsubjpass
combinations	NNS	O	2	cc
of	IN	O	2	conj
Morgan	NNP	B-PERSON	9	case
's	POS	O	9	nmod:poss
material	NN	O	6	case
range	NN	O	9	compound
were	VBD	O	2	nmod
examined	VBN	O	11	auxpass
and	CC	O	11	cc
considered	VBN	O	11	conj
to	TO	O	15	mark
contain	VB	O	13	xcomp
heat	NN	O	15	dobj
and	CC	O	16	cc
fire	NN	B-CAUSE_OF_DEATH	16	conj
,	,	O	11	punct
minimise	VB	O	11	conj
further	JJ	O	23	amod
fire	NN	B-CAUSE_OF_DEATH	23	compound
risk	NN	O	20	dobj
and	CC	O	11	cc
counter	VBP	O	11	conj
the	DT	O	27	det
issue	NN	O	25	dobj
of	IN	O	30	case
heat	NN	O	30	compound
transfer	NN	O	27	nmod
.	.	O	11	punct

The	DT	O	0	ROOT
ideal	NN	O	4	det
bag	NN	O	4	amod
solution	NN	O	4	compound
uses	VBZ	O	5	nsubj
at	IN	O	8	case
its	PRP$	O	8	nmod:poss
core	NN	O	5	nmod
the	DT	O	11	det
same	JJ	O	11	amod
product	NN	O	5	dobj
-	:	O	11	punct
FireMaster	NNP	O	16	compound
Marine	NNP	B-TITLE	16	compound
Plus	NNP	O	16	compound
blanket	NN	O	11	dep
,	,	O	11	punct
which	WDT	O	21	nsubjpass
is	VBZ	O	21	auxpass
typically	RB	O	21	advmod
used	VBN	O	11	acl:relcl
to	TO	O	23	mark
protect	VB	O	21	xcomp
FRP	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	30	compound
composite	JJ	O	30	amod
,	,	O	25	punct
steel	NN	O	25	conj
and	CC	O	25	cc
aluminium	NN	O	25	conj
structures	NNS	O	23	dobj
for	IN	O	33	case
extended	VBN	O	33	amod
periods	NNS	O	23	nmod
.	.	O	5	punct

The	DT	O	0	ROOT
outer	NN	O	3	det
layer	NN	B-TITLE	3	amod
comprises	VBZ	O	4	nsubj
a	DT	O	8	det
silicone-coated	JJ	O	8	amod
glass	NN	O	8	compound
cloth	NN	O	4	dobj
and	CC	O	8	cc
hook-and-loop	JJ	O	12	amod
tape	NN	O	12	compound
fastener	NN	O	8	conj
to	TO	O	14	mark
secure	VB	O	4	advcl
the	DT	O	16	det
bag	NN	O	14	dobj
once	IN	B-DATE	22	mark
the	DT	O	19	det
contents	NNS	O	22	nsubjpass
had	VBD	O	22	aux
been	VBN	O	22	auxpass
placed	VBN	O	14	advcl
inside	IN	O	22	advmod
.	.	O	4	punct

The	DT	O	0	ROOT
materials	NNS	O	2	det
have	VBP	O	5	nsubjpass
been	VBN	O	5	aux
chosen	VBN	O	5	auxpass
to	TO	O	7	mark
maintain	VB	O	5	xcomp
their	PRP$	O	9	nmod:poss
integrity	NN	O	7	dobj
even	RB	O	11	advmod
when	WRB	O	13	advmod
they	PRP	O	13	nsubj
come	VBP	O	7	advcl
into	IN	O	15	case
contact	NN	O	13	nmod
with	IN	O	17	case
water	NN	O	15	nmod
,	,	O	13	punct
which	WDT	O	22	nsubjpass
can	MD	O	22	aux
be	VB	O	22	auxpass
added	VBN	O	13	dep
immediately	RB	O	22	advmod
to	TO	O	25	mark
help	VB	O	22	xcomp
cool	VB	O	25	ccomp
down	RP	O	26	compound:prt
the	DT	O	30	det
overheated	JJ	O	30	amod
battery	NN	B-CRIMINAL_CHARGE	26	dobj
.	.	O	5	punct

The	DT	O	0	ROOT
dimensions	NNS	O	2	det
of	IN	O	8	nsubj
the	DT	O	5	case
bags	NNS	O	5	det
are	VBP	O	2	nmod
500	CD	B-NUMBER	8	cop
mm	JJ	O	8	nummod
x	$	O	8	cc
500	CD	B-NUMBER	11	nummod
mm	NN	O	8	conj
and	CC	O	8	cc
are	VBP	O	14	auxpass
bound	VBN	O	8	conj
with	IN	O	18	case
a	DT	O	18	det
high-temperature	NN	O	18	amod
yarn	NN	O	14	nmod
which	WDT	O	22	nsubjpass
is	VBZ	O	22	auxpass
typically	RB	O	22	advmod
used	VBN	O	18	acl:relcl
in	IN	O	26	case
heat	NN	O	26	compound
protection	NN	O	26	compound
clothing	NN	O	22	nmod
and	CC	O	26	cc
welding	JJ	O	29	compound
equipment	NN	O	26	conj
.	.	O	8	punct

The	DT	O	0	ROOT
bags	NNS	O	2	det
have	VBP	O	6	nsubjpass
been	VBN	O	6	aux
extensively	RB	O	6	auxpass
tested	VBN	O	6	advmod
together	RB	O	6	advmod
with	IN	O	9	case
Germanwings	NNP	O	6	nmod
,	,	O	9	punct
which	WDT	O	13	nsubj
is	VBZ	O	13	cop
part	NN	O	9	acl:relcl
of	IN	O	17	case
the	DT	O	17	det
Lufthansa	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	17	compound
group	NN	O	13	nmod
.	.	O	6	punct

Lighter	JJR	O	0	ROOT
planes	NNS	O	2	amod
are	VBP	O	8	nsubj
the	DT	B-DATE	8	cop
future	NN	I-DATE	8	det
A	NNP	O	8	compound
global	JJ	O	8	compound
fleet	NN	O	8	amod
of	IN	O	11	case
composite	JJ	O	11	amod
planes	NNS	O	8	nmod
could	MD	O	13	aux
reduce	VB	O	8	dep
carbon	NN	O	15	compound
emissions	NNS	O	13	dobj
by	IN	O	19	case
up	IN	O	19	dep
to	TO	O	17	mwe
15	CD	B-NUMBER	13	nmod
per	IN	O	21	case
cent	NN	O	19	nmod
,	,	O	13	punct
but	CC	O	13	cc
the	DT	O	26	det
lighter	JJR	O	26	amod
planes	NNS	O	30	nsubj
alone	RB	O	26	advmod
will	MD	O	30	aux
not	RB	O	30	neg
enable	VB	O	13	conj
the	DT	O	33	det
aviation	NN	O	33	compound
industry	NN	O	30	dobj
to	TO	O	35	mark
meet	VB	O	30	xcomp
its	PRP$	O	38	nmod:poss
emissions	NNS	O	38	compound
targets	NNS	O	35	dobj
,	,	O	8	punct
according	VBG	O	43	case
to	TO	O	40	mwe
new	JJ	O	43	amod
research	NN	O	8	nmod
.	.	O	8	punct

The	DT	O	0	ROOT
study	NN	O	2	det
,	,	O	21	nsubj
by	IN	O	2	punct
the	DT	O	6	case
Universities	NNS	B-ORGANIZATION	6	det
of	IN	I-ORGANIZATION	2	nmod
Sheffield	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	8	case
,	,	O	6	nmod
Cambridge	NNP	B-CITY	8	punct
and	CC	O	8	conj
UCL	NNP	O	8	cc
-LRB-	NNP	O	16	compound
University	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	16	punct
College	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	16	compound
London	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	16	compound
-RRB-	NNP	O	8	conj
,	,	O	16	punct
is	VBZ	O	2	punct
the	DT	O	21	cop
first	JJ	B-ORDINAL	21	det
to	TO	O	23	mark
carry	VB	O	21	acl
out	RP	O	23	compound:prt
a	DT	O	29	det
comprehensive	JJ	O	29	amod
life	NN	O	29	compound
cycle	NN	O	29	compound
assessment	NN	O	23	dobj
-LRB-	NNP	O	31	punct
LCA	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	29	appos
-RRB-	NNP	O	31	punct
of	IN	O	36	case
a	DT	O	36	det
composite	JJ	O	36	amod
plane	NN	O	29	nmod
,	,	O	29	punct
such	JJ	O	42	case
as	IN	O	38	mwe
the	DT	O	42	det
Boeing	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	42	compound
Dreamliner	NNP	O	29	nmod
787	CD	B-NUMBER	42	nummod
or	CC	O	42	cc
Airbus	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	42	conj
350	CD	B-NUMBER	45	nummod
,	,	O	21	punct
and	CC	O	21	cc
extrapolate	VB	O	21	conj
the	DT	O	51	det
results	NNS	O	49	dobj
to	TO	O	55	case
the	DT	O	55	det
global	JJ	O	55	amod
fleet	NN	O	49	nmod
.	.	O	21	punct

The	DT	O	0	ROOT
LCA	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	2	det
covers	VBZ	O	3	nsubj
manufacture	NN	O	3	dobj
,	,	O	4	punct
use	NN	O	4	conj
and	CC	O	4	cc
disposal	NN	O	4	conj
,	,	O	3	punct
using	VBG	O	3	advcl
publicly	RB	O	12	advmod
available	JJ	O	13	amod
information	NN	O	10	dobj
on	IN	O	19	case
the	DT	O	19	det
Boeing	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	19	compound
Dreamliner	NNP	O	19	compound
787	CD	B-NUMBER	19	nummod
fuselage	NN	O	13	nmod
and	CC	O	19	cc
from	IN	O	24	case
the	DT	O	24	det
supply	NN	O	24	compound
chain	NN	O	19	conj
-	:	O	13	punct
such	JJ	O	30	case
as	IN	O	26	mwe
the	DT	O	30	det
energy	NN	O	30	compound
usage	NN	O	13	nmod
of	IN	O	33	case
the	DT	O	33	det
robots	NNS	O	30	nmod
that	WDT	O	35	nsubj
construct	VBP	O	33	acl:relcl
the	DT	O	37	det
planes	NNS	O	35	dobj
.	.	O	3	punct

The	DT	O	0	ROOT
study	NN	O	2	det
compares	VBZ	O	3	nsubj
the	DT	O	5	det
results	NNS	O	3	dobj
to	TO	O	14	case
the	DT	O	14	det
traditional	JJ	O	14	amod
-	:	O	8	punct
and	CC	O	8	cc
heavier	JJR	O	8	conj
-	:	O	8	punct
aluminium	NN	O	14	compound
planes	NNS	O	3	nmod
.	.	O	3	punct

Emissions	NNS	O	0	ROOT
during	IN	O	11	nsubj
the	DT	O	4	case
manufacture	NN	O	4	det
of	IN	O	1	nmod
composite	JJ	O	7	case
planes	NNS	O	7	amod
are	VBP	O	4	nmod
over	IN	O	11	cop
double	JJ	O	11	case
those	DT	O	11	amod
of	IN	O	14	case
aluminium	JJ	O	14	compound
planes	NNS	O	11	nmod
.	.	O	11	punct

But	CC	O	0	ROOT
because	IN	O	15	cc
the	DT	O	9	mark
lighter	NN	O	6	det
aircraft	NN	O	6	amod
use	NN	O	6	compound
significantly	RB	O	9	nsubj
less	RBR	O	8	advmod
fuel	JJ	O	9	amod
,	,	O	15	advcl
these	DT	O	15	punct
increased	VBN	O	13	det
emissions	NNS	O	13	amod
are	VBP	O	15	nsubjpass
offset	VBN	O	15	auxpass
after	IN	O	21	case
just	RB	O	21	advmod
a	DT	O	21	det
few	JJ	O	21	amod
international	JJ	O	21	amod
flights	NNS	O	15	nmod
.	.	O	15	punct

Over	IN	O	0	ROOT
its	PRP$	O	3	case
lifetime	NN	O	3	nmod:poss
,	,	O	8	nmod
a	DT	O	8	punct
composite	JJ	O	7	det
plane	NN	O	7	amod
creates	VBZ	O	8	nsubj
up	IN	O	11	dep
to	TO	O	11	dep
20	CD	B-NUMBER	8	advmod
per	IN	O	16	case
cent	NN	O	16	compound
fewer	NN	O	16	amod
CO2	NNP	O	16	compound
emissions	NNS	O	11	nmod
than	IN	O	20	case
its	PRP$	O	20	nmod:poss
aluminium	JJ	O	20	compound
equivalent	NN	O	11	nmod
.	.	O	8	punct

Professor	NNP	B-TITLE	0	ROOT
in	IN	O	15	nsubj
Advanced	NNP	O	5	case
Materials	NNP	O	5	compound
Technologies	NNPS	O	5	compound
at	IN	O	1	nmod
the	DT	O	8	case
University	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	8	det
of	IN	I-ORGANIZATION	1	nmod
Sheffield	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	10	case
,	,	O	8	nmod
Alma	NNP	B-PERSON	1	punct
Hodzic	NNP	I-PERSON	13	compound
,	,	O	1	appos
says	VBZ	O	1	punct
:	:	O	15	punct
``	``	O	15	punct
This	DT	O	19	det
study	NN	O	20	nsubj
shows	VBZ	O	15	ccomp
that	IN	O	29	mark
the	DT	O	25	det
fuel	NN	O	25	compound
consumption	NN	O	25	compound
savings	NNS	O	29	nsubj
with	IN	O	27	case
composites	NNS	O	25	nmod
far	RB	O	29	advmod
outweigh	VBP	O	20	ccomp
the	DT	O	33	det
increased	JJ	O	33	amod
environmental	JJ	O	33	amod
impact	NN	O	29	dobj
from	IN	O	36	case
their	PRP$	O	36	nmod:poss
manufacture	NN	O	33	nmod
.	.	O	15	punct

Despite	IN	O	0	ROOT
ongoing	VBG	O	3	case
debates	NNS	O	3	amod
within	IN	O	15	nmod
the	DT	O	6	case
industry	NN	O	6	det
,	,	O	3	nmod
the	DT	O	15	punct
environmental	JJ	O	12	det
and	CC	O	12	amod
financial	JJ	O	9	cc
savings	NNS	O	9	conj
from	IN	O	15	nsubj
composites	NNS	O	14	case
mean	VBP	O	12	nmod
that	IN	O	19	mark
these	DT	O	18	det
materials	NNS	O	19	nsubj
offer	VBP	O	15	ccomp
a	DT	O	23	det
much	RB	O	22	advmod
better	JJR	O	23	amod
solution	NN	O	19	dobj
.	.	O	15	punct
''	''	O	15	punct

The	DT	O	0	ROOT
researchers	NNS	O	2	det
fed	VBP	O	3	nsubj
the	DT	O	5	det
data	NN	O	3	dobj
from	IN	O	8	case
the	DT	O	8	det
LCA	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	5	nmod
into	IN	O	13	case
a	DT	O	13	det
wider	NN	O	13	amod
transport	NN	O	13	compound
model	NN	B-TITLE	3	nmod
to	TO	O	15	mark
gauge	VB	O	13	acl
the	DT	O	17	det
impact	NN	O	15	dobj
on	IN	O	20	case
CO2	NNP	O	20	compound
emissions	NNS	O	17	nmod
as	IN	O	25	mark
composite	JJ	O	23	amod
planes	NNS	O	25	nsubjpass
are	VBP	O	25	auxpass
introduced	VBN	O	15	advcl
into	IN	O	29	case
the	DT	O	29	det
global	JJ	O	29	amod
fleet	NN	O	25	nmod
over	IN	O	34	case
the	DT	B-DURATION	34	det
next	JJ	B-DATE	34	amod
25	CD	I-DATE	34	nummod
years	NNS	I-DATE	25	nmod
,	,	O	15	punct
taking	VBG	O	15	xcomp
into	IN	O	40	case
account	NN	O	40	compound
other	JJ	O	40	amod
factors	NNS	O	36	nmod
including	VBG	O	42	case
population	NN	O	40	nmod
,	,	O	42	punct
economic	JJ	O	45	amod
prosperity	NN	O	42	conj
,	,	O	42	punct
oil	NN	O	48	compound
prices	NNS	O	42	conj
and	CC	O	42	cc
speed	NN	O	42	conj
of	IN	O	52	case
adoption	NN	O	50	nmod
of	IN	O	56	case
the	DT	O	56	det
new	JJ	O	56	amod
technology	NN	O	52	nmod
.	.	O	3	punct

The	DT	O	0	ROOT
study	NN	O	2	det
-	:	O	14	nsubj
published	VBN	O	2	punct
in	IN	O	2	acl
the	DT	O	8	case
International	NNP	O	8	det
Journal	NNP	O	8	compound
of	IN	O	4	nmod
Life	NNP	O	12	case
Cycle	NNP	O	12	compound
Assessment	NNP	O	12	compound
-	:	O	8	nmod
estimated	VBN	O	2	punct
that	IN	O	22	mark
by	IN	O	17	case
2050	CD	B-DATE	22	nmod
,	,	O	22	punct
composite	JJ	O	20	amod
planes	NNS	O	22	nsubj
could	MD	O	22	aux
reduce	VB	O	14	ccomp
emissions	NNS	O	22	dobj
from	IN	O	27	case
the	DT	O	27	det
global	JJ	O	27	amod
fleet	NN	O	22	nmod
by	IN	O	29	case
14-15	JJ	B-DATE	22	nmod
per	IN	O	31	case
cent	NN	O	29	nmod
relative	NN	O	29	amod
to	TO	O	35	case
a	DT	O	35	det
fleet	NN	O	32	nmod
that	WDT	O	37	nsubj
maintains	VBZ	O	35	acl:relcl
its	PRP$	O	41	nmod:poss
existing	VBG	O	41	amod
aluminium-based	JJ	O	41	amod
configuration	NN	O	37	dobj
.	.	O	14	punct

Professor	NNP	B-TITLE	0	ROOT
in	IN	O	12	nsubj
Energy	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	3	case
and	CC	I-ORGANIZATION	1	nmod
Transport	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	3	cc
at	IN	O	3	conj
UCL	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	7	case
,	,	O	1	nmod
Andreas	NNP	B-PERSON	1	punct
Schafer	NNP	I-PERSON	10	compound
,	,	O	1	appos
explains	VBZ	O	1	punct
:	:	O	12	punct
``	``	O	12	punct
The	DT	O	18	det
overall	JJ	O	18	amod
emissions	NNS	O	18	compound
reduction	NN	O	24	nsubj
for	IN	O	22	case
the	DT	O	22	det
global	JJ	O	22	amod
fleet	NN	O	18	nmod
is	VBZ	O	24	cop
lower	JJR	O	12	ccomp
than	IN	O	27	case
the	DT	O	27	det
reduction	NN	O	24	nmod
for	IN	O	31	case
an	DT	O	31	det
individual	JJ	O	31	amod
plane	NN	O	27	nmod
,	,	O	24	punct
partly	RB	O	24	advmod
,	,	O	24	punct
because	IN	O	47	mark
by	IN	O	37	case
2050	CD	B-DATE	47	nmod
,	,	O	47	punct
not	RB	O	42	neg
all	PDT	O	42	det:predet
the	DT	O	42	det
fleet	NN	O	47	nsubj
will	MD	O	47	aux
be	VB	O	47	cop
of	IN	O	47	case
composite	JJ	O	47	amod
construction	NN	O	24	advcl
.	.	O	12	punct

New	NNP	O	0	ROOT
planes	NNS	O	2	compound
entering	VBG	O	2	acl
the	DT	O	5	det
fleet	NN	O	3	dobj
before	IN	O	12	mark
2020	CD	B-DATE	12	nsubj
could	MD	O	12	aux
still	RB	O	12	advmod
be	VB	O	12	cop
in	IN	O	12	case
use	NN	O	3	advcl
by	IN	O	14	case
2050	CD	B-DATE	12	nmod
,	,	O	2	punct
but	CC	O	2	cc
the	DT	O	20	det
faster	JJR	O	20	advmod
the	DT	O	20	det
uptake	NN	O	2	conj
of	IN	O	23	case
this	DT	O	23	det
technology	NN	O	20	nmod
,	,	O	20	punct
the	DT	O	26	det
greater	JJR	O	20	appos
the	DT	O	29	det
environmental	JJ	O	29	amod
benefits	NNS	O	31	nsubj
will	MD	O	31	aux
be	VB	O	26	ccomp
.	.	O	2	punct
''	''	O	2	punct

Dr	NNP	O	0	ROOT
Lynette	NNP	B-PERSON	3	compound
Dray	NNP	I-PERSON	3	compound
from	IN	O	10	nsubj
Cambridge	NNP	B-CITY	7	case
's	POS	O	7	nmod:poss
Department	NNP	O	5	case
of	IN	O	3	nmod
Architecture	NNP	O	9	case
agrees	VBZ	O	7	nmod
:	:	O	10	punct
``	``	O	10	punct
Given	VBN	O	10	dep
that	IN	O	19	mark
global	JJ	O	17	amod
air	NN	O	17	compound
traffic	NN	O	19	nsubjpass
is	VBZ	O	19	auxpass
projected	VBN	O	13	ccomp
to	TO	O	21	mark
increase	VB	O	19	xcomp
four-fold	JJ	O	21	advmod
between	IN	O	24	case
now	RB	B-DATE	21	nmod
and	CC	I-DATE	24	cc
2050	CD	I-DATE	24	conj
,	,	O	13	punct
changing	VBG	O	33	csubj
the	DT	O	30	det
materials	NNS	O	28	dobj
used	VBN	O	30	acl
could	MD	O	33	aux
avoid	VB	O	13	conj
500	CD	B-NUMBER	35	compound
million	CD	I-NUMBER	36	nummod
tonnes	NNS	O	33	dobj
of	IN	O	39	case
CO2	NNP	O	39	compound
emissions	NNS	O	36	nmod
in	IN	O	41	case
2050	CD	B-DATE	33	nmod
alone	RB	O	41	advmod
,	,	O	13	punct
a	DT	O	45	det
value	NN	O	13	conj
that	WDT	O	48	nsubj
roughly	RB	O	48	advmod
corresponds	VBZ	O	45	acl:relcl
to	TO	O	52	case
current	JJ	B-DATE	52	amod
emission	NN	O	52	compound
levels	NNS	O	48	nmod
.	.	O	10	punct
''	''	O	10	punct

Professor	NNP	B-TITLE	0	ROOT
Hodzic	NNP	B-PERSON	2	compound
adds	VBZ	O	3	nsubj
:	:	O	3	punct
``	``	O	3	punct
The	DT	O	8	det
industry	NN	O	8	compound
target	NN	O	9	nsubj
is	VBZ	O	31	ccomp
to	TO	O	11	mark
halve	VB	O	9	xcomp
CO2	NNP	O	13	compound
emissions	NNS	O	11	dobj
for	IN	O	16	case
all	DT	O	16	det
aircraft	NN	O	11	nmod
by	IN	O	18	case
2020	CD	B-DATE	11	nmod
and	CC	O	11	cc
while	IN	O	23	mark
composites	NNS	O	23	nsubj
will	MD	O	23	aux
contribute	VB	O	11	conj
to	TO	O	25	case
this	DT	O	23	nmod
,	,	O	31	punct
it	PRP	O	31	nsubjpass
can	MD	O	31	aux
not	RB	O	31	neg
be	VB	O	31	auxpass
achieved	VBN	O	3	ccomp
by	IN	O	34	case
the	DT	O	34	det
introduction	NN	O	31	nmod
of	IN	O	38	case
lighter	JJR	O	38	amod
composite	JJ	O	38	amod
planes	NNS	O	34	nmod
alone	RB	O	38	advmod
.	.	O	3	punct

However	RB	O	0	ROOT
,	,	O	5	advmod
our	PRP$	O	5	punct
findings	NNS	O	4	nmod:poss
show	VBP	O	5	nsubj
that	IN	O	18	mark
composites	VBZ	O	18	nsubj
-	:	O	7	punct
alongside	IN	O	11	case
other	JJ	O	11	amod
technology	NN	O	7	nmod
and	CC	O	11	cc
efficiency	NN	O	14	compound
measures	NNS	O	11	conj
-	:	O	7	punct
should	MD	O	18	aux
be	VB	O	18	cop
part	NN	O	5	ccomp
of	IN	O	21	case
the	DT	O	21	det
picture	NN	O	18	nmod
.	.	O	5	punct
''	''	O	5	punct
.	.	O	0	ROOT

Iris	NNP	B-PERSON	0	ROOT
for	IN	O	12	nsubj
safer	JJR	O	5	case
air	NN	O	5	amod
travel	IN	O	5	compound
9	CD	B-DATE	1	nmod
May	NNP	I-DATE	10	nummod
2014	CD	I-DATE	10	compound
Aviation	NNP	O	10	nummod
accidents	NNS	B-CAUSE_OF_DEATH	10	compound
sometimes	RB	O	5	dep
highlight	VBD	O	12	advmod
how	WRB	O	14	advmod
much	JJ	O	17	advmod
we	PRP	O	17	nsubj
still	RB	O	17	advmod
rely	VBP	O	12	ccomp
on	IN	O	21	case
old-fashioned	JJ	O	21	amod
radio	NN	O	21	compound
contact	NN	O	17	nmod
by	IN	O	23	case
pilots	NNS	O	21	nmod
and	CC	O	23	cc
vulnerable	JJ	O	27	amod
tracking	VBG	O	27	compound
systems	NNS	O	23	conj
.	.	O	12	punct

But	CC	O	0	ROOT
satellites	NNS	O	4	cc
are	VBP	O	4	nsubjpass
set	VBN	O	4	auxpass
to	TO	O	6	mark
change	VB	O	4	xcomp
sky	JJ	O	8	compound
safety	NN	O	6	dobj
,	,	O	4	punct
thanks	NNS	O	4	nmod:npmod
to	TO	O	13	case
international	JJ	O	13	amod
collaboration	NN	O	10	nmod
.	.	O	4	punct

ESA	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	0	ROOT
's	POS	O	4	nmod:poss
Iris	NNP	O	1	case
programme	NN	O	4	compound
is	VBZ	O	6	nsubj
looking	VBG	O	6	aux
to	TO	O	8	case
satellites	NNS	O	6	nmod
to	TO	O	10	mark
make	VB	O	6	xcomp
aviation	NN	O	12	nsubj
safer	NN	O	10	xcomp
through	IN	O	15	case
modern	JJ	O	15	amod
communications	NNS	O	12	nmod
.	.	O	6	punct

Worldwide	NNP	O	0	ROOT
digital	JJ	O	4	compound
data	NNS	O	4	amod
links	NNS	O	4	compound
via	IN	O	14	nsubj
satellite	NN	O	6	case
,	,	O	4	nmod
offering	VBG	O	4	punct
much	JJ	O	4	acl
higher	JJR	O	10	advmod
capacity	NN	O	11	amod
,	,	O	8	dobj
will	MD	O	4	punct
become	VB	O	14	aux
the	DT	O	16	det
standard	NN	O	14	xcomp
for	IN	O	19	case
cockpit	NN	O	19	compound
crews	NNS	O	16	nmod
,	,	O	14	punct
with	IN	O	23	case
voice	NN	O	23	compound
communications	NNS	O	14	nmod
kept	VBD	O	23	acl
as	IN	O	26	case
backup	NN	O	24	nmod
.	.	O	14	punct

Iris	NNP	B-PERSON	0	ROOT
is	VBZ	O	3	nsubj
part	NN	O	3	cop
of	IN	O	8	case
a	DT	O	8	det
much	JJ	O	7	advmod
broader	JJR	O	8	amod
push	NN	O	3	nmod
to	TO	O	10	mark
modernise	VB	O	8	acl
how	WRB	O	15	advmod
air	NN	O	13	compound
traffic	NN	O	15	nsubjpass
is	VBZ	O	15	auxpass
managed	VBN	O	10	ccomp
in	IN	O	17	case
collaboration	NN	O	15	nmod
with	IN	O	23	case
the	DT	O	23	det
Single	NNP	B-MISC	23	amod
European	NNP	B-NATIONALITY	23	amod
Sky	NNP	B-MISC	23	compound
effort	NN	O	17	nmod
of	IN	O	27	case
the	DT	O	27	det
European	JJ	B-ORGANIZATION	27	amod
Commission	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	23	nmod
,	,	O	27	punct
Eurocontrol	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	27	conj
,	,	O	27	punct
airport	NN	O	32	compound
operators	NNS	O	27	conj
,	,	O	27	punct
air	NN	O	36	compound
navigation	NN	O	36	compound
providers	NNS	O	27	conj
and	CC	O	27	cc
aerospace	NN	O	39	compound
companies	NNS	O	27	conj
.	.	O	3	punct

Digital	NNP	O	0	ROOT
data	NNS	O	3	compound
links	NNS	O	3	compound
via	IN	O	10	nsubj
satellite	JJ	O	6	case
Modernisation	NN	O	6	compound
on	IN	O	3	nmod
this	DT	O	9	case
scale	NN	O	9	det
demands	VBZ	O	6	nmod
a	DT	O	14	det
long-term	JJ	O	14	amod
stepped	JJ	O	14	amod
approach	NN	O	10	dobj
but	CC	O	10	cc
it	PRP	O	17	nsubj
promises	VBZ	O	10	conj
to	TO	O	19	mark
boost	VB	O	17	xcomp
efficiency	NN	O	19	dobj
,	,	O	20	punct
capacity	NN	O	20	conj
and	CC	O	20	cc
performance	NN	O	20	conj
.	.	O	10	punct

Iris	NNP	B-PERSON	0	ROOT
is	VBZ	O	3	nsubjpass
divided	VBN	O	3	auxpass
into	IN	O	6	case
two	CD	B-NUMBER	6	nummod
phases	NNS	O	3	nmod
,	,	O	6	punct
in	IN	O	9	case
line	NN	O	6	nmod
with	IN	O	14	case
Europe	NNP	B-LOCATION	14	nmod:poss
's	POS	O	11	case
master	NN	O	14	compound
plan	NN	O	9	nmod
for	IN	O	16	mark
managing	VBG	O	14	acl
future	JJ	B-DATE	19	amod
air	NN	O	19	compound
traffic	NN	O	16	dobj
.	.	O	3	punct

First	RB	B-ORDINAL	0	ROOT
,	,	O	8	advmod
the	DT	O	8	punct
Iris	NNP	O	6	det
Precursor	NNP	O	6	compound
service	NN	O	6	compound
will	MD	O	8	nsubj
provide	VB	O	8	aux
air-ground	JJ	O	10	amod
communications	NNS	O	8	dobj
for	IN	O	16	case
initial	JJ	O	16	amod
4D	CD	O	16	compound
flight	NN	O	16	compound
path	NN	O	16	compound
control	NN	O	10	nmod
by	IN	O	18	case
2018	CD	B-DATE	8	nmod
,	,	O	8	punct
pinpointing	VBG	O	8	advcl
an	DT	O	22	det
aircraft	NN	O	20	dobj
in	IN	O	25	case
four	CD	B-NUMBER	25	nummod
dimensions	NNS	O	20	nmod
:	:	O	20	punct
latitude	NN	O	20	dep
,	,	O	27	punct
longitude	NN	O	27	conj
,	,	O	27	punct
altitude	NN	O	27	conj
and	CC	O	27	cc
time	NN	O	27	conj
.	.	O	8	punct

Controlling	VBG	O	0	ROOT
flight	NN	O	8	csubj
paths	NNS	O	3	compound
with	IN	O	1	dobj
4D	CD	O	5	case
is	VBZ	O	3	nmod
safer	JJR	O	8	cop
Second	JJ	B-ORDINAL	8	advmod
,	,	O	8	punct
by	IN	O	11	case
2028	CD	B-DATE	8	nmod
,	,	O	8	punct
the	DT	O	16	det
Iris	NNP	O	16	compound
long-term	JJ	O	16	amod
service	NN	O	18	nsubj
will	MD	O	18	aux
enable	VB	O	8	parataxis
full	JJ	O	21	amod
4D	CD	O	21	compound
management	NN	O	18	dobj
over	IN	O	23	case
airspaces	NNS	O	18	nmod
across	IN	O	26	case
the	DT	O	26	det
globe	NN	O	23	nmod
and	CC	O	23	cc
the	DT	O	30	det
data	NN	O	30	compound
link	NN	O	35	nsubj
will	MD	O	35	aux
be	VB	O	35	cop
the	DT	O	35	det
primary	JJ	O	35	amod
means	NNS	O	23	conj
of	IN	O	37	case
communications	NNS	O	35	nmod
between	IN	O	39	case
controllers	NNS	O	37	nmod
and	CC	O	39	cc
cockpit	JJ	O	42	compound
crews	NNS	O	39	conj
.	.	O	8	punct

Controlling	VBG	O	0	ROOT
flight	NN	O	7	csubj
paths	NNS	O	3	compound
with	IN	O	1	dobj
4D	CD	O	5	case
is	VBZ	O	3	nmod
safer	JJR	O	7	cop
and	CC	O	7	cc
more	RBR	O	10	advmod
reliable	JJ	O	7	conj
.	.	O	7	punct

To	TO	O	0	ROOT
help	VB	O	2	mark
achieve	VB	O	9	advcl
this	DT	O	2	ccomp
goal	NN	O	5	det
,	,	O	3	dobj
ESA	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	9	punct
is	VBZ	O	9	nsubj
developing	VBG	O	9	aux
a	DT	O	13	det
new	JJ	O	13	amod
global	JJ	O	13	amod
standard	NN	O	9	dobj
for	IN	O	15	case
satcoms	NNS	O	13	nmod
that	WDT	O	19	nsubjpass
can	MD	O	19	aux
be	VB	O	19	auxpass
adopted	VBN	O	15	acl:relcl
worldwide	JJ	O	19	advmod
,	,	O	9	punct
and	CC	O	9	cc
is	VBZ	O	24	aux
designing	VBG	O	9	conj
infrastructure	NN	O	24	dobj
to	TO	O	27	mark
make	VB	O	24	advcl
this	DT	O	29	det
service	NN	O	30	nsubj
available	JJ	O	27	xcomp
in	IN	O	32	case
Europe	NNP	B-LOCATION	30	nmod
.	.	O	9	punct

Some	DT	O	0	ROOT
airlines	NNS	O	2	det
already	RB	O	4	nsubj
use	VBP	O	4	advmod
satellite	JJ	O	6	compound
services	NNS	O	4	dobj
To	TO	O	8	mark
meet	VB	O	4	advcl
safety	NN	O	10	compound
regulations	NNS	O	8	dobj
,	,	O	10	punct
aircraft	NN	O	10	appos
in	IN	O	15	case
European	JJ	B-NATIONALITY	15	amod
airspace	NN	O	12	nmod
fly	VBP	O	4	advcl
an	DT	O	20	det
extra	JJ	O	20	amod
42	CD	B-NUMBER	20	nummod
km	NN	O	16	dobj
on	IN	O	22	case
average	NN	O	16	nmod
than	IN	O	29	mark
they	PRP	O	29	nsubj
would	MD	O	29	aux
on	IN	O	29	case
an	DT	O	29	det
optimal	JJ	O	29	amod
route	NN	O	16	advcl
,	,	O	16	punct
incurring	VBG	O	16	xcomp
unnecessary	JJ	O	33	amod
costs	NNS	O	31	dobj
and	CC	O	33	cc
carbon	NN	O	37	compound
dioxide	NN	O	37	compound
emissions	NNS	O	33	conj
.	.	O	4	punct

4D	CD	O	0	ROOT
paths	NNS	O	2	compound
will	MD	O	4	nsubj
enable	VB	O	4	aux
precise	JJ	O	6	amod
tracking	NN	O	4	dobj
of	IN	O	8	case
flights	NNS	O	6	nmod
and	CC	O	8	cc
more	RBR	O	11	advmod
efficient	JJ	O	12	amod
management	NN	O	8	conj
of	IN	O	14	case
traffic	NN	O	12	nmod
.	.	O	4	punct

A	DT	O	0	ROOT
key	JJ	O	3	det
benefit	NN	O	3	amod
of	IN	O	6	nsubj
4D	CD	O	5	case
is	VBZ	O	3	nmod
that	IN	O	9	mark
it	PRP	O	9	nsubj
allows	VBZ	O	6	ccomp
rapid	JJ	O	11	amod
rerouting	NN	O	9	xcomp
,	,	O	11	punct
meaning	VBG	O	11	advcl
fewer	JJR	O	16	amod
flight	NN	O	16	compound
cancellations	NNS	O	13	dobj
and	CC	O	16	cc
delays	NNS	O	16	conj
,	,	O	16	punct
and	CC	O	16	cc
safer	JJR	O	23	amod
air	NN	O	23	compound
travel	SYM	O	16	conj
-	:	O	16	punct
possible	JJ	O	16	amod
partly	RB	O	33	advmod
because	IN	O	33	mark
all	DT	O	29	det
aircraft	NN	O	33	nsubjpass
will	MD	O	33	aux
be	VB	O	33	auxpass
continuously	RB	O	33	advmod
monitored	VBN	O	25	advcl
and	CC	O	33	cc
locations	NNS	O	37	nsubj
periodically	RB	O	37	advmod
reported	VBD	O	33	conj
to	TO	O	39	mark
control	VB	O	37	xcomp
centres	NNS	O	39	dobj
.	.	O	6	punct

Airlines	NNS	O	0	ROOT
have	VBP	O	3	nsubj
accepted	VBN	O	3	aux
the	DT	O	5	det
need	NN	O	3	dobj
to	TO	O	7	mark
switch	VB	O	5	acl
to	TO	O	10	case
digital	VB	O	10	amod
services	NNS	O	7	nmod
,	,	O	3	punct
and	CC	O	3	cc
some	DT	O	15	det
satellite	NN	O	15	compound
services	NNS	O	19	nsubj
are	VBP	O	19	cop
already	RB	O	19	advmod
in	IN	O	19	case
use	NN	O	3	conj
over	IN	O	22	case
ocean	JJ	O	22	compound
airspace	NN	O	19	nmod
.	.	O	3	punct

The	DT	O	0	ROOT
changes	NNS	O	2	det
will	MD	O	4	nsubj
take	VB	O	4	aux
some	DT	O	6	det
time	NN	O	4	dobj
because	IN	O	13	mark
manufacturing	NN	O	9	amod
schedules	NNS	O	13	nsubjpass
for	IN	O	11	case
aircraft	NN	O	9	nmod
are	VBP	O	13	auxpass
set	VBN	O	4	advcl
years	NNS	B-DURATION	13	nmod:tmod
in	IN	O	16	case
advance	NN	O	14	nmod
.	.	O	4	punct

Existing	VBG	O	0	ROOT
planes	NNS	O	2	amod
require	VBP	O	3	nsubj
modifications	NNS	O	3	dobj
to	TO	O	6	mark
install	VB	O	3	xcomp
the	DT	O	9	det
new	JJ	O	9	amod
hardware	NN	O	6	dobj
,	,	O	3	punct
and	CC	O	3	cc
affordability	NN	O	13	nsubj
requires	VBZ	O	3	conj
that	IN	O	17	mark
costs	NNS	O	17	nsubjpass
are	VBP	O	17	auxpass
kept	VBN	O	13	ccomp
to	TO	O	20	case
a	DT	O	20	det
minimum	NN	O	17	nmod
.	.	O	3	punct

``	``	O	0	ROOT
This	DT	O	22	punct
programme	NN	O	3	det
will	MD	O	5	nsubj
bring	VB	O	5	aux
essential	JJ	O	22	ccomp
improvements	NNS	O	7	amod
to	TO	O	5	dobj
the	DT	O	10	case
safety	NN	O	10	det
of	IN	O	5	nmod
air	NN	O	13	case
travel	NN	O	13	compound
as	RB	O	10	nmod
well	RB	O	5	cc
as	IN	O	14	mwe
vast	JJ	O	14	mwe
economic	JJ	O	19	amod
benefits	NNS	O	19	amod
,	,	O	5	conj
''	''	O	22	punct
notes	VBZ	O	22	punct
Magali	NNP	B-PERSON	24	compound
Vaissiere	NNP	I-PERSON	22	nsubj
,	,	O	24	punct
ESA	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	28	nmod:poss
's	POS	O	26	case
Director	NNP	B-TITLE	24	appos
of	IN	O	30	case
Telecommunications	NNP	O	28	nmod
and	CC	O	30	cc
Integrated	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	33	compound
Applications	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	30	conj
.	.	O	22	punct

``	``	O	0	ROOT
We	PRP	O	5	nsubj
can	MD	O	5	aux
only	RB	O	5	advmod
do	VB	O	1	root
it	PRP	O	5	dobj
if	IN	O	9	mark
we	PRP	O	9	nsubj
join	VBP	O	5	advcl
forces	NNS	O	9	dobj
,	,	O	5	punct
and	CC	O	5	cc
are	VBP	O	14	cop
ready	JJ	O	5	conj
to	TO	O	16	mark
tackle	VB	O	14	xcomp
this	DT	O	19	det
challenge	JJ	O	19	compound
step	NN	O	16	dobj
by	IN	O	21	case
step	NN	O	16	nmod
.	.	O	5	punct
''	''	O	5	punct
.	.	O	0	ROOT

Numerical	JJ	O	0	ROOT
model	NN	B-TITLE	2	amod
for	IN	O	7	case
much	JJ	O	7	amod
cleaner	NN	B-TITLE	7	amod
aircraft	NN	O	7	compound
engines	VBZ	O	2	nmod
A	DT	O	11	det
European	JJ	B-NATIONALITY	11	amod
research	NN	O	11	compound
consortium	NN	O	12	nsubj
intends	VBZ	O	7	acl:relcl
to	TO	O	14	mark
develop	VB	O	12	xcomp
a	DT	O	17	det
numerical	JJ	O	17	amod
model	NN	B-TITLE	14	dobj
that	WDT	O	20	nsubj
will	MD	O	20	aux
allow	VB	O	17	acl:relcl
CO2	NNP	O	22	compound
emissions	NNS	O	20	dobj
of	IN	O	26	case
new	JJ	O	26	amod
aircraft	NN	O	26	compound
engines	NNS	O	22	nmod
to	TO	O	29	mark
be	VB	O	29	auxpass
halved	VBN	O	20	xcomp
and	CC	O	29	cc
NOx	NNP	O	32	compound
emissions	NNS	O	29	conj
to	TO	O	35	mark
be	VB	O	35	auxpass
reduced	VBN	O	29	xcomp
by	IN	O	38	case
80	CD	B-PERCENT	38	nummod
%	NN	I-PERCENT	35	nmod
.	.	O	2	punct

The	DT	O	0	ROOT
project	NN	O	2	det
,	,	O	12	nsubjpass
which	WDT	O	2	punct
started	VBD	O	5	nsubj
last	JJ	B-DATE	2	acl:relcl
Friday	NNP	I-DATE	7	amod
in	IN	O	5	nmod:tmod
Eindhoven	NNP	B-CITY	9	case
,	,	O	5	nmod
is	VBZ	O	2	punct
coordinated	VBN	O	12	auxpass
by	IN	O	14	case
dr.ir	NN	O	12	nmod
.	.	O	12	punct

Jeroen	NNP	B-PERSON	0	ROOT
van	NN	I-PERSON	3	compound
Oijen	NNP	I-PERSON	3	compound
of	IN	O	6	nsubj
TU	NNP	O	5	case
e	NN	O	3	nmod
.	.	O	6	punct
The	DT	O	0	ROOT
project	NN	O	2	det
is	VBZ	O	4	nsubjpass
called	VBN	O	4	auxpass
DREAMCODE	NNP	O	7	compound
-	:	O	7	punct
Development	NNP	O	4	xcomp
of	IN	O	10	case
Reliable	NNP	O	10	compound
Emission	NNP	O	7	nmod
and	CC	O	10	cc
Atomization	NNP	O	13	compound
Models	NNP	O	10	conj
for	IN	O	16	case
COmbustor	NNP	O	16	compound
DEsign	NNP	O	7	nmod
.	.	O	4	punct

It	PRP	O	0	ROOT
forms	VBZ	O	2	nsubj
part	NN	O	2	dobj
of	IN	O	8	case
a	DT	O	8	det
larger	JJR	O	8	amod
European	JJ	B-NATIONALITY	8	amod
project	NN	O	3	nmod
,	,	O	8	punct
called	VBN	O	8	acl
CleanSky	NNP	O	10	xcomp
,	,	O	8	punct
aimed	VBN	O	8	acl
at	IN	O	16	case
technology	NN	O	16	compound
breakthroughs	NNS	O	13	nmod
to	TO	O	18	mark
meet	VB	O	13	xcomp
more	RBR	O	20	advmod
stringent	JJ	O	22	amod
environmental	JJ	O	22	amod
demands	NNS	O	18	dobj
.	.	O	2	punct

Through	IN	O	0	ROOT
these	DT	O	3	case
projects	NNS	O	3	det
the	DT	O	7	nmod
EU	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	5	det
is	VBZ	O	7	nsubj
bringing	VBG	O	7	aux
the	DT	O	10	det
aviation	NN	O	10	compound
industry	NN	O	7	dobj
and	CC	O	7	cc
advanced	VBD	O	7	conj
research	NN	O	14	compound
institutes	NNS	O	12	dobj
closer	RBR	O	16	advmod
together	RB	O	12	advmod
.	.	O	7	punct

Acting	VBG	O	0	ROOT
as	IN	O	3	case
coordinator	NN	O	1	nmod
for	IN	O	5	case
DREAMCODE	NNP	O	3	nmod
,	,	O	5	punct
TU	NNP	O	5	appos
e	NN	O	10	nsubj
will	MD	O	10	aux
work	VB	O	5	acl:relcl
together	RB	O	10	advmod
with	IN	O	15	case
RWTH	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	15	compound
Aachen	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	15	compound
University	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	10	nmod
,	,	O	15	punct
the	DT	O	19	det
Karlsruhe	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	19	compound
Institute	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	15	conj
of	IN	I-ORGANIZATION	21	case
Technology	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	19	nmod
,	,	O	15	punct
Imperial	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	25	compound
College	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	25	compound
London	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	15	conj
and	CC	O	15	cc
aircraft	NN	O	30	compound
engine	NN	O	30	compound
builder	NN	B-TITLE	30	compound
Rolls-Royce	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	15	conj
in	IN	O	35	case
the	DT	B-DATE	35	det
coming	JJ	I-DATE	35	amod
three	CD	I-DATE	35	nummod
years	NNS	I-DATE	10	nmod
on	IN	O	38	case
this	DT	O	38	det
project	NN	O	35	nmod
.	.	O	1	punct

The	DT	O	0	ROOT
aim	NN	O	2	det
is	VBZ	O	3	nsubj
to	TO	O	5	mark
develop	VB	O	3	xcomp
an	DT	O	11	det
accurate	NN	O	11	amod
and	CC	O	7	cc
reliable	JJ	O	7	conj
numerical	JJ	O	11	amod
model	NN	B-TITLE	5	dobj
to	TO	O	13	mark
predict	VB	O	11	acl
the	DT	O	15	det
emissions	NNS	O	13	dobj
of	IN	O	21	case
new	JJ	O	21	amod
,	,	O	21	punct
advanced	JJ	O	21	amod
aircraft	NN	O	21	compound
engines	NNS	O	15	nmod
.	.	O	3	punct

The	DT	O	0	ROOT
model	NN	B-TITLE	2	det
will	MD	O	4	nsubj
allow	VB	O	4	aux
the	DT	O	6	det
development	NN	O	4	dobj
of	IN	O	11	case
new	JJ	O	11	amod
,	,	O	11	punct
environment-friendly	JJ	O	11	amod
engines	NNS	O	6	nmod
for	IN	O	14	case
commercial	JJ	O	14	amod
aircraft	NN	O	11	nmod
,	,	O	4	punct
reducing	VBG	O	4	advcl
CO2	NNP	O	18	compound
emissions	NNS	O	16	dobj
by	IN	O	21	case
50	CD	B-PERCENT	21	nummod
%	NN	I-PERCENT	16	nmod
and	CC	O	21	cc
NOx	NNP	O	24	compound
emissions	NNS	O	21	conj
by	IN	O	27	case
80	CD	B-PERCENT	27	nummod
%	NN	I-PERCENT	16	nmod
.	.	O	4	punct

Associate	NNP	O	0	ROOT
professor	NN	B-TITLE	5	amod
Jeroen	NNP	B-PERSON	5	compound
van	NN	I-PERSON	5	compound
Oijen	NNP	I-PERSON	5	compound
,	,	O	5	punct
from	IN	O	9	case
the	DT	O	9	det
TU	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	24	nmod
e	NN	I-ORGANIZATION	24	dep
Combustion	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	13	compound
Technology	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	13	compound
group	NN	O	24	nsubj
led	VBD	O	13	acl
by	IN	O	19	case
professor	NN	B-TITLE	19	compound
Philip	NNP	B-PERSON	19	compound
de	IN	I-PERSON	19	amod
Goey	NNP	I-PERSON	14	nmod
,	,	O	13	punct
is	VBZ	O	24	cop
the	DT	O	24	det
project	NN	O	24	compound
coordinator	NN	O	5	acl:relcl
.	.	O	5	punct

Each	DT	O	0	ROOT
of	IN	O	7	nsubj
the	DT	O	5	case
research	NN	O	5	det
institutes	VBZ	O	5	compound
involved	VBN	O	1	nmod
has	VBZ	O	5	acl
its	PRP$	O	10	nmod:poss
own	JJ	O	10	amod
specialization	NN	O	7	dobj
in	IN	O	13	case
the	DT	O	13	det
fields	NNS	O	7	nmod
of	IN	O	15	case
modeling	NN	O	13	nmod
and	CC	O	15	cc
combustion	NN	O	15	conj
-	:	O	7	punct
for	IN	O	20	case
TU	NNP	O	25	nmod
e	NN	O	22	dep
this	DT	O	25	nsubj
is	VBZ	O	25	cop
the	DT	O	25	det
development	NN	O	7	parataxis
of	IN	O	29	case
efficient	JJ	O	29	amod
calculation	NN	O	29	compound
methods	NNS	O	25	nmod
for	IN	O	33	case
complex	JJ	O	33	amod
chemical	NN	O	33	compound
processes	NNS	O	29	nmod
during	IN	O	35	case
combustion	NN	O	33	nmod
,	,	O	25	punct
involving	VBG	O	25	acl
tens	NNS	O	37	dobj
of	IN	O	40	case
thousands	NNS	O	38	nmod
of	IN	O	42	case
reactions	NNS	O	40	nmod
between	IN	O	44	case
hundreds	NNS	O	38	nmod
of	IN	O	47	case
chemical	NN	O	47	compound
components	NNS	O	44	nmod
.	.	O	7	punct

This	DT	O	0	ROOT
demands	VBZ	O	2	nsubj
so	RB	O	4	advmod
much	JJ	O	6	amod
computing	VBG	O	6	compound
power	NN	O	2	dobj
that	IN	O	15	mark
such	PDT	O	11	det:predet
a	DT	O	11	det
detailed	JJ	O	11	amod
model	NN	B-TITLE	15	nsubjpass
can	MD	O	15	aux
not	RB	O	15	neg
be	VB	O	15	auxpass
used	VBN	O	6	dep
in	IN	O	18	case
the	DT	O	18	det
simulation	NN	O	15	nmod
of	IN	O	22	case
a	DT	O	22	det
real	JJ	O	22	amod
engine	NN	O	18	nmod
.	.	O	2	punct

TU	NNP	O	0	ROOT
e	NN	O	2	compound
has	VBZ	O	4	nsubj
developed	VBN	O	4	aux
a	DT	O	6	det
method	NN	O	4	dobj
to	TO	O	8	mark
make	VB	O	6	acl
a	DT	O	12	det
simplified	JJ	O	12	amod
chemical	NN	O	12	compound
model	NN	B-TITLE	8	dobj
that	WDT	O	14	nsubj
allows	VBZ	O	12	acl:relcl
the	DT	O	16	det
computations	NNS	O	14	dobj
to	TO	O	19	mark
be	VB	O	19	auxpass
carried	VBN	O	14	xcomp
out	IN	O	19	compound:prt
without	IN	O	22	mark
losing	VBG	O	19	advcl
too	RB	O	24	advmod
much	JJ	O	25	amod
accuracy	NN	O	22	dobj
.	.	O	4	punct

The	DT	O	0	ROOT
project	NN	O	2	det
has	VBZ	O	3	nsubj
a	DT	O	5	det
budget	NN	O	3	dobj
of	IN	O	9	case
1.3	CD	B-MONEY	8	compound
million	CD	I-MONEY	9	nummod
euros	NNS	I-MONEY	5	nmod
,	,	O	9	punct
of	IN	O	12	case
which	WDT	O	17	nmod
75	CD	B-PERCENT	14	nummod
percent	NN	I-PERCENT	17	nsubjpass
will	MD	O	17	aux
be	VB	O	17	auxpass
paid	VBN	O	9	acl:relcl
by	IN	O	20	case
the	DT	O	20	det
EU	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	17	nmod
.	.	O	3	punct

About	IN	O	0	ROOT
5	CD	B-NUMBER	2	advmod
PhD	NNP	O	4	nummod
candidates	NNS	O	4	compound
will	MD	O	7	nsubjpass
be	VB	O	7	aux
involved	VBN	O	7	auxpass
in	IN	O	9	mark
working	VBG	O	7	advcl
on	IN	O	12	case
the	DT	O	12	det
project	NN	O	9	nmod
.	.	O	7	punct

Penn	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	0	ROOT
State	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	2	compound
,	,	O	7	nsubj
Pratt	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	2	punct
&	CC	I-ORGANIZATION	2	conj
Whitney	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	2	cc
inaugurate	VBP	O	2	conj
most	RBS	O	9	advmod
advanced	JJ	O	12	amod
turbine	NN	O	12	compound
testing	VBG	O	12	compound
lab	NN	O	7	dobj
in	IN	O	16	case
U.S	NNP	B-LOCATION	16	compound
UNIVERSITY	NNP	B-CITY	16	compound
PARK	NNP	I-CITY	34	nmod
,	,	O	16	punct
Pa.	NNP	B-STATE_OR_PROVINCE	16	appos
-	:	O	16	punct
Penn	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	21	compound
State	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	34	nsubj
and	CC	O	21	cc
Pratt	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	21	conj
&	CC	I-ORGANIZATION	23	cc
Whitney	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	23	conj
,	,	O	23	punct
a	DT	O	31	det
United	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	31	compound
Technologies	NNPS	I-ORGANIZATION	31	compound
Corp.	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	31	compound
company	NN	O	23	appos
,	,	O	23	punct
officially	RB	O	34	advmod
unveiled	VBD	O	12	acl:relcl
the	DT	O	40	det
Steady	JJ	O	40	compound
Thermal	NNP	O	40	amod
Aero	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	40	compound
Research	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	40	compound
Turbine	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	44	nsubj
-LRB-	NNP	O	42	punct
START	NNP	O	40	appos
-RRB-	NNP	O	42	punct
facility	NN	O	34	ccomp
,	,	O	44	punct
the	DT	O	47	det
country	NN	O	53	nmod:poss
's	VBZ	O	47	case
most	RBS	O	50	advmod
advanced	JJ	O	53	amod
turbine	NN	O	53	compound
testing	VBG	O	53	compound
laboratory	NN	O	44	appos
,	,	O	44	punct
at	IN	O	58	case
a	DT	O	58	det
ribbon-cutting	JJ	O	58	amod
ceremony	NN	O	44	nmod
March	NNP	B-DATE	58	nmod:tmod
19	CD	I-DATE	59	nummod
at	IN	O	63	case
Cato	NNP	B-CITY	63	compound
Park	NNP	B-LOCATION	58	nmod
.	.	O	7	punct

The	DT	O	0	ROOT
new	JJ	O	3	det
facility	NN	O	3	amod
is	VBZ	O	5	nsubjpass
supported	VBN	O	5	auxpass
by	IN	O	7	case
Pratt	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	5	nmod
&	CC	I-ORGANIZATION	7	cc
Whitney	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	7	conj
,	,	O	7	punct
the	DT	O	12	det
Department	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	7	appos
of	IN	I-ORGANIZATION	19	case
Energy	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	19	nmod:poss
's	POS	I-ORGANIZATION	14	case
National	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	19	compound
Energy	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	19	compound
Technology	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	19	compound
Laboratory	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	12	nmod
and	CC	O	19	cc
Penn	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	22	compound
State	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	19	conj
.	.	O	5	punct

Penn	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	0	ROOT
State	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	5	compound
President	NNP	B-TITLE	5	compound
Rodney	NNP	B-PERSON	5	compound
Erickson	NNP	I-PERSON	5	compound
;	:	O	43	nsubj
David	NNP	B-PERSON	5	punct
Wormley	NNP	I-PERSON	8	compound
,	,	O	5	dep
Harold	NNP	B-PERSON	8	punct
and	CC	O	8	conj
Inge	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	8	cc
Marcus	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	14	compound
Dean	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	14	compound
of	IN	I-ORGANIZATION	8	conj
Engineering	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	16	case
;	:	O	14	nmod
Karen	NNP	B-PERSON	5	punct
Thole	NNP	I-PERSON	19	compound
,	,	O	5	conj
head	NN	O	19	punct
of	IN	O	19	appos
mechanical	JJ	O	26	case
and	CC	O	26	amod
nuclear	JJ	O	23	cc
engineering	NN	O	23	conj
;	:	O	21	nmod
and	CC	O	5	punct
Al	NNP	B-PERSON	5	cc
Brockett	NNP	I-PERSON	30	compound
,	,	O	5	conj
Pratt	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	30	punct
&	CC	I-ORGANIZATION	30	conj
Whitney	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	30	cc
's	POS	O	37	nmod:poss
vice	NN	B-TITLE	34	case
president	NN	I-TITLE	37	compound
of	IN	O	30	conj
engineering	NN	O	41	case
module	NN	O	41	compound
centers	NNS	O	41	compound
,	,	O	37	nmod
attended	VBD	O	5	punct
the	DT	O	45	det
event	NN	O	43	dobj
.	.	O	43	punct

``	``	O	0	ROOT
By	IN	O	14	punct
collaborating	VBG	O	3	mark
with	IN	O	14	advcl
best-in-class	JJ	O	7	case
research	NN	O	7	amod
partners	NNS	O	7	compound
such	JJ	O	3	nmod
as	IN	O	11	case
Penn	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	8	mwe
State	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	11	compound
,	,	O	7	nmod
we	PRP	O	14	punct
improve	VBP	O	14	nsubj
our	PRP$	O	35	dep
products	NNS	O	16	nmod:poss
and	CC	O	14	dobj
advance	VB	O	16	cc
the	DT	O	16	conj
aviation	NN	O	21	det
industry	NN	O	21	compound
while	IN	O	18	dobj
developing	VBG	O	23	mark
the	DT	O	14	advcl
next	JJ	O	26	det
generation	NN	O	26	amod
of	IN	O	23	dobj
engineers	NNS	O	28	case
,	,	O	26	nmod
scientists	NNS	O	28	punct
and	CC	O	28	conj
researchers	NNS	O	28	cc
,	,	O	28	conj
''	''	O	14	punct
said	VBD	O	14	punct
Brockett	NNP	B-PERSON	35	nsubj
.	.	O	35	punct

``	``	O	0	ROOT
We	PRP	O	4	nsubj
are	VBP	O	4	cop
proud	JJ	O	1	root
to	TO	O	6	mark
strengthen	VB	O	4	xcomp
our	PRP$	O	8	nmod:poss
partnership	NN	O	6	dobj
with	IN	O	11	case
Penn	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	11	compound
State	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	8	nmod
.	.	O	4	punct

The	DT	O	0	ROOT
University	NNP	O	2	det
has	VBZ	O	6	nsubj
been	VBN	O	6	aux
a	DT	O	6	cop
Pratt	NNP	O	6	det
&	CC	O	6	cc
Whitney-sponsored	NNP	O	9	compound
Center	NNP	O	6	conj
of	IN	O	11	case
Excellence	NNP	O	6	nmod
since	IN	O	13	case
2008	CD	B-DATE	6	nmod
.	.	O	6	punct
''	''	O	6	punct

At	IN	O	0	ROOT
the	DT	O	3	case
laboratory	NN	O	3	det
,	,	O	7	nmod
researchers	NNS	O	7	punct
will	MD	O	7	nsubj
simulate	VB	O	7	aux
and	CC	O	7	cc
test	VB	O	7	conj
a	DT	O	12	det
new	JJ	O	12	amod
generation	NN	O	9	dobj
of	IN	O	16	case
High	JJ	O	16	amod
Pressure	NN	O	16	compound
Turbine	NNP	O	12	nmod
-LRB-	NNP	O	18	punct
HPT	NNP	O	16	appos
-RRB-	NNP	O	18	punct
systems	NNS	O	16	dep
that	WDT	O	25	nsubj
will	MD	O	25	aux
be	VB	O	25	cop
more	RBR	O	25	amod
fuel	JJ	O	12	acl:relcl
efficient	NN	O	25	amod
than	IN	O	30	case
today	NN	B-DATE	30	nmod:poss
's	POS	O	28	case
models	NNS	O	26	nmod
.	.	O	7	punct

The	DT	O	0	ROOT
lab	NN	O	2	det
will	MD	O	4	nsubj
evaluate	VB	O	4	aux
leakage	NN	O	8	nsubj
and	CC	O	5	cc
gas-path	NN	O	5	conj
flows	NNS	O	4	ccomp
along	IN	O	13	case
with	IN	O	13	case
new	JJ	O	13	amod
cooling	VBG	O	13	compound
technologies	NNS	O	8	nmod
for	IN	O	20	case
next	JJ	O	20	amod
generation	NN	O	20	compound
gas	NN	O	20	compound
turbine	NN	O	20	compound
engine	NN	O	20	compound
designs	NNS	O	13	nmod
,	,	O	20	punct
such	JJ	O	24	case
as	IN	O	22	mwe
those	DT	O	20	nmod
used	VBN	O	24	acl
for	IN	O	30	case
aircraft	NN	O	30	compound
and	CC	O	27	cc
power	NN	O	27	conj
generation	NN	O	25	nmod
,	,	O	20	punct
to	TO	O	33	mark
improve	VB	O	20	acl
fuel	NN	O	35	compound
efficiency	NN	O	33	dobj
and	CC	O	33	cc
reduce	VB	O	33	conj
emissions	NNS	O	37	dobj
.	.	O	4	punct

Thole	NNP	B-PERSON	0	ROOT
said	VBD	O	2	nsubj
that	IN	O	8	mark
gas	NN	O	6	compound
turbine	NN	O	6	compound
engines	NNS	O	8	nsubj
have	VBP	O	8	aux
rotating	VBG	O	2	ccomp
and	CC	O	8	cc
stationary	JJ	O	12	amod
airfoil	NN	O	12	compound
components	NNS	O	8	conj
that	WDT	O	14	nsubj
contain	VBP	O	12	acl:relcl
gaps	NNS	O	14	dobj
at	IN	O	18	case
the	DT	O	18	det
interfaces	NNS	O	14	nmod
in	IN	O	20	case
which	WDT	O	24	nmod
flow	NN	O	22	compound
sealing	NN	O	24	nsubj
is	VBZ	O	24	cop
difficult	JJ	O	18	acl:relcl
.	.	O	2	punct

At	IN	O	0	ROOT
these	DT	O	3	case
interfaces	NNS	O	3	det
,	,	O	10	nmod
she	PRP	O	6	punct
explained	VBD	O	6	nsubj
,	,	O	10	parataxis
flow	NN	O	6	punct
may	MD	O	10	nsubj
leak	VB	O	10	aux
into	IN	O	10	dep
or	CC	O	11	dep
out	IN	O	16	case
of	IN	O	16	case
the	DT	O	16	det
gaps	NNS	O	12	conj
and	CC	O	16	cc
ultimately	RB	O	19	advmod
reduce	VB	O	16	conj
turbine	NN	O	21	compound
efficiency	NN	O	19	dobj
.	.	O	10	punct

Because	IN	O	0	ROOT
hot	JJ	O	10	mark
combustion	NN	O	4	amod
gases	NNS	O	4	compound
passing	VBG	O	10	nsubj
through	IN	O	4	acl
the	DT	O	8	case
turbine	NN	O	8	det
can	MD	O	5	nmod
melt	VB	O	10	aux
the	DT	O	16	advcl
airfoils	NNS	O	12	det
,	,	O	10	dobj
it	PRP	O	16	punct
is	VBZ	O	16	nsubj
critical	JJ	O	16	cop
to	TO	O	18	mark
keep	VB	O	16	ccomp
the	DT	O	20	det
components	NNS	O	21	nsubj
cool	NN	O	18	xcomp
and	CC	O	18	cc
ensure	VB	O	18	conj
the	DT	O	25	det
seals	NNS	O	28	nsubj
do	VBP	O	28	aux
not	RB	O	28	neg
allow	VB	O	23	ccomp
hot	JJ	O	30	amod
gases	NNS	O	28	dobj
to	TO	O	32	mark
pass	VB	O	28	xcomp
into	IN	O	35	case
the	DT	O	35	det
gaps	NNS	O	32	nmod
.	.	O	16	punct

As	IN	O	0	ROOT
turbine	NN	O	4	mark
efficiencies	NNS	O	3	compound
go	VBP	O	4	nsubj
up	RB	O	4	advmod
,	,	O	4	punct
the	DT	O	8	det
need	NN	O	6	root
for	IN	O	11	case
fuel	NN	O	11	compound
decreases	NNS	O	8	nmod
.	.	O	8	punct

Thole	NNP	B-PERSON	0	ROOT
said	VBD	O	2	nsubj
improving	VBG	O	6	csubj
the	DT	O	5	det
seal	NN	O	3	dobj
designs	VBZ	O	12	csubj
to	TO	O	8	mark
reduce	VB	O	6	xcomp
the	DT	O	10	det
leakages	NNS	O	8	dobj
could	MD	O	12	aux
mean	VB	O	2	ccomp
savings	NNS	O	12	dobj
of	IN	O	17	case
25	CD	B-NUMBER	16	compound
million	CD	I-NUMBER	17	nummod
barrels	NNS	O	13	nmod
of	IN	O	20	case
crude	NN	O	20	amod
oil	NN	O	17	nmod
a	DT	B-DURATION	22	det
year	NN	I-DURATION	17	nmod:npmod
and	CC	O	12	cc
reduce	VB	O	12	conj
green	JJ	O	28	amod
house	NN	O	28	compound
gas	NN	O	28	compound
emissions	NNS	O	24	dobj
by	IN	O	33	case
10	CD	B-NUMBER	31	compound
million	CD	I-NUMBER	33	nummod
metric	JJ	O	33	amod
tons	NNS	O	24	nmod
per	IN	O	35	case
year	NN	B-DURATION	33	nmod
.	.	O	2	punct

But	CC	O	0	ROOT
,	,	O	11	cc
Thole	NNP	B-PERSON	4	punct
said	VBD	O	4	nsubj
,	,	O	11	parataxis
existing	VBG	O	4	punct
experimental	JJ	O	8	amod
facilities	NNS	O	8	amod
do	VBP	O	11	nsubj
not	RB	O	11	aux
have	VB	O	11	neg
the	DT	O	13	det
ability	NN	O	24	nsubj
to	TO	O	15	mark
evaluate	VB	O	13	acl
new	JJ	O	18	amod
sealing	VBG	O	18	amod
designs	NNS	O	15	dobj
to	TO	O	20	mark
curb	VB	O	15	advcl
these	DT	O	23	det
gap	NN	O	23	compound
leakage	NN	O	20	dobj
flows	VBZ	O	11	ccomp
.	.	O	11	punct

``	``	O	0	ROOT
Current	JJ	B-DATE	3	amod
rigs	NNS	O	6	nsubj
are	VBP	O	6	cop
not	RB	O	6	neg
able	JJ	O	1	root
to	TO	O	8	mark
simulate	VB	O	6	xcomp
the	DT	O	11	det
rotational	JJ	O	11	amod
speeds	NNS	O	8	dobj
and	CC	O	11	cc
air-flow	JJ	O	14	compound
speeds	NNS	O	11	conj
that	IN	O	17	dobj
engineers	NNS	O	17	nsubj
need	VBP	O	11	acl:relcl
to	TO	O	19	mark
simulate	VB	O	17	xcomp
the	DT	O	21	det
complex	JJ	O	19	dobj
flows	VBZ	O	6	xcomp
that	IN	O	24	det
result	NN	O	22	dobj
in	IN	O	27	case
gap	NN	O	27	compound
leakages	NNS	O	24	nmod
between	IN	O	30	case
airfoil	NN	O	30	compound
stages	NNS	O	27	nmod
in	IN	O	33	case
operating	NN	O	33	amod
turbines	NNS	O	30	nmod
.	.	O	6	punct
''	''	O	6	punct

The	DT	O	0	ROOT
START	NNP	O	3	det
lab	NN	O	3	compound
,	,	O	15	nsubj
which	WDT	O	3	punct
will	MD	O	9	nsubj
be	VB	O	9	aux
fully	RB	O	9	cop
operational	JJ	O	9	advmod
in	IN	O	3	acl:relcl
January	NNP	B-DATE	11	case
2014	CD	I-DATE	9	nmod
,	,	O	11	nummod
will	MD	O	3	punct
give	VB	O	15	aux
researchers	NNS	O	15	iobj
the	DT	O	18	det
opportunity	NN	O	15	dobj
to	TO	O	20	mark
simulate	VB	O	18	acl
and	CC	O	20	cc
test	VB	O	20	conj
the	DT	O	25	det
next	JJ	O	25	amod
generation	NN	O	20	dobj
of	IN	O	30	case
fuel-efficient	JJ	O	30	amod
gas	NN	O	30	compound
turbine	NN	O	30	compound
engines	NNS	O	25	nmod
while	IN	O	33	mark
also	RB	O	33	advmod
educating	VBG	O	15	advcl
the	DT	O	36	det
next	JJ	O	36	amod
generation	NN	O	33	dobj
of	IN	O	39	case
turbine	NN	O	39	compound
engineers	NNS	O	36	nmod
.	.	O	15	punct

It	PRP	O	0	ROOT
includes	VBZ	O	2	nsubj
a	DT	O	6	det
continuously	RB	O	5	advmod
flowing	VBG	O	6	amod
turbine	NN	O	2	dobj
that	WDT	O	9	nsubj
will	MD	O	9	aux
operate	VB	O	6	acl:relcl
at	IN	O	13	case
realistic	JJ	O	13	amod
engine	NN	O	13	compound
conditions	NNS	O	9	nmod
that	WDT	O	18	nsubj
have	VBP	O	18	aux
not	RB	O	18	neg
been	VBN	O	18	cop
possible	JJ	O	13	acl:relcl
in	IN	O	21	case
any	DT	O	21	det
laboratory	NN	O	18	nmod
in	IN	O	25	case
the	DT	O	25	det
United	NNP	B-COUNTRY	25	compound
States	NNPS	I-COUNTRY	21	nmod
.	.	O	2	punct

Since	IN	O	0	ROOT
1990	CD	B-DATE	2	case
,	,	O	10	nmod
Pratt	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	10	punct
&	CC	I-ORGANIZATION	10	nsubj
Whitney	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	4	cc
and	CC	O	4	conj
UTC	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	4	cc
have	VBP	O	4	conj
sponsored	VBN	O	10	aux
more	JJR	O	13	advmod
than	IN	O	11	mwe
$	$	B-MONEY	10	dobj
14.5	CD	I-MONEY	15	compound
million	CD	I-MONEY	13	nummod
in	IN	O	17	case
research	NN	O	13	nmod
across	IN	O	20	case
the	DT	O	20	det
University	NNP	O	10	nmod
,	,	O	10	punct
including	VBG	O	23	case
projects	NNS	O	10	nmod
at	IN	O	28	case
the	DT	O	28	det
Applied	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	28	compound
Research	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	28	compound
Laboratory	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	23	nmod
,	,	O	28	punct
Materials	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	32	compound
Research	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	32	compound
Institute	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	28	conj
,	,	O	28	punct
architectural	JJ	O	36	amod
engineering	NN	O	36	compound
department	NN	O	28	conj
,	,	O	28	punct
aerospace	NN	O	40	compound
engineering	NN	O	40	compound
department	NN	O	28	conj
,	,	O	28	punct
industrial	JJ	O	46	amod
and	CC	O	42	cc
manufacturing	VBG	O	42	conj
engineering	NN	O	46	compound
department	NN	O	28	conj
,	,	O	28	punct
and	CC	O	28	cc
mechanical	JJ	O	53	amod
and	CC	O	49	cc
nuclear	JJ	O	49	conj
engineering	NN	O	53	compound
department	NN	O	28	conj
.	.	O	10	punct
.	.	O	0	ROOT
FlySafe	NNP	B-PERSON	0	ROOT
adds	VBZ	O	2	nsubj
new	JJ	O	4	amod
dimension	NN	O	2	dobj
to	TO	O	2	xcomp
safe	VB	O	5	ccomp
flying	VBG	O	6	dep
15	CD	B-DATE	9	nummod
January	NNP	I-DATE	7	nmod:tmod
2013	CD	I-DATE	9	nummod
Migrating	NNP	O	7	advcl
birds	NNS	O	13	nsubj
fly	VBP	O	11	ccomp
as	RB	O	15	advmod
long	RB	O	13	advmod
as	IN	O	18	mark
it	PRP	O	18	nsubj
takes	VBZ	O	15	advcl
to	TO	O	20	mark
get	VB	O	18	xcomp
to	TO	O	23	case
their	PRP$	O	23	nmod:poss
destination	NN	O	20	nmod
,	,	O	13	punct
no	DT	O	26	neg
matter	NN	O	13	xcomp
what	WP	O	28	det
obstacles	VBZ	O	32	nsubj
are	VBP	O	32	cop
in	IN	O	32	case
their	PRP$	O	32	nmod:poss
way	NN	O	26	ccomp
.	.	O	2	punct

When	WRB	O	0	ROOT
that	DT	O	6	advmod
obstacle	NN	O	3	det
is	VBZ	O	6	nsubj
an	DT	O	6	cop
aircraft	NN	O	6	det
,	,	O	12	advcl
the	DT	O	12	punct
results	NNS	O	9	det
can	MD	O	12	nsubj
be	VB	O	12	aux
deadly	RB	O	12	cop
.	.	O	12	punct

According	VBG	O	0	ROOT
to	TO	O	7	case
the	DT	O	1	mwe
US	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	7	det
Federal	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	7	compound
Aviation	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	7	compound
Administration	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	7	compound
,	,	O	12	nmod
bird	NN	O	12	punct
strikes	NNS	O	10	compound
have	VBP	O	12	nsubj
killed	VBN	O	12	aux
more	JJR	O	15	advmod
than	IN	O	13	mwe
231	CD	B-NUMBER	16	nummod
people	NNS	O	12	dobj
and	CC	O	12	cc
destroyed	VBN	O	12	conj
over	IN	O	21	case
220	CD	B-NUMBER	21	nummod
aircraft	NN	O	18	nmod
worldwide	NN	O	18	advmod
since	IN	O	24	case
1988	CD	B-DATE	18	nmod
.	.	O	12	punct

Satellites	NNS	O	0	ROOT
are	VBP	O	3	nsubj
helping	VBG	O	3	aux
to	TO	O	5	mark
change	VB	O	3	xcomp
this	DT	O	8	det
deadly	JJ	O	8	amod
scene	NN	O	5	dobj
.	.	O	3	punct

In	IN	O	0	ROOT
2007	CD	B-DATE	2	case
,	,	O	5	nmod
ESA	NNP	O	5	punct
began	VBD	O	5	nsubj
the	DT	O	8	det
FlySafe	NNP	O	8	compound
project	NN	O	5	dobj
in	IN	O	10	case
partnership	NN	O	5	nmod
with	IN	O	21	case
the	DT	O	21	det
Dutch	NNP	B-NATIONALITY	17	dep
,	,	O	13	punct
Belgian	NNP	B-NATIONALITY	13	dep
,	,	O	13	punct
French	NNP	B-NATIONALITY	21	amod
and	CC	O	17	cc
German	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	17	conj
Air	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	21	compound
Forces	NNPS	I-ORGANIZATION	10	nmod
and	CC	O	10	cc
in	IN	O	24	case
cooperation	NN	O	10	conj
with	IN	O	26	case
industry	NN	O	24	nmod
and	CC	O	26	cc
research	NN	O	29	compound
institutes	NNS	O	26	conj
from	IN	O	33	case
several	JJ	O	33	amod
European	JJ	B-NATIONALITY	33	amod
countries	NNS	O	24	nmod
.	.	O	5	punct

FlySafe	NNP	B-PERSON	0	ROOT
showed	VBD	O	2	nsubj
how	WRB	O	27	csubj
combining	VBG	O	4	advmod
weather	NN	O	2	ccomp
and	CC	O	8	compound
environmental	JJ	O	5	cc
data	NNS	O	5	conj
from	IN	O	4	dobj
Earth-observing	NNP	B-MISC	11	case
satellites	NNS	O	11	amod
and	CC	O	8	nmod
tracking	NN	O	11	cc
of	IN	O	11	conj
individual	JJ	O	16	case
birds	NNS	O	16	amod
from	IN	O	11	nmod
space	NN	O	18	case
with	IN	O	16	nmod
local	JJ	O	22	case
migration	NN	O	22	amod
information	NN	O	22	compound
from	IN	O	18	nmod
ground	NN	O	25	case
radars	NNS	O	25	compound
can	MD	O	22	nmod
improve	VB	O	27	aux
national	JJ	O	30	amod
bird-warning	JJ	O	30	compound
systems	NNS	O	27	dobj
.	.	O	27	punct

Satcoms	NNS	O	0	ROOT
relay	VBP	O	2	nsubj
data	NNS	O	2	dobj
in	IN	O	5	case
areas	NNS	O	2	nmod
where	WRB	O	10	advmod
terrestrial	JJ	O	8	amod
means	NNS	O	10	nsubj
are	VBP	O	10	cop
unavailable	JJ	O	5	acl:relcl
,	,	O	10	punct
as	RB	O	10	cc
well	RB	O	12	mwe
as	IN	O	12	mwe
helping	VBG	O	10	conj
to	TO	O	17	mark
track	VB	O	15	xcomp
individual	JJ	O	19	amod
birds	NNS	O	17	dobj
via	IN	O	22	case
GPS	NNP	O	22	compound
tags	NNS	O	17	nmod
.	.	O	2	punct

Ground	NN	O	0	ROOT
radars	NNS	O	2	compound
include	VBP	O	3	nsubj
weather	JJR	O	5	compound
radars	NNS	O	3	dobj
,	,	O	5	punct
surveillance	NN	O	8	compound
radars	NNS	O	5	conj
and	CC	O	5	cc
short-range	JJ	O	13	amod
local	JJ	O	13	amod
radar	NN	O	13	compound
systems	NNS	O	5	conj
equipped	VBN	O	13	acl
with	IN	O	16	case
technology	NN	O	14	nmod
developed	VBN	O	16	acl
by	IN	O	21	case
Robin	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	21	compound
Radar	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	21	compound
Systems	NNPS	I-ORGANIZATION	17	nmod
.	.	O	3	punct

US	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	0	ROOT
Airways	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	3	compound
flight	NN	O	3	compound
1549	CD	B-DATE	5	nsubj
ended	VBD	O	3	nummod
in	IN	O	9	case
the	DT	O	9	det
Hudson	NNP	B-CITY	9	compound
River	NNP	B-TITLE	5	nmod
after	IN	O	13	mark
geese	JJ	O	13	nsubjpass
were	VBD	O	13	auxpass
ingested	VBN	O	5	advcl
into	IN	O	16	case
the	DT	O	16	det
engines	NNS	O	13	nmod
.	.	O	5	punct

US	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	0	ROOT
Airways	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	3	compound
flight	NN	O	3	compound
falls	VBZ	O	4	nsubj
victim	NN	O	4	dobj
to	TO	O	8	case
bird	VB	O	8	compound
strike	VB	O	4	nmod
The	DT	O	11	det
Dutch	JJ	B-NATIONALITY	11	amod
company	NN	O	12	nsubj
started	VBD	O	8	acl:relcl
selling	VBG	O	12	xcomp
the	DT	O	15	det
technology	NN	O	13	dobj
developed	VBD	O	15	acl
under	IN	O	18	case
FlySafe	NNP	O	16	nmod
as	IN	O	23	case
an	DT	O	23	det
operational	JJ	O	23	amod
bird-warning	NN	O	23	amod
service	NN	O	12	nmod
in	IN	O	25	case
2010	CD	B-DATE	23	nmod
to	TO	O	27	case
customers	NNS	O	23	nmod
in	IN	O	29	case
Belgium	NNP	B-COUNTRY	23	nmod
,	,	O	29	punct
Bulgaria	NNP	B-COUNTRY	29	conj
,	,	O	29	punct
Estonia	NNP	B-COUNTRY	29	conj
,	,	O	29	punct
Netherlands	NNP	B-COUNTRY	29	conj
,	,	O	29	punct
Norway	NNP	B-COUNTRY	29	conj
,	,	O	29	punct
Poland	NNP	B-COUNTRY	29	conj
,	,	O	29	punct
Spain	NNP	B-COUNTRY	29	conj
and	CC	O	29	cc
Turkey	NNP	B-COUNTRY	29	conj
,	,	O	23	punct
including	VBG	O	51	case
the	DT	O	51	det
Dutch	NN	B-NATIONALITY	51	amod
and	CC	O	47	cc
Belgian	NNP	B-ORGANIZATION	47	conj
Air	NNP	I-ORGANIZATION	51	compound
Forces	NNPS	I-ORGANIZATION	23	nmod
.	.	O	4	punct

Since	IN	O	0	ROOT
then	RB	O	2	case
,	,	O	7	nmod
the	DT	O	7	punct
company	NN	O	5	det
has	VBZ	O	7	nsubj
expanded	VBN	O	7	aux
its	PRP$	O	9	nmod:poss
workforce	NN	O	7	dobj
fourfold	NN	O	7	advmod
and	CC	O	7	cc
increased	VBD	O	7	conj
its	PRP$	O	14	nmod:poss
revenues	NNS	O	12	dobj
by	IN	O	19	case
more	JJR	O	18	advmod
than	IN	O	16	mwe
25	CD	B-PERCENT	19	nummod
%	NN	I-PERCENT	12	nmod
every	DT	B-SET	22	det
six	CD	I-SET	22	nummod
months	NNS	I-SET	12	nmod:tmod
.	.	O	7	punct

``	``	O	0	ROOT
Air	NNP	O	28	punct
forces	NNS	O	3	compound
use	VBP	O	4	nsubj
the	DT	O	28	ccomp
system	NN	O	6	det
in	IN	O	4	dobj
combination	NN	O	8	case
with	IN	O	4	nmod
their	PRP$	O	12	case
surveillance	NN	O	12	nmod:poss
radars	NNS	O	12	compound
for	IN	O	8	nmod
en	IN	O	18	case
route	NN	O	18	amod
bird	NN	O	18	compound
strike	NN	O	18	compound
prevention	NN	O	18	compound
,	,	O	12	nmod
during	IN	O	4	punct
low-flying	JJ	O	22	case
exercises	NNS	O	22	amod
,	,	O	4	nmod
for	IN	O	4	punct
example	NN	O	25	case
,	,	O	4	nmod
''	''	O	28	punct
explains	VBZ	O	28	punct
company	NN	O	32	compound
CEO	NNP	B-TITLE	32	compound
Siete	NNP	B-PERSON	32	compound
Hamminga	NNP	I-PERSON	28	nsubj
.	.	O	28	punct

``	``	O	0	ROOT
With	IN	O	5	case
their	PRP$	O	5	nmod:poss
long-range	JJ	O	5	amod
detection	NN	O	10	nmod
,	,	O	10	punct
these	DT	O	8	det
systems	NNS	O	10	nsubj
can	MD	O	10	aux
scan	VB	O	1	root
hundreds	NNS	O	10	dobj
of	IN	O	13	case
kilometres	NNS	O	11	nmod
around	IN	O	10	advmod
.	.	O	10	punct
